Hi, I'm Bob Tabor with www.learnvisualstudio.net.
Up to now we've only looked at binding
to Styles, using the Binding expression
with the curly braces, StaticResource
and then some Style name, alright,
and we said earlier that this type of Binding,
this StaticResource Binding only happens
once when the app first starts, that's why
it's a "StaticResource," it won't change
throughout the life of the app.
However, there are other examples of
Binding statements that are not static.
For example, there's a themed resource
which is similar to the StaticResource,
but the resource lookup is evaluated
when the theme changes, so what's
a theme, you might wonder?
Well a theme is a collection of colors
that are selected by the end user
at an operating system level,
so in the Windows 10 Desktop you can pop open
the Settings App, go to personalization,
and here you can choose a background color
and I think also an accent color,
alright, and so in this case I've got black
as my background and then this
blue accent color, alright?
You can also personalize the phone and
the Xbox One as well by choosing a
background and an accent, now admittedly,
each have a different set of options,
but in general the end user can
personalize their colors in all the
Windows 10 flavors, alright, so as a developer
you can choose to utilize these color selections
in your app so that your app honors
the user's choices, now you're not
required to do this, but you probably should
unless you have a particular branding goal in mind,
so there are a set of colors that allow you,
or rather a set of styles that allow you
to utilize those colors that
were selected by the user.
Getting to that ResourceDictionary,
where those Styles are defined,
that's a little bit tricky and that'll
be the topic of this lesson.
Now if you take a look, let's shut that down
and open up our MainPage.xaml
in a New Project that I'm calling ThemeResources.
If you take a look at the Grid here,
as you create a brand new Blank App Template app,
you'll see that the grid utilizes a ThemeResource
called ApplicationPageBackgroundThemeBrush,
all right, now if you put your mouse cursor just
anywhere in that word, application page
background theme brush, and then you hit
the F12 key on your keyboard, it'll open up
this file in the preview called generic.xaml
and if you hover your mouse cursor over it
and unfortunately, let me just double click it.
Can I do that?
There we go, if I hover my mouse cursor over
you can see the full path of that file
on my copy of Windows here, it's
Program Files (x86)\Windows Kits\10\DesignTime\CommonConfiguration\Neutral\UAP (version number)\Generic\generic.xaml
okay, and you can see here
that's it's defined a SolidColorBrush
with that Key that's automatically being
used in our Grid and that sets it
to this Color which is white with all Fs, alright.
In this lesson I'm primarily going to be talking
about or referring to colors defined
as ThemeResources, however there are many
different types of Styles that are defined
in this generic.xaml file, including Font Faces
and weights and sizes and thicknesses
and there are even, it defines default Styles,
behavior and layout for all the
basic XAML Controls, so if you ever wonder
why something is styled a certain way
or why it behaves in a certain way,
this generic.xaml file is where
you can look and you can use that technique
that I used just a moment ago to get it,
but you can see it's a very long file.
Looks like it's 14,000 lines of code, alright.
You just would have to stare at it
for days on end to really figure out all that it's doing.
But at any rate, the way that you utilize
those Styles is to reference them inside
of your own Styles, and so here, let's just
create a little ResourceDictionary area here
for the page, so Page.Resources.
Inside of here I might wanna create
a SolidColorBrush that I call AccentBrush.
Then I would set the Color equal to that...
ThemeResource called SystemAccentColor.
Alright, so that SystemAccentColor will
give me access to the accent colors that
the user selects, so let me just add for example
a Rectangle here and I'll set the Width="100"
and the Height="100" and I'm gonna set the...
The Fill equal to that system.
Or rather, that StaticResource
that I called AccentBrush.
Let's take a look at our designer here
and you can see that it chose that same
blue color that you see in the tab
of Visual Studio because Visual Studio's using that
that blue color for the selected tab.
Also for the bar down the bottom
and other places here as well.
Alright, so you can see how I defined
a StaticResource using a ThemeResource,
but I could just go straight to the
ThemeResource as well, so let me just
copy this out here and use this instead.
Like so.
Nothing changes, all right.
That's how I get at the accent color,
how about the color of the windows in general here.
To get that color, let me just copy this down
and then we'll make this 50 and 50.
If we wanna get this light color, we would use
SystemColorWindowColor like so, and so that's
going to give us a light-colored area inside of the blue box.
Again, that matches that light color
and the rest of the window.
We're gonna see how that plays out
here in just a moment when we play
with the preferred Theme, but let's
come back to that in just a moment.
If you want an entire list of all of
these Themes, take a look at this XAML ThemeResource,
here, let me just put where you can find this
at bit.do/theme-resources.
You can come to this webpage and it has just
this long list of the different theme brushes,
colors for buttons and texts and all sorts of stuff.
You might want to spend some time on this page
to learn more about that.
On the Windows Phone you get to do
something a little bit different, let's go
to the emulator here and run it real quick.
On the Windows 10 Phone, the user can select
both a theme and an accent color, just like
whenever you're building for the Windows 10 Desktop,
you the developer get to decide whether
to use those colors or not.
Now on the phone, the user can select a Dark Theme
or a Light Theme and you can see here in this
particular case that I've chosen the Dark Theme.
How do I know that?
Because this system window color is not white
on the phone, it's actually black,
let's take a look in the Settings,
see if I can get to that.
In the simulator.
Let's go down to Settings, yeah, there we go.
We go to Personalization and then Colors.
You can see you can choose your mode,
either Light or Dark, so now I'm gonna
change from Dark to Light and I'm going to go back
to my app and go all the way down here.
Take a look at the ThemeResources app again
and notice that that system color
changed from Black to White.
The intent of that Light and Dark Theme
was really to change the shell, the colors
that are used by the operating system,
but again, as the developer you can choose
to actually utilize those colors and each
control of the Buttons, the TextBoxes,
everything are already Themed for
both Light and Dark and by default
the, I think the Dark will be used,
however, as the developer, you can change
or choose your preferred Theme by
setting it in the App.xaml.
I'm going to go here, App.xaml, and you can see
by default the RequestedTheme is Light,
but what if I change that to Dark?
Run the application again.
Okay, now you can see that the background color
for the window is black even though that
I chose the color, even though I chose the
Light Theme for the application.
This works the same way inside of our
Desktop apps as well, now that I've changed the
RequestedTheme to Dark, let's take a look
at this again on my local machine, you'll recall
last time we ran the app it had a white background
but now we're running with a black background, okay.
All right, so I'm not gonna show you how to
override the Styles that are defined in this
generic.xaml, but you can read about it in that
page that I pointed to you just a moment ago,
here, that XAML Theme Resources page,
it'll tell you about how to that.
All right, finally, a moment ago I said
that you could request a Theme and I wanted
to emphasize the fact that it's merely a request
and even the property says RequestedTheme.
If the user is using one of the high-contrast Themes
on the desktop, it's gonna override the RequestedTheme
as well as any Styles that you create for your Control,
so high-contrast Themes are for accessibility,
for people that are vision impaired, and that takes
precedence over any aesthetic that you might
want to use for your app, so here's what I'm
gonna do is go again to Settings, let me choose,
let me see if I can get to high-contrast,
yeah, high contrast settings.
It's under ease of access, choose "High contrast",
and I'm going to choose high contrast theme number one.
Then select apply.
Alright, and I don't know how much of that
you saw, but the system does a quick reboot
and now you can see that the Settings App
looks completely different, Visual Studio
looks different, when we run our app, this time
we get the Theme colors primarily for,
instead of any colors that we defined in our app.
Like I said earlier, ThemedResources should be
leveraged to keep your app looking like
they belong on the user's desktop or device,
so you should always resist the urge to
use custom colors or fonts and things
of that nature unless you have
a really good reason to do so.
One of the good reasons would be
for branding purposes for your company,
like think about Netflix, how they have that
iconic red color with the white text
and that specific font, alright.
Furthermore, there are built in Styles that
are available to your app, so for example,
if I go back to this MainPage.xaml and I took
a look and this is hard to look at,
so I'm gonna go back here and change
out of high-contrast settings.
Select none.
Ah, much better, okay.
There we go.
Let me change this to a StackPanel real quick here.
Then I'm gonna add a TextBlock and I'll set
the Text="My App Title", something like that,
and then I'm gonna set the Style equals,
we'll get to that point right there.
Okay, and so I can take advantage of some
of the default styling built into...
That generic.xaml page, like for example
here let's just use...
"StaticResource HeaderTextBlockStyle".
You can see, and let's just put this up to 66%.
We have this very specific font, I think it's
one of the Segoe fonts, but it's very thin and light
and you'll see that particular font used often in
applications, so we can borrow from that as well.
If you ever are wondering where you can
actually find some of these, some of these Styles,
for example for the TextBlock, let me go over here
to the Properties window on the right-hand side.
I'm going go to, I'm going to go to Miscellaneous
and then you can see that right now under Style
I get this Windows.UI.Xaml.Style,
if I click this little green button,
you can see that I can choose from...
A System Resource, let me move this over
a little bit so you can see it better.
Choose from one of the System Resources,
in this case I've chosen the HeaderTextBlockStyle,
but we could also choose for example
the sSubheaderTextBlockStyle or the...
CaptionTextBlockStyle, okay, a much smaller font.
There's one last thing that I wanna point out here
and that is if we were to put our mouse cursor
on the CaptionTextBlockStyle and hit F12,
you'll notice that it brings us to line 12,400
in the generic.xaml file.
If you scroll over to the right, you'll see that
this Style has a BasedOn Attribute, and so this Style
builds on something called BaseTextBlockStyle.
And that it adds a couple of modifications to it
and so this is where you'll see that it's
a lot like Cascading Style Sheets where you are,
you take a Style and you keep modifying it
and adding additional changes to it.
Now if we wanted to look at this BaseTextBlockStyle,
I'll just hit F12 again, oops, can't naviagate
to the definition, let's just go ahead
and control copy that and look
through it to find it.
All right, and so we can see it defined here
as the BaseTextBlockStyle, it doesn't,
it's not based on anything else.
TargetType="TextBlock" and then here it
sets the FontFamily, FontWeight, FontSize,
TextTrimming, Wrapping, LineStackingStrategy,
TextLineBounds, everything, and you can see
that there are a number of these Attributes that
we saw just a moment ago in the Properties window
that are all based on that BaseTextBlockStyle.
We can actually utilize BasedOn in our own Styles,
again, to give us that Cascading Style Sheet
approach to Styling the app.
Okay, so just to recap, the big takeaway
from this lesson was the ways in which you
can utilize ThemeResources in your apps
to achieve styling that's consistent with
other apps on the user's desktop or on their device.
I think it's time for a review,
see you in the next lesson where we'll
add to our little cheat sheet.
Thanks.