Hi, I'm Bob Tabor with www.learnvisualstudio.net
and this is the challenge that I'm calling
the Stupendous Styles Challenge.
And you can see that I've got a
fictitious company I created called GoNuts.
So my idea here is that someday when I'm burnt out
or when everybody discovers I'm a fraud (laughs),
I will open up a donut shop.
And I thought it'd be cool, you know, if you go up
and you pull up to some sort of a terminal
and you push in your order and then you drive around
and a robot delivers it into your car.
That would be pretty cool.
So this is the kiosk application that I just came up with.
It's just a layout, there's no real
e-commerce functionality, but let me walk you through it.
You can see that I have some navigation across the top.
I'll give you some specific instruction
about that in a moment.
And you can say, "Hey, I want, you know, so many,
"three glazed and four of the specials."
I'm going to go and order a dark
with sugar and cream.
And then let's make sure to pick that up,
let's see, tomorrow morning at,
I would say, like 9:30am, I should be there.
And then finally, hit the Complete
and I get this little ticket that tells me
which order number that I have.
And you'll notice that, and I make a point of this,
that it's responsive insomuch that,
you can resize things and they mostly look good.
You see there's like this attractive little graphic here
on the right-hand side.
That I've got these,
even though different colors on the different Pages.
I've got the logo on the last Page.
There's a color logo.
What else can I show you here?
Well, tell you what.
We have a bunch of resources, let me shut this down.
And let's talk about the requirements here.
You can see that I have this folder for you
to download from
wherever you're currently watching this video.
Make sure you grab this because it has instructions
and all the resource files
that you're going to need to put this together.
So here's the instruction file,
and let's go through it really quick here.
You can see that, even if you're fast,
this is going to take you 45 minutes.
Like, it took me 50 minutes to solve this on camera,
and then I wanted to re-record it and split it up
because it was so long.
So don't get discouraged if it takes you a while,
just keep plugging away.
First of all, you want to use Styles as often as possible.
So if you see the same thing happening in multiple places,
if you see that you're applying the same
Margins and Colors and Fonts to more than one item,
then make a Style for it, ok?
That's really the point of this lesson, is to exercise that,
as well as to exercise some of the new Controls
that we just added on the last couple of videos.
So you're going to create five pages,
or you're obviously going to have the MainPage
and then four others.
And so let's talk about each of the Pages.
That "MainPage.xaml" will host the navigation buttons
at the very top, those black buttons.
And I talk about how to get that effect,
the black background, white text, 18 point font.
There will be an icon next to the text.
You want a gray border on the right that's two pixels.
Not sure if we've talked about how to apply a border.
Look through the properties of the button
to see if you can figure out how to give the border a color,
and how to give it a size on one side,
but not have any border on the rest,
on the other sides of the button, ok?
And then I give you a hint about how to create
those large buttons,
basically create a grid with four columns
and then set the Vertical and HorizontalAlignment
to Stretch on each of those buttons,
and that will fill up that entire area of the cell.
Alright, also on the "MainPage.xaml",
you want to split that bottom area
underneath the navigation, and you want to give it,
I guess I need to write this in here, let me add this in.
This, make that
100 pixels tall
for the buttons spot.
Probably should have re-phrased that.
I'll edit that off camera.
So, you want to take the rest of the area
that's beneath the buttons,
and you want to split that area to 66% and 33%.
On the one side, you want to put the pages.
We'll load in the
DonutPage, CoffeePage, SchedulePage, CompletePage.
And then on the right-hand side, the 33%,
we're going to put that neat little background image
of the coffee and the donuts there,
kind of to style it up a little bit.
And so whenever a user clicks on one of the
black navigation buttons at the top, it will load in
one of the other Pages into that bottom Frame area.
And so, you'll start with the DonutPage.
It's just going to host a white logo
and two slider controls.
Make sure you add some padding
around the sides of those controls.
Make sure that you can only order up to
two dozen of each type of donut, arbitrary limit there.
On the CoffeePage, little more involved.
There will be some logic on this page.
First of all, you'll notice that it had
a white logo and three buttons.
And each of the buttons are going to have a flyout menu,
and I give you the contents of those flyout menus here.
And whenever a selection is made,
you want to update a Label Control
that will display the, your selection from the TextBlock.
I don't know if I demoed that,
so let me run that again really quick here.
Let me show you what I mean.
Here I'm going to say, I want
Medium, Sugar, and Whole Milk.
But if I were to set the Coffee equal to None,
then it removes everything else,
because obviously you can't just order,
you can't just order a coffee,
you can't just order sweetener and cream
without a coffee, you know?
Although I've tried that before.
Ok, so next up, also, you'll need that color for the Brown,
because there's not a preset color
that had exactly the right color that I was looking for.
Ok, number 7, the SchedulePage.
It had that TimePicker and DatePicker
that allowed me to choose the day and the time
where I want to pick up my order.
And you want to make sure to match the colors
to screenshots that I give you.
And let's go ahead and talk about those.
Look, I give you the screenshots,
what everything should look like here in a bunch of images
so you don't have to keep the videos open.
So here's for the four Pages, A, B, C, and D there.
Alrighty, next up,
there is the CompletePage,
and it'll have the color version of the logo,
so, this file here, as well as the,
that ticket.jpg.
And let's, let's go to the view
and look at the large icons here,
that'll show us what we're looking at here.
Alright, so there's a bunch of icons.
You can see they have the suffix, "-icon.png".
Here's that ticket icon, ticket graphic
and you're going to superimpose the word,
"Order 96" on top of it.
And there's the white-logo and the color-logo.
So, that should be all good.
Some general requirements.
The design should be responsive.
You notice when I was resizing,
things resized nicely, to an extent.
The navigation's at the top, they have to have that
border thickness of two and a gray border brush.
I think I already mentioned that earlier,
but I just want, bears repeating.
Most margins are 10 or 20, most font sizes are 18.
Try to match up as well as you can
if I haven't specified it.
Some of this is to your discretion,
whatever you come up with.
Make sure it just looks good.
You'll only need code behind for the navigation itself.
We're not talking about any other logic
unless I've noted above, ok, earlier in the document.
You have those images, A through D,
that will give you the various layouts
so you can look at it.
Also, you want to try to resolve this
without watching the next few videos.
where I think I'm going to split this up into like
four or five videos so you can get to
just the help that you need.
Only watch enough of the solution to get unstuck
and then continue on struggling.
Because struggling is how you learn.
And if you do wind up finishing it
and you've got an hour to spare,
you can watch how I solved the challenge
and the Styles that I created
and how I went about working in Visual Studio.
Probably will learn a little bit about maneuvering around,
but that is not necessarily an hour well spent,
just bear that in mind.
There's a lot of tedious work.
This isn't hard, it's just, there's a lot to it, ok?
Alright, well see what you come up with.
I know you can do it.
It's not that hard based on everything we've learned
up to this point, if you're paying attention.
Might have struggled a little bit,
may have to go back and look at
some of the work that we've done previously,
look at the cheat sheet, but I think you can do this, ok?
Alright, we'll see you in the next,
the next couple of videos for the solution.
Thanks.