So in my music collection,
I literally have...
hundreds, hundreds of albums
that I've purchased legitimately through the years.
And sometimes I don't even remember what I have,
so I can concocted a little game here
that will allow you to rediscover music that you have
in your music collection, in your music library,
and will make a little game out of it.
And so you've gotta kind of watch closely here
at the game itself.
Alright, so these are songs, or album covers
representing songs on my hard drive.
(music plays)
Ok. And I successfully guessed that song
and I got it right, and I scored 70 points
as a result of that.
Here we go, the next one.
(music plays)
Ok, I missed that one and I lost 80 points,
so I'm at a negative 10 after two rounds,
as you can see.
(music plays)
Alright, and so as you might guess,
this is not my music collection.
I'll explain that in the next video,
but these are purely songs that somebody
created for me.
(music plays)
But you can also see here that there's
a little blue area down here.
This actually represents an advertisement
from Microsoft Advertisement Network.
(music plays)
Okay.
So you can see that after five rounds,
I've got a massive negative score of 260.
I can choose to play again,
but that's really not the most significant thing
about this application.
What it will do is it'll allow you to go through
special folders on the user's device
or desktop, specifically the music library.
And it'll go through every single folder
in the music library
and find a list of all MP3 files.
It'll then grab the metadata from the MP3 file itself,
so information like the album name, the artist's name,
the album art,
so you can see that we've got the cover art
for the album itself,
and then it's going to choose to randomly play songs
and as the user, I then have to guess,
and it's going to evaluate my guess whether right or wrong
and it will change the tile
as a result of that
and it'll keep score, and there's a lot of logic
around what songs to play,
what to stay away from because you've already guessed
that album art or it's already been used once,
you can't use it because it's already got an X on it,
sort of thing, okay?
Like I said, we demonstrate how to use
and monetize this application through Microsoft Advertising.
We'll demonstrate that and then we'll also demonstrate
how to remove ads,
so to add a premium feature to the app
and allow you to monetize it
by allowing the user to click a button
and it'll pop up the
"are you sure you want to purchase this for a dollar?"
Now, this is a little simulator and we'll talk about this
near the end of our time together building this,
but I'm going to go ahead and say "Yes,"
the user successfully purchased the removal of ads
in the app.
And so we're going to demonstrate how to add
in-app purchases in your application.
So there's a lot to learn in this app,
it's going to be a lot of fun, a lot of logic,
a lot of typing,
so you'll need to follow along closely or you'll probably,
honestly you'll probably just want to look at the source code
after I finish the video,
but just follow along with the thought process
as I work my way through this example.
Alright, ready?
Let's get started in the next video.
Thanks.