Hi, I'm Bob Tabor with www.LearnVisualStudio.Net.
We're picking apart XAML bit by bit.
And in this brief video, I want to explain
one curious little feature called Type Converters
that we see in play in this example
that we created in the previous lesson,
this "What Is XAML" app.
So, you'll notice a couple of things here.
First of all, I uncommented out the button
on our MainPage.xaml.
And, if you took a few moments to examine this project
between the previous video and this video,
and if you had a keen eye,
you may have noticed that
the horizontal alignment property,
and this goes true as well
for the vertical alignment,
but let's just focus on horizontal alignment property,
is set to a string with the value "Left".
However, the C# version is a little bit different.
If you take a look at when we set
that horizontal alignment property,
we're actually using a strongly typed enumeration,
not a string, a strongly typed enumeration of type,
Windows.UI.Xaml.HorizontalAlignment,
and the particular enumeration is also Left,
but it's strongly typed.
So, how does this work?
Why is it that we can use a string here,
but we have to use a strong type in C#?
Well, the reason why this works
is because the XAML parser will perform a conversion
to turn this string value
into a strongly typed version of that value
of type Windows.UI.Xaml.HorizontalAlignment.left
through the use of a feature called a Type Converter.
And a Type Converter is simply a class that has
one function, and that is to translate a string value
into a strong type.
And there are several of these that are
built into the Universal Windows Platform API
that we'll use throughout this series.
So, in this example of the horizontal alignment property,
when it was developed by Microsoft's developers
was marked with a special attribute
in the source code,
which signals to the XAML parser that looks through our code
and makes sure everything is okay
and that it would compile.
To run that string value left through a Type Converter
and try to match the literal string left
with one of the enumeration values defined
in this Windows.UI.Xaml.HorizontalAlignment enumeration.
So, just for fun, let's take a look at what happens
if we were to misspell the word "Left".
Let's get rid of the "t" on the end.
And notice that right away, the XAML parser
kicks in and says, "Wait a second.
"I can't find a match for this literal string, lef,
(without the T), with any of the enumerations
that are defined in this
Windows.UI.Xaml.HorizontalAlignment enumeration."
All right, so you can see how this works.
And, we'll get
basically a compilation error
because the Type Converter can't find the exact match
so that it can convert that to a strong type.
So, one of the first characteristics of XAML
as we begin to pick it apart bit by bit,
is that it's succinct means of creating instances of classes
and setting properties in Type Converters,
is one little trick that XAML uses that helps
to accomplish this so that we don't have to waste characters
and that we can actually just use a very succinct
syntax to set values that might be
actually representing longer
class and enumeration names behind the scenes.
Okay, simple as that.
So, let's keep on moving along
and investigating XAML.
More XAML in the next lesson.
We'll see you there.
Thanks.