UWP 声音版 —— 使用 MediaElement 控件播放声音
翻译 : scripter糖　审核：@geelaw（微博）　压制：<压制人>
Okay, so now it's time to have fun./好了，现在就是娱乐时间了
We're going to actually wire up the/我们用 MediaElement 来播放音频
I'll also do a little clean up and get the filtering to work/我也会做一些筛选的功能
by selecting one of the categories./通过选择其中一种分类
Only show those categories in the GridView./从而在GridView中只显示此类别音频
So let's go ahead and get started here.//那就从这里开始吧
And I'm going to open up the MainPage.xaml/我现在去打开MainPage.xaml
and in here what I want to do is handle the,/在这里我想处理一下，嗯
I think this is it, the ListView_ItemClick Event./我想可能是它， ListView_ItemClick事件
Let me make sure that's the correct EventHandler./让我们搞清楚这是否是正确的事件处理方法
So basically when somebody selects/当某人选择了SoundGridView中的某一个Item
that we created, we want to play the sound/对应的音频需要被播放
that's associated with the image that was clicked on./那也意味着某一张图片被点击过了
So, actually, this is the EventHandler that we want./所以呢，这应该就是我们需要的事件处理方法
SoundGridView_ItemClick./SoundGridView_ItemClick
让我们继续
这个方法我们已经不再需要它了
If we do, we'll add it back./如果以后还要用就把它再加回来
Alright, and so here it's pretty easy stuff./好，现在这里看起来就很简单了
All we need to do is grab the Item that was clicked on/我们只需要分清楚被点击具体的的Item
and so that'll be given to us here/那么这里给了我们一个参数 ItemClickEventArgs e
And we can just choose the clicked Item and then/然后我们选择 ClickedItem 之后
cast that to what it represents/把它的类型转换为它实际的类型
which is a sound in our application./也就是我们应用中的 Sound
So I can do something like this:/所以我又 var 了一个变量 sound，对应的就是音频
and then we'll set, I think I called it/接下来我们设置一些属性，应该是 MyMediaElement.Source
MyMediaElement.Source, and we'll just set it to/我们把它设置成对应的音频文件属性
Now, to do this, we actually need to give it a URI,/为了做到这个，我们需要一个 Uri
if you hover over, you can see the Source property/当鼠标停在上面，你可以看见对应的Source属性
accepts a URI, which is a Uniform Resource Indicator,/接受一个URI
（URI : Uniform Resource Indicator，统一资源指示符）
and that's just going to be a location for the file./这也就是表示文件所处的地址
Now, what we need to do, there's a couple/我们现在有很多种方案来填写参数
I think the easiest way is just to specify the base URI./我认为最简单的就是设置 baseUri
That will give us, like, the root of the project,/这会给予我们一个好用的东西，像是这个项目的起点一样
and then we can give it the actual audio file/然后我们就需要给予它实际的音频文件
that will contain that /Assets/Audio/Category/Sound./这会包含 “/Assets/Audio/Category/Sound”路径下的文件
So we'll just do this.BaseUri,/我们选择 this.BaseUri
and then we'll use the sound.AudioFile/接下来就是使用 sound.AudioFile
and, with any luck, this will actually work,/嗯，运气不错的话，就应该就可以管用了
so let's see what we've got so far./那就让我们看看做了这么多所收获的成果吧
Alright, it's time for the moment of truth./现在就是揭晓真相的时刻
(laugh)/（笑声）
(siren)/（汽笛声）
(cow moos)/（牛的声音）
OK, so it was that easy./好了，就是这么简单
That's all we needed to do to wire everything up, great./这就是我们连接所有东西所需要做的事情
Now, when we ran the application,/现在，当我们运行这个程序的时候
there were some other issues with layout,/还有一些关于界面布局的问题
with the hamburger navigation,/比如汉堡按钮导航
let's go ahead and fix some of those things,/让我们继续修正并解决它们
because that's really what's holding us back now./因为这真的有必要再回顾一下
Let me take note of a few things,/我们会记录下需要修正的事项
rerunning the application here,/现在返回到这个应用中来
and we'll just address them little by little./我们会一点点的解决
Alright, so you can see here that we've got some/好，的确是有问题的
issues with each of the ListView Items./ListView 的项显示并不完全
Well, the text needs to be moved down a little bit./标题文字需要往下放一点，从而居中
If we can move things to the left a bit,/如果我们把它们整体往左边移动一下就很有帮助了
that would be helpful, because we wanted to line up/因为我们很需要把这些项对齐
So, generally, some spacing issues there./另外一个问题看起来就是空间问题了
As far as these items, they need to be/这些项需要被往左边移动一点
because it's just it's just kind of running together here,/因为看起来就像是挤在一起了一样
in that upper left-hand corner area./在左上角的区域
So let's work on those two things right now./来着手为这两者开工吧
Let's go over to the the MainPage.xaml./现在来查看 MainPage.xaml 文件
Now, as far as the MediaElement is concerned,/现在我们最关注的 MediaElement
we're going to use it at length for another project,/它的更多功能将在其它项目中被使用
and we're going to learn how to manipulate the sounds,/比如我们将会学习如何操作音频文件
and how much of the sound to play,/以及播放音量的控制
how do we manipulate the volume so that it/怎么使它们播放结束的时候渐渐淡去
nicely fades out, instead of abruptly ends./而不是戛然而止
When we get to another project/当我们到另外一个项目的时候
that we're going to work on together,/就是全部运用的时候了
so this is really our introduction to the MediaElement./所以这是我们真正的 MediaElement 的初学引导
It can also play videos,/它也能播放视频
which I don't think we're going to demonstrate/我想我们不需要在这个版本里证明了
in this series, but if you take a look/如果你有看过我为 Windows 8.1 以及 Windows Phone 8.1 做的开发指导视频
video, using the MediaElement./就知道我演示过怎么使用 MediaElement 播放视频
Ok, so let's go up here to ListView,/现在上来看看 ListView
and what we want to do first of all, is,/我们先把这些代码分到不同行
One of the first things I want to try to do is/第一件我想尝试的事情是
set a negative Margin, because I really want/设置一个负的 Margin
that image to move to the left quite a bit./因为我真的很想让图片往左边移动一点
And we've not talked about negative Margins./我们之前没有讨论过负的 Margin
Let's just try, like, -15,/但咱们尽管尝试，比如 -15
and maybe then 10 on the top, 0/或许上面的间距可以是10
on the right and 10 on the bottom./右边是 0，下面则是 10
That should make things a little more interesting there./这样这里就有一点有趣的东西了
And as far as the TextBlock, I think we need to set/以及所有的 TextBlock
the VerticalAlignment="Center", that should/我认为应该把它们的 VerticalAlignment 设置为 Center
move things down a little bit./这样字体的位置就会偏低一点了
Let's see what kind of impact that has./来看看这些修改的影响
Alright, that definitely moved things over to the left,/很好，它们已经移动到了左边
which is great, and it looks like we've centered the text./真是太好了，这些字体看起来也被垂直居中了
That's good too. And the last thing,/最后一件事.....
It's a hard call, right? I think what we ultimately need/这有点难以描述？
are these icons to be a tiny bit smaller,/我想我们需要把这些图标做小一点
and maybe that would fix some of the issues there./这样或许也可以修复这里的一些问题
So let's back off on this to a -10, and then/回到这里，把它设置为 -10
set the Height and the Width of/之后设置宽度和高度
these just a tiny bit smaller there,/让他们稍微小一点点
and maybe even create a little more/甚至也可以尝试在项间加入一些小小的边距
The other thing that I want to do now is/另外一件我现在想做的事情是.....
come over to this, in the Content area,/来到这里，Content区域
I want to, on that whole item, that whole Content area,/我想把这整个 Item，以及整个 Content 区域
I want to push things out a little bit./全部推出去一点
So I'm going to set the Margin on the left 20,/所以我把这里 Margin 的左间距设置为 20
and then I'll just go zeros for the rest of this/剩下的则全部设置为 0
until I get a chance to look at it a little bit./咦，我多了一个逗点
See what we have there./看看我们现在的东西吧
So you can see that this is a lot of tinkering,/所以你能看到这里有很多可以小修小补的地方
just seeing 'Does that look right? What if we do this?'/只是问问 “这看起来对吗？” ”我们这么做会怎么样？“ 就能做很多
I probably should even make those icons/我或许需要这些图标再小一点
a bit smaller, they're still pretty large./它们依然很大
So, let me do that./那么就这么做
But I like the spacing here./但我喜欢这里留出的空隙
We might even come down from the top a little bit./我们甚至还应该把顶部再往上放一点
So let's make those two adjustments./让我们做出那两个调整
Let's make the icons a tiny bit smaller,/先让图标小一点
so let's go, 35, and 35 here./尺寸设置为 35
I'm going to reduce that back down to 10./我去把这里的上间距设置为 10
It was just a little bit too much/15 有点太多了
Margin on the top and bottom./上下间距也设置好了
And the other thing that I wanted to do was,/另外一些事我想做的是
here I'm going to set.../这里我把它设置为.....
Let's try 20 from the top./试试上外边距为 20
That should push that Grid down 20 from the top,/这样 Grid 距离顶部就有 20 的距离了
giving us a little more space there./我们就有了更多空隙
Alright, I feel a little better about that./很好，我感觉更好了一点
That might be a bit much, but, overall,/只是微小的改进，但整体都感觉变好了
I like where we're going with this./我喜欢我们正在做的事情
The next thing I want to do is get the menu/接下来我想做的事情是菜单分类选择了
actually working, so it actually filters./的确是有作用，这其实是个分类选择项
So let's work on that part right there./那就开始在右边的区域下功夫
And the ListView that we have/这是我们有的 ListView
we're going to accept input from the/我们将从 MenuItemsListView_ItemClick 事件处理程序获得输入
Here again, what I want to do is grab that Event Item/这里还是，我要弄清是哪个项产生了事件
that was clicked on from the ItemClickEventArgs e,/被点击可以从 ItemClickEventArgs e
so, once again, I'm going grab the e.ClickedItem./对，我要取出 e.ClickedItem
I'm going to cast it, this time on a menuItem,/这次则是把类型转换为 MenuItem
remember that was the class that represent/记得，这是一个表示
each of the items that we're Binding to./被绑定在具体的 Items 上的菜单项的类
Then I'll do var menuItem equals/接下来 var menuItem =
there we go. Great./这样就好了，棒
Now what we want to do here is/现在我们想在这里做的
"Filter on", by category./是一个通过类别选择的筛选工作
Great./好
So, we'll set the Category/我们会设置 Category
I think we have a CategoryTextBox./我认为我们有一个 CategoryTextBox
Nah, let's see what we call that./看看我们给它的命名是什么
Okay, CategoryTextBlock, let's grab that./ CategoryTextBlock，就是它了
CategoryTextBlock.Text = menuItem.Category / CategoryTextBlock.Text = menuItem.Category
and we'll just do a ToString on that./我们给它加上一个 ToString() 方法
That should give us what we need there./这样就可以给我们所需要的东西了
In this point we want to change our Sounds Collection,/在这点上我想改变 Sounds 集合
remember that that is a ObservableCollection /记住这是一个  ObservableCollection<Sound>
and so what we're going to want to to is /所以我们要去做的是
filter that, so we're going to call/筛选它，我们调用
the SoundManager.GetSoundsByCategory /SoundManager.GetSoundsByCategory
this time, passing in our ObservableCollection /传入我们的 ObservableCollection<Sound>
and then the Sound Categories./接下来是声音分类
So, menuItem.Category./所以， menuItem.Category
Alright, so that should give us what we need./很好，这应该就可以给我们想要的了
What's wrong here?/这里出了什么幺蛾子？
Oh, I see. We can't set it equal./哦，我看见了，我们不能把这里写成 =
Sorry, I forgot how I designed that method./抱歉，我刚才忘记了我怎么设计这个方法的了
And, I'm not even sure we need to do anything else./并且，我也不确定会不会还需要做这种事情
I think that's the only two things we need to do,/我认为那只有两件事我们需要做
so let's go ahead and try that./先来试试吧
So, lets say I only want Animals,/我现在只需要 Animals 类别的
I only want Taunts, I only want Warnings. /我只需要 Taunt 类别的，我只需要 Warning 类别的
I only want Cartoons, awesome. /我只需要 Cartoon 类别的，真好
OK, that works./好了，都有效了
Now we want to get the BackButton to work./现在我们需要后退按钮有效
Really, the BackButton should only be displayed/这个后退按钮应该只在我们选择了某一个项之后才会出现
so, really, at this point, we should say/在这点上，我们应该说
"Hey, BackButton, go ahead and set your visibility /“嘿，返回按钮，设置好你的 Visibility 属性为 Visibility.Visible 枚举值！”
"otherwise, it should be set to/“另外，这个该被设置为
"Collapsed."/Collapsed。”
Alright, when we see all of the Items./好，当我们看见所有项时
Alright, so let's try that, and let's see,/好，那就试试，再看看结果
and I may have to adjust that./我或许得调整这个
I've kind of forgotten what I need to do there./我有点儿忘记这里我需要做的东西了
But, whenever we hit the BackButton,/但是，不管我们怎么点击后退按钮
what we want to do is actually go back to that./我们真正想的是返回到上一个地方
to All Sounds./也就是全部的声音
So here we'll go/所以现在我们来
SoundManager.GetAllSounds/SoundManager.GetAllSounds
and we'll just pass in our Sounds,/我们只要入我们的 Sounds
and we're going to tell that MenuItemsListView/并且我们会告诉 MenuItemsListView
MenuItemsListView.SelectedItem = null
so nothing will be selected then./所以就不会有项被选定
It'll just be back to its original state./这只会后退到上一个地方
And that's all we should have to do./这就是我们所需要做的全部
So let's see if that actually works./看看这个是否有效
OK, so all sounds initially, then we're going to say/“好，所有声音”
"Hey, just give me the taunts."/“只给我 Taunts 类别的”
Notice that the Back Button showed up./注意到后退按钮出现了
I'm going to hit the Back Button./我去点击这个按钮
I see we have some work to do here. We're not 100%./我看我们这里还有工作要做，并没有100%完成
We hit the BackButton, we want to go back to All Sounds./我们点击后退按钮，我们需要返回到所有声音
And then we would also want to make that/接下来我们也需要设置
BackButton.Visibility = Visibility.Collapsed. /BackButton.Visibility = Visibility.Collapsed
Alright, so let's pay attention to that state/好，现在注意一下位置
one more time here, specifically, that BackButton./多次注意下这个特别的后退按钮
OK, we don't see a Back Button,/好，我们没有看见这个后退按钮
and we're viewing All Sounds./我们浏览一下所有的声音
Now we want to go Taunts/现在我们需要到 Taunts 类别中
and then I'll hit Back Button All Sounds./接下来我想回到全部声音
And we could implement this in a/我们也可以用另一种方式实现
more robust way and keep track of the/这种方式更加可靠，它追踪
various Pages that were loaded in,/我们浏览过的页面
and then just call Navigation.GoBack,/然后调用 Navigation.GoBack，可以后退回去
but I'm not doing it that way./不过我不会这么去做
The BackButton will just take us back to All Sounds./这个后退按钮只会带我们返回到全部声音
So it's really just a matter/所以这只是一个你怎么实现的问题
But I feel comfortable with this approach./但是我觉得这个方法挺好
(loud siren)/（刺耳的笛声）
Excuse me./抱歉
I actually scared myself to death./我差点把我自己都吓死了
I didn't realize I was going to make a sound, I forgot./我没意识到我添加了一个这样的声音，我忘记了
Alright, at so any rate, that's exciting stuff, right?/很好，不管怎么看，这都是一个很刺激的素材
We made a lot of progress on this one, and I think/我们进展不错，我觉得
the next thing we're going to do is add some/我们下一件要做的事情是文件拖入和拖出的问题
That will be interesting./这会很有趣
So we'll be able to take a sound off of our desktop,/我们将会从桌面拖出一个声音（文件）
and drag-and-drop it in, and then hear it./拖入程序并释放，然后听这个声音（文件）
And add it to the List, and then actually hear it./以及把它们添加进列表，之后聆听它
So that'll be a big one./所以这会是一个大工程
We'll do that in the next lesson. Thanks./我们会在下一节课上完成这个，谢谢