Okay, so now it's time to have fun.
We're going to actually wire up the
MediaElement to play the Sounds.
I'll also do a little clean up and get the filtering to work
by selecting one of the categories.
Only show those categories in the GridView.
So let's go ahead and get started here.
And I'm going to open up the MainPage.xaml
and in here what I want to do is handle the,
I think this is it, the ListView_ItemClick Event.
Let me make sure that's the correct EventHandler.
So basically when somebody selects
one of the items in this SoundGridView
that we created, we want to play the sound
that's associated with the image that was clicked on.
So, actually, this is the EventHandler that we want.
SoundGridView_ItemClick.
Let me go ahead and,
I think we don't need this one anymore.
If we do, we'll add it back.
Alright, and so here it's pretty easy stuff.
All we need to do is grab the Item that was clicked on
and so that'll be given to us here
in this ItemClickEventArgs e.
And we can just choose the clicked Item and then
cast that to what it represents
which is a sound in our application.
So I can do something like this:
var sound equals ClickedItem, cast it to Sound,
and then we'll set, I think I called it
MyMediaElement.Source, and we'll just set it to
that Sounds audio file property.
Now, to do this, we actually need to give it a URI,
if you hover over, you can see the Source property
accepts a URI, which is a Uniform Resource Indicator,
and that's just going to be a location for the file.
Now, what we need to do, there's a couple
different ways to go about this.
I think the easiest way is just to specify the base URI.
That will give us, like, the root of the project,
and then we can give it the actual audio file
that will contain that /Assets/Audio/Category/Sound.
So we'll just do this.BaseUri,
and then we'll use the sound.AudioFile
and, with any luck, this will actually work,
so let's see what we've got so far.
Alright, it's time for the moment of truth.
(laugh)
(siren)
(cow moos)
OK, so it was that easy.
That's all we needed to do to wire everything up, great.
Now, when we ran the application,
there were some other issues with layout,
with the hamburger navigation,
let's go ahead and fix some of those things,
because that's really what's holding us back now.
Let me take note of a few things,
rerunning the application here,
and we'll just address them little by little.
Alright, so you can see here that we've got some
issues with each of the ListView Items.
Well, the text needs to be moved down a little bit.
If we can move things to the left a bit,
that would be helpful, because we wanted to line up
with the hamburger icon.
So, generally, some spacing issues there.
As far as these items, they need to be
pushed off from the left hand side a bit,
because it's just it's just kind of running together here,
in that upper left-hand corner area.
So let's work on those two things right now.
Let's go over to the the MainPage.xaml.
Now, as far as the MediaElement is concerned,
we're going to use it at length for another project,
and we're going to learn how to manipulate the sounds,
and how much of the sound to play,
how do we manipulate the volume so that it
nicely fades out, instead of abruptly ends.
When we get to another project
that we're going to work on together,
so this is really our introduction to the MediaElement.
It can also play videos,
which I don't think we're going to demonstrate
in this series, but if you take a look
at the previous series that I created
for 8.1, so Windows Phone 8.1 Development
for Absolute Beginners, I demo how to display
video, using the MediaElement.
Ok, so let's go up here to ListView,
and what we want to do first of all, is,
I'm going to separate
some of these on other lines.
One of the first things I want to try to do is
set a negative Margin, because I really want
that image to move to the left quite a bit.
And we've not talked about negative Margins.
Let's just try, like, -15,
and maybe then 10 on the top, 0
on the right and 10 on the bottom.
That should make things a little more interesting there.
And as far as the TextBlock, I think we need to set
the VerticalAlignment="Center", that should
move things down a little bit.
Let's see what kind of impact that has.
Alright, that definitely moved things over to the left,
which is great, and it looks like we've centered the text.
That's good too. And the last thing,
It's a hard call, right? I think what we ultimately need
are these icons to be a tiny bit smaller,
and maybe that would fix some of the issues there.
So let's back off on this to a -10, and then
set the Height and the Width of
these just a tiny bit smaller there,
and maybe even create a little more
Height and more Margin between each of the items.
The other thing that I want to do now is
come over to this, in the Content area,
I want to, on that whole item, that whole Content area,
I want to push things out a little bit.
So I'm going to set the Margin on the left 20,
and then I'll just go zeros for the rest of this
until I get a chance to look at it a little bit.
See what we have there.
So you can see that this is a lot of tinkering,
just seeing 'Does that look right? What if we do this?'
I probably should even make those icons
a bit smaller, they're still pretty large.
So, let me do that.
But I like the spacing here.
We might even come down from the top a little bit.
So let's make those two adjustments.
Let's make the icons a tiny bit smaller,
so let's go, 35, and 35 here.
I'm going to reduce that back down to 10.
It was just a little bit too much
Margin on the top and bottom.
And the other thing that I wanted to do was,
here I'm going to set...
Let's try 20 from the top.
That should push that Grid down 20 from the top,
giving us a little more space there.
Alright, I feel a little better about that.
That might be a bit much, but, overall,
I like where we're going with this.
The next thing I want to do is get the menu
actually working, so it actually filters.
So let's work on that part right there.
And the ListView that we have
we're going to accept input from the
MenuItemsListView_ItemClick EventHandler.
Here again, what I want to do is grab that Event Item
that was clicked on from the ItemClickEventArgs e,
so, once again, I'm going grab the e.ClickedItem.
I'm going to cast it, this time on a menuItem,
remember that was the class that represent
each of the items that we're Binding to.
Then I'll do var menuItem equals
there we go. Great.
Now what we want to do here is
"Filter on", by category.
Great.
So, we'll set the Category
I think we have a CategoryTextBox.
Nah, let's see what we call that.
Okay, CategoryTextBlock, let's grab that.
CategoryTextBlock.Text = menuItem.Category,
and we'll just do a ToString on that.
That should give us what we need there.
In this point we want to change our Sounds Collection,
remember that that is a ObservableCollection,
and so what we're goign to want to to is
filter that, so we're going to call
the SoundManager.GetSoundsByCategory
this time, passing in our ObservableCollection,
and then the Sound Categories.
So, menuItem.Category.
Alright, so that should give us what we need.
What's wrong here?
Oh, I see. We can't set it equal.
Sorry, I forgot how I designed that method.
And, I'm not even sure we need to do anything else.
I think that's the only two things we need to do,
so let's go ahead and try that.
So, lets say I only want Animals,
I only want Taunts, I only want Warnings.
I only want Cartoons, awesome.
OK, that works.
Now we want to get the BackButton to work.
Really, the BackButton should only be displayed
whenever we click on one of the Items.
so, really, at this point, we should say
"Hey, BackButton, go ahead and set your visibility
"equal to Visibility.Visible,
"otherwise, it should be set to
"Collapsed."
Alright, when we see all of the Items.
Alright, so let's try that, and let's see,
and I may have to adjust that.
I've kind of forgotten what I need to do there.
But, whenever we hit the BackButton,
what we want to do is actually go back to that.
to All Sounds.
So here we'll go
SoundManager.GetAllSounds,
and we'll just pass in our Sounds,
and we're going to tell that MenuItemsListView
MenuItemsListView.SelectedItem = null
MenuItemsListView.SelectedItem = null,
so nothing will be selected then.
It'll just be back to its original state.
And that's all we should have to do.
So let's see if that actually works.
OK, so all sounds initially, then we're going to say
"Hey, just give me the taunts."
Notice that the Back Button showed up.
I'm going to hit the Back Button.
I see we have some work to do here. We're not 100%.
We hit the BackButton, we want to go back to All Sounds.
And then we would also want to make that
BackButton.Visibility = Visibility.Collapsed.
Alright, so let's pay attention to that state
one more time here, specifically, that BackButton.
OK, we don't see a Back Button,
and we're viewing All Sounds.
Now we want to go Taunts
and then I'll hit Back Button All Sounds.
And we could implement this in a
more robust way and keep track of the
various Pages that were loaded in,
and then just call Navigation.GoBack,
but I'm not doing it that way.
The BackButton will just take us back to All Sounds.
So it's really just a matter
of how you want to implement it.
But I feel comfortable with this approach.
(loud siren)
Excuse me.
I actually scared myself to death.
I didn't realize I was going to make a sound, I forgot.
Alright, at so any rate, that's exciting stuff, right?
We made a lot of progress on this one, and I think
the next thing we're going to do is add some
drag-and-drop functionality.
That will be interesting.
So we'll be able to take a sound off of our desktop,
and drag-and-drop it in, and then hear it.
And add it to the List, and then actually hear it.
So that'll be a big one.
We'll do that in the next lesson. Thanks.