- Hi I'm Bob Tabor with www.learnvisualstudio.net,
and in this lesson we're going to add more controls
to our repertoire.
And we'll do it exactly like we did the previous time,
where we copied in some XAML, talked about the Control,
showed you how to access the values of that Control
and so on.
So let's begin by getting our example started off.
You can see that I created a new project called
ControlsExamplePart2,
and I'm going to replace the Grid with one that I had
on my clipboard.
This will create a number of RowDefinitions
and two ColumnDefinitions.
And inside of here, we're going to begin to copy and paste
some XAML for the various Controls that we'll cover.
We're going to start by talking about Controls
that allow user input for times and dates.
And so the first Control that I want to call
your attention to is the TimePicker.
This would allow a user to select an hour
and a minute for your application.
So say I want a reminder at 9:30 PM,
this would allow your user to easily select that
whether with touch or with mouse.
So the most interesting property, I believe,
is this ClockIdentifier property.
It comes with two potential values,
either a 12HourClock that will allow the user
to select AM/PM,
or a 24HourClock, which in the United States,
is known as military time.
So I'm going to choose the 12-hour clock,
and then let's go ahead and run the application.
And you can see that currently, as I'm recording,
it is 4:07 PM.
As I select the Control itself, it shows
a nice pop-up that would look good in a mobile device,
as well as a desktop.
And here I can select different times and choose AM/PM
and then click the check mark for acceptance
or the X to cancel.
All right, and you can see my selections now are displayed
in the Control's body as well.
Very nice.
The next Control that I want to talk about relates to dates.
And there are actually two of these.
The first one is what is called a CalendarDatePicker.
And so when you hear the term "Picker",
typically you're going to see a flyout up here.
In other words, you're not going to see the entire body
of the Control, you'll just see
a little part of the Control.
You click on that Control and it will show you more
items to choose from.
In this case, you'll see a Calendar pop up.
So let's go ahead and run the application as is,
and then we'll talk about some of its special properties.
So here you can see that we get this little Control,
select a date, a little date or Calendar icon
off to the right hand side.
And when I select it, you can see that
we get a nice Calendar here.
Today is selected by default.
I can move up and down in months.
I can choose different dates and when I do,
notice that it makes that selection
and puts it into the visible area of that CalendarPicker.
Now if you take a look here over on the,
let me get this off here,
take a look out here on the right-hand side
in the Properties area, you can see that there are
a number of interesting Properties
like the type of Calendar that we're going to use.
By default, in the United States,
it's set to GregorianCalendar.
However, you can see that there are
many different types of Calendars for various
Asian countries.
There is a HebrewCalendar and others as well, okay?
IsTodayHighlighted, that is interesting.
It's, by default, selected.
You can change the PlaceholderText,
and I'll just go ahead and change that to "choose a date",
and we'll see that the next time we run.
And there might be some other interesting
little things here, but I think that is probably
the majority of the interesting things to look at
with the CalendarDatePicker.
Now the other type of Calendar Control
is actually just called the CalendarView.
And when you hear the word view, typically,
in XAML controls, it means that it is going to be
displayed all of the time.
So in this case, we have a CalendarView control,
you can see that I have a SelectedDatesChanged EventHandler.
So let me go ahead and just create that EventHandler
by putting my mouse cursor on that word
and then hitting F12 on the keyboard,
that should satisfy for now.
We'll come back to and add some code to that
in just a moment.
Notice here that we can make Multiple selections
in the Calendar instead of just one.
Let's see what the other values are.
So No selection, a Single date selection
or Multiple date selections.
Leave it at Multiple and then run the application.
And so you can see today is highlighted by default.
I can make various selections and notice that
everytime I make a selection it highlights that date, okay?
Notice how much space this actually takes up
in our application as well.
Now let's actually handle the SelectedDateChanged,
and you can see here that I've added a TextBlock called
CalendarViewResultTextBlock.
What I want to do inside of that is add
all of the SelectedDates so that we can see them.
Now to get to the SelectedDates, we'll go
into the SelectedDateChanged EventHandler,
and I'm going to copy in some code here
and explain what it does.
So you might think that
what I do here is a little bit roundabout,
but I'm going to explain why we do all of this.
Let me move this over to the side here.
Alright, so what I want to do is get
a list of SelectedDates.
So the sender is of type CalendarView,
so we're going to say give me all the SelectedDates
for that Calendar Control.
Then we're going to Select
and make sure that we're choosing
or projecting out of those selections, the month/day.
The Select statement is a projection statement and link
and we're just choosing the data that we want to spit out
or emit from that statement.
So we're getting all the SelectedDates
but just give me the date/day as a string
and then I want all those dates to be added to an Array.
So I called the ToArray() in the very end of that.
So now we have an Array of strings called SelectedDates,
and the reason I put them in an Array is so that
I can call the string.Join method and separate
each of them with a comma.
And you'll see the effect in just a moment.
Now that we have are joined string,
we can set it as the text property to that TextBlock
that I added.
So let's see how this works.
All right, so now I'm going to start selecting some dates.
And as I select them, notice that they show up
as the month/day,
and they're separated by commas, all right?
So hopefully that little snippet of code will help you
to work with Multiple date selection.
All right, so that's enough with dates and times.
Let us move on and talk about the next thing,
which is going to be a Flyout Control.
And there is two different Flyout buttons
that we're going to look at.
The first one will just pop open
a little message box for us here.
So you can see that...
Actually, let me do this.
Let me put my mouse cursor in that Click,
that Click EventHandler,
InnerFlyoutButton_Click.
Hit F12 in my keyboard.
That'll create the EventHandler stub,
which we'll come back to in just a moment.
And what we'll do is you can see that
many of the Controls actually, in this case,
the Button Control, has a Flyout property.
And what you can put inside of that Flyout property
is either a Flyout or a Flyout menu
like we'll look at in just a moment.
And inside of that Flyout, we can add
any Controls that we want.
In this case, I'm going to create a StackPanel
and add a TextBlock and a Button.
And here I'm just going to put out some text inside of that
little dialog that I'm creating kind of manually.
And so then when somebody clicks the Button,
what we want to do is actually hide that Flyout again.
So let me go ahead and hit F12 again
with my mouse cursor selected on that name,
and I am going to add some code that will actually hide
the Flyout so that when we click the OK button,
that Flyout will hide.
Now you might be still wondering, what does this do?
I don't even know what a Flyout is?
Well, here.
You'll see, it's real simple.
Here's my little Flyout button,
it could be many different controls but in this case,
we're choosing a Button,
and when I click it you can see that there is a little
dialog box that I created with a little message.
And when I click the OK button, it hides.
Alright?
So that's one style of Flyout.
Let's take look at now a Flyout menu.
And you've probably seen these if you've worked
inside of
inside of Windows 10
or inside of the Windows 10 on the phone,
and this will often be useful
whenever you are trying to create a contextual menu
for giving control.
In this case, again, I'm only going to use a Button,
but you'll see that many different Controls
have a Flyout property, a complex property
that we can add this MenuFlyout.
We can also state where we want this placed.
Here in this case, I am saying put it to the Bottom.
But we can set it to the Left, the Right,
the Top or make it full-screen.
Let's go Bottom again.
So we want it below whatever, if possible,
put the menu below the Button.
Next up, we're going to create a series of Flyout
or MenuFlyoutItems,
and each of these could have a Click event
that we can handle, but I am not at the moment.
Here is a FlyoutSeparator, so a little line
that will make sections inside of our context menu
that we created.
Here, we're creating a MenuFlyoutSubItem.
So this will allow us to create kind of a hierarchical menu.
So inside that Item 3, when we click it,
we'll see Item 4, Item 5.
Item 5 is another SubItem Menu Flyout,
which has Item 6 and Item 7.
Alright.
And then also, at the very bottom you'll see that
I have a ToggleMenuFlyoutItem,
and this is useful whenever you want to turn something
on and off and show that
a selection has been made for a little,
a little checkmark in the left-hand corner.
Okay, so let's go ahead and run the application.
And unfortunately, we can't see it.
But I'm going to go ahead and click it now.
I said put it to the bottom,
however there wasn't enough space below it so in this case,
it put it above it.
But notice I have two items and then a separator,
then I have Item 3, which gives me a submenu,
and Item 5 which even gives me an additional submenu.
And then with Item 8, I selected it,
and now the next time I look at it,
it has a checkmark next to it.
So now it is, now it is off.
Okay?
So this is useful for contextual menus.
Again, I want to emphasize that
I'm using a Button in this case,
but we can use many different Controls that have this
Flyout property, where we can add
a contextual menu or just dialog as a result
of clicking on that item or interacting with it in some way.
All right, so the next item that I want to take a look at
is the AutoSuggestBox.
And this will become very helpful to us
whenever we're building real applications
that include the search feature
like a hamburger-style navigation that we've seen
up to this point.
Here again, so that the application compiles,
I'm going to put my mouse cursor on
this little TextChanged EventHandler
and then hit F12 in my keyboard just to create the stub
and my code behind.
And then coming back here to the MainPage,
you can see that I have
a number of interesting Properties here like
the PlaceholderText.
So we're going to say Search or Find Something,
maybe something like this,
so that this is very distinctive, right?
We can set also the QueryIcon.
Let's see what our options are there.
All right, so there are a number of different icons
that we can choose from.
But in our case, let us just go back to the Find icon.
Now let's run the application.
Now what it will do by itself,
there's not a whole lot that it'll do, honestly.
Unfortunately let's move that up a little bit.
So I can start typing in here,
and nothing really happens.
And you might think, "Well, this is not very interesting."
The reason this becomes interesting, as I close this down,
is what you can do with it to filter results.
So let's go back over here into the code behind,
and at the very top, what I want to do
is copy in a new Array of strings that I am calling
selectionItems.
And you can see that this is just a list of names.
And some of them start with the letter F,
some of them start with the letters F-R, F-R.
Some of them start with the letter T, T-A, T-O, okay.
And we're going to see how we narrow down that selection
as we type, as the text is changing
in that AutoSuggestBox.
Now we don't get that functionality automatically.
We're going to have to add some code.
And so I'm pasting in some additional code here.
The sender is an AutoSuggestBox,
so I'm just getting a reference to it
here in this line number 48.
In line number 49, here I'm going to do a Where clause
on that Array of strings, that selectionItems
that I paste in up here.
So we're going to filter that list
by looking for items that start with whatever text
was typed into the AutoSuggestBox.
Then we'll call ToArray on it,
and we'll use that filtered box and pass it
to the ItemsSource of our AutoSuggestBox.
And now that source will be,
you will see a little menu pop up
with all the filtered items that we can choose from.
So let's go ahead and run the application.
All right, so this time I'm going to type in the letter F.
And as you can see when I do that,
I get a number of options.
And then I can use the up and down arrow
to actually select one of the two.
So as I select it, then it removes all the other options.
All right, so let's try that with T.
T-A,
T-A-N,
T-A-N-Y,
and then I can use the down arrow
and then hit enter on my keyboard, it makes that selection.
So the AutoSuggestBox, very helpful,
especially for a search feature
that we'll be adding to our applications.
All right, so let's go on to the next one.
I want to talk about the Slider Control.
And the Slider, you'll see this often used in Windows 10.
It will allow the user to make a selection.
Here, we're going to make, allow them to make
a Maximum selection of 100 and a Minimum selection of 0.
So when we run the application,
you can see that there's this little Slider Control.
And it even has the number above it.
We can control the increments and whether or not
to display that little thing on the top.
But you'll this often used in Windows 10.
We're going to use it too in our applications.
The next thing I want to show,
that kind of goes along with it, is...
I'm going to copy some of it but not all just yet,
I'm going to talk about a ProgressBar.
And a ProgressBar will give feedback to the user
for long-running operations.
So in this particular case,
I can set the Value="57".
So the Maximum will be 100,
but I'm going to hardcode this Value to 57.
So let's run the application,
and you can see that we're 57% of the way through
our progress.
Now this isn't very interesting to set it
statically like that.
Ideally, you would be setting it
through some code behind operation
during the long-running operation.
But let me show you something really neat,
and let me just paste it in
and then I'll explain what it does in just a moment here.
I'm going to remove this Value="57"
and replace it with this strange syntax.
And then let's run the application
and I'll show you what it does.
So what I've done is I've bound
the current value of the ProgressBar
to whatever the value of the Slider is.
So notice as I move the Slider,
notice that I am also moving
the ProgressBar, okay?
So we're binding, data binding.
And binding statement, there is a new binding statement
new to the Universal Windows Platform,
and we'll talk about this in an upcoming lesson.
However, what we can do is say,
"Hey, you know that Slider, that Control called
"MySlider that I named up here?
"I want you to grab its value and bind to it."
Now this will be a one-way binding,
meaning that if I make any changes to the ProgressBar,
it will not reflect back to the Slider.
It's one way.
Any changes at the Slider will affect the ProgressBar,
but not vice versa, okay?
There is also other modes.
We'll talk about those later.
But this is just one of the kinds of things
that you can do with binding in XAML.
It's a very powerful feature that we'll be harnessing
frequently throughout the remainder of the series.
And then I guess the last thing that I want to talk about
is the ProgressRing, another type of progress.
This doesn't give the user
any specific feedback on how far we are through the process.
It's merely just displaying the fact that
something is in operation,
that something is going on and it's ongoing.
You see it's just a little ring,
it just goes up around and around and around
until we tell it to stop.
And so there's a method that allows us to start
and a method that will would us to stop,
or actually, a Property.
IsActive="True" or IsActive="False", okay?
All right, so hopefully you can see how these Controls
could be useful when building real applications,
whether they work with dates, whether we need
some contextual menus or some dialogs
to pop up, to notify the user of something,
to ask for some input.
We also looked at the AutoSuggestBox,
which will be huge when we create our own
search functionality and that hamburgers-style navigation.
We looked at the Slider Control,
which is used frequently in Windows 10,
especially in the Settings window.
And then finally, the ProgressBar
and the ProgressRing, okay?
So great.
More tools under our belt.
More tools in our toolbox that we can use
to build more powerful applications.
Let's continue on, keep building on this.
See you in the next lesson.
Thank you.