Hi, I'm Bob Tabor
with http://www.LearnVisualStudio.NET.
I really don't want to rush through this.
I mean, there were some key takeaways
from that previous lesson that are important enough
to elaborate on as we're getting started here.
So, let's take a few moments
and chat about what we just did in the previous lesson.
First of all, I hope you realize that
you're going to be able to leverage your existing knowledge
of creating user interfaces
and doing so in Visual Studio,
and apply that towards creating
Universal Windows Platform apps.
Did you notice how similar it was
to creating WPF and ASP.Net Web Forms?
That was no accident.
Its a very similar experience
and a very similar workflow.
And as a result, its just as fun,
and its just as easy,
and you know, certainly there's a lot to learn here
but its really nothing to be intimidated about.
So, as we pointed out,
we have a couple of different options
for laying out our application,
at least here at the very beginning.
We were able to make changes to the user interface
in the most visual of ways,
by dragging and dropping controls
from the Toolbox onto the design surface
and we could even resize things and move them around.
And we also can make changes in the Properties window,
to modify the various attributes of the controls
that we see on screen.
However, I think you're going to find that,
just like HTML,
a visual designer won't give you the level
of control that you're really going to want
over the various properties
and how they relate to each other.
So, there's really no way around
learning the actual XAML syntax itself.
And we'll being learning about that in earnest
in the next lesson.
Furthermore, just like ASP.NET Web Forms
and WPF applications that we created,
every screen, or rather every page
has a code behind file that's associated with it,
where we can write event handler code in C#,
that perform operations whenever
the user interacts with our application in a given way.
So, we can also see that there's that same relationship here
between, as we noted in the previous lesson,
the MainPage.xaml and the MainPage.xaml.cs.
In fact, what I want you to notice is here,
in the MainPage.xaml.cs,
you can see that we're in the namespace: HelloWorld
and we're creating a class called MainPage,
notice that it says "partial class".
Now, I'm not sure that we talked about this
in that fundamentals series in C#,
but essentially, we can create multiple files
and all have them be partial definitions of a single class,
stored in different files, whatever the case might be.
But as long as that
file has the same class name,
its in the same name space,
and it has the keyword "partial",
we can create many different files to represent a class.
Same thing is true here.
So notice that this MainPage derives from
an object called Page.
If we were to hover over,
you can see that this is a class called
Windows.UI.XAML.Controls.Page.
Now, if you go to the MainPage.xaml,
and look here at the very top,
notice here that we're working with a Page object
and notice that the class name
is also HelloWorld, namespace,
MainPage, class.
Alright, so that's when I said that these were two parts
of the same puzzle,
two puzzle pieces that go together.
What I really meant to say
is that these are two different files
that represent the same class.
One of these files represents the class
from a visual perspective
and the other represents it from a behavioral aspect.
Okay, and we'll talk about this more a little bit later.
And then, after we kind of built our whole application
and we were able to run it in debug mode,
and I didn't demonstrate this at the time.
But, you know, we can do,
and you can see I've already done this
once or twice here.
You can use break point, you can for example,
if we set this back to local machine
and actually run the application,
we can then click the button
and we'll be in debug mode at that point.
We can evaluate different property values,
variables, whatever the case might be.
We can use all the same little tools
that are available to us
when building any other style of application.
The one thing that I noticed, or that I pointed out
but I didn't really talk about at length was: why?
Why there are so many different emulators available
here in debug mode.
And they're really there to emulate
the different screen sizes and resolutions,
but then also, the different memory constraints
for the different hardware,
phone hardware that we'll find out in the market today.
So we can test our application in a low memory environment
or test our application
in a high memory environment,
as well as screen resolutions and sizes, as well.
And also, what I didn't talk about
whenever we were talking about emulators,
and let's just go ahead and launch the emulator.
And what I didn't talk about at the time were these little,
these actions on the toolbar
and some of them are pretty obvious as to what they do.
You know, like rotation and so on,
and just to see how our app looks
whenever we rotate our phone around,
how to do multi-touch input,
and then also just to zoom the application.
But, then there are also
tools that we can access through this
double chevron icon at the bottom.
And this opens up a whole dialogue
of additional tools.
So for example, if we want to test
our application's accelerometer feature,
we can record a shaking motion,
or some sort of gesture on the phone
and then test it and see how our application responds to it
if we are actually handling events
for those type of gestures.
And we can also do the same thing with GPS
and we'll talk about both location services
and how to test them using the phone emulator.
We'll actually use the phone emulator
to tell our application that we're in a different
physical location then we really are.
Its a great feature.
We also, back here on the main page,
we also built our app utilizing various XAML controls
from the Toolbox,
we use the Button Control,
and then also, you can't see it right now,
but the resultTextBlock.
Down there a little bit further,
there we go, just a little sliver.
(laughing)
And a control has both a visual quality
and a behavior,
and both of these can be modified by you and I as developers
by either changing properties of the control,
like we did whenever we modified the XAML
or the Properties window,
or by writing code in response to certain key events,
at key moments in time in the application's life.
Like we did whenever we clicked the little
lightening bolt icon,
and we said, hey we want to handle
a particular event for the button in this case,
the click event, kay?
Now, as obviously, the toolbox has dozens of other controls,
there are simple controls, input controls
like the Button and like a TextBox,
there are display controls like the TextBlock
that we used,
there are input selection controls
like DropDownListBoxes,
or like the Date Control where we can select
dates and times,
there are grids that can be used to display data,
there are grids and other layout controls
that can be used to help us to position controls
in our application.
You can see that there's actually a Grid
that came automatically out of the box,
whenever we start building our user interface.
We'll talk about these a little bit more in depth,
a little bit later.
But, the funny thing is that we'll actually
spend a lot more time than you might think
learning about layout controls,
they're very important to the adaptive story
of Universal Windows Platform apps.
Layout controls allow a single code base
to be utilized across many different
devices of device form factors.
And so, the Universal Windows Platform API
provides this rich collection of visual controls
that work across all Windows devices.
They allow input via mouse in some cases,
or via finger in other cases.
But that same API also provides us with thousands of methods
across hundreds of classes of namespaces
that allow you to do really cool stuff
with your application.
For example, if you need to access the Internet
to go retrieve some sort of resource,
or if you want to work with a file on the file system,
whether it be on a phone, or a tablet,
or a desktop, or even the Xbox.
Or if you want to play a media file,
like a song or a video,
there are methods in the UWP API,
that make all of those things possible and a lot more,
as you're going to learn throughout this lesson,
a series of lessons.
Additionally, we can harness capabilities available
to specific device families
using what are called extension SDKs
or rather, Software Development Kits.
These extension SDKs contain additional classes
and methods that allow you to harness features
only available on that particular device family.
So for example, if I create an application
that I intend to run across all Windows 10 devices, great.
However, I might decide at some point to add features
that only light up,
which is secret code for become available,
whenever I'm running that app
specifically on a phone device.
So, I can use the Mobile Extension SDK
and gain access to classes and methods
that deal with things like accelerometers, and GPS,
and the camera, and things like that.
So, whenever I choose to light up features
based on a device family,
then I'm writing adaptive code
and you'll hear that term used a lot.
Especially just the term "adaptive".
Now alternatively, I can decide that my app
only really makes sense whenever its running
on a specific device family.
So, here again I might choose to only allow
the app to run on phones
because the nature of the application
relies so heavily on the Mobile Extension SDK's features.
And this would be called a "mobile only app", in that case.
But the point of this is that we as developers
get to decide what device families to target
and which ones to exclude.
And we'll learn more about adaptive
and device specific consideration throughout the series
because its one of the most important
new features available in the Universal Windows Platform.
Furthermore, not only could our application's
core functionality change based on the device family,
but also it's layout and visual qualities.
As well as its navigation.
They may need to change based on the screen size.
So, I can create adaptive triggers
that will modify the layout and the scale
of items in our application based on the size of the screen.
Again, this will be another topic
that I'll be demonstrating often throughout this series
because it too, is one of the most important new features
available in the Universal Windows Platform.
So, just backing up a little bit here,
whenever I sit down to learn something new,
a new technology, new API,
I spend a lot of time just trying to
organize things in my mind,
making key distinctions,
putting things in buckets, I guess you could say.
And learning UWP for me, was no different.
And so, here's what I kind of came up with,
I categorized all the topics that
we really need to understand,
you and I as developers.
And so then, using those categorizations,
we'll go through and we'll learn these things
and it'll hopefully be clear how
they all relate to each other.
So, first of all
we're going to need to learn XAML, as I said earlier,
we talked about how its a language
that allows us to layout our forms
or our applications.
XAML is not specific to the Universal Windows Platform,
its been around for about a decade now.
But building a Universal Windows Platform app
really all starts with the fundamental understanding
of the XAML language
and how to mold it and shape it
to do what we want it to do for our application.
So, learning XAML is number one
and we'll start that in the very next lesson.
Then secondly, we're going to need to learn
how to use C# to call methods of classes
in the Universal Windows Platform API itself.
So, there is the language, the programing languages
XAML and C#,
but then there's also then an API,
a library of functionality that Microsoft created,
that we can tap into and utilize for our applications.
And so you call UWP API methods
to do meaningful things in your application
like load, and save data in a file,
or access the network, things of that nature.
And then third, you know if you only learned C#
from my C# Fundamentals for Absolute Beginners series,
and that's all the C# that you know,
then there's going to be some new C# features
that you're going to need to learn.
Especially like, async, await, and task,
these keywords and what they represent.
And they're used extensively whenever you're working
with the Universal Windows Platform API
and I'll explain why when we get to that point.
But you're also going to need to learn about data formats
like XML, which is kind of the basis for XAML.
Also, we'll cover JSON,
which is JavaScript Object Notation,
because we're going to call web-based APIs
to get current weather from the open weather map API,
or to get comic book character data from Marvel comics
and they'll deliver back their data in JSON,
so we'll need to learn how to de-serialize JSON
into a format that we can work with in C#.
The fourth thing that we're going to learn about
is the tooling that helps us build
Universal Windows Platform apps.
So, we're talking about things like
Visual Studios Designers, and it's wizards,
and the project template itself,
we'll learn about the emulators.
So, many times you're going to learn about
tooling at the same time
as you learn about some specific UWP feature,
just like we did in the last lesson.
So, we probably won't spend entire lessons
on how to use Blend,
or how to use some designer surface, right?
It'll just kind of come natural to us
as we're learning.
And then sixth, and finally,
we're going to have to learn about,
at a higher level, as we step back,
patterns that we should follow
whenever we're building our applications.
So, patterns are guidance,
they're good solutions to common problems.
There are patterns that help us
design our application's user interface,
so that it looks and it behaves
like other Windows 10 applications.
Then there are patterns that apply to navigation,
so that users who have used other Windows 10 applications
feel comfortable navigating through the various pages
in our application.
And then there's also coding patterns,
especially when working with data in C#
and displaying updates to that data,
back to the user.
So, hopefully we took a few moments here
and talked about all these topics that are very high level
and my intent was to orient you in the right direction.
Now, believe it or not we've already conquered
some of the biggest conceptual hurdles
that we'll actually face
when learning how to build Universal Windows Platform apps,
its really not that hard.
Now, all we need to do is just incrementally
add the details,
how do I do this, how do I do that?
Its not really that hard,
its just takes some time to cover the details.
But we can work our way through it
and you'll be building your own apps in no time.
So, we're going to start filling in those details
in the very next lesson.
We'll see you there, thanks.