My goal in this video is todisplay a list of comics,
maybe ten comics at most,for the currently selected
character that we was able toachieve in the previous video.
And the good news is that we'vealready got a template for how
it should work, we're just gonnaneed to call a different API,
we'll get to thatin just a moment.
Before we do that while I'm herein the developer portal, we were
talking about attributionpreviously on this page, but
there's also something we needto consider with regard to
rate limits.
Notice here that it says,most services default to 1,000
calls per day but some servicesmay have different rate limits.
So if this applicationbecomes popular,
that means at most it canonly be launched 1,000 times
by all customers combined.
And that's the best-casescenario where every request
comes through successfully,and it doesn't take three or
four requests to get allthe data that we need.
So if this were a realapplication that I plan
on distributing tothe world at large,
I would reconsider the waythat I go about this.
One of two things, I wouldeither require end users to get
their own key, which is kind of,that's a lot of friction in
the process, or I might actuallycreate a web service similar to
what we did inthe UWP weather app.
I would make a callfrom my local app
to the web service sitting inAzure or wherever, and it would
then go out to the Marvel API,make the necessary call,
grab the data andthen cache it locally.
Now, you can see that you can,in fact, cache results, save
them off locally for a periodof time, at most 24 hours.
But as they say, the data doeschange on a regular basis so
you can't just put itin the database, and
store it until the end of time.
If you do, you're breakingthe agreement that you have with
Marvel, andtheir usage of their API.
And also, we can't just go offand grab the entire database
in one shot, it says onlymake the calls that you need.
So, what I would understand thatto be is I can make a call for
one client, and then cache offthe data that I get from him and
hold on to it forno more that 24 hours.
The second client makes aconnection and it requests data
and I can grab data forhim and cache him as well and
then a third client requestsdata and I can get data for her.
And so now I have datafrom three clients and
I'm making these calls, at somepoint I'm going to get an error.
Where does that specify there?
Yeah, you're gonna geta return code of 429,
which means you'vemade too many calls.
At that point, I can startserving up from my local cache.
Does that make sense?
That's not what we're gonnado in this application, but
if I really wanted touse this going forward,
that's how I would goabout it at a high level.
Let's now navigate to ourinteractive documentation
because what I need to do isfind a list of comics for
a given character.
And so I spent some time andI went through all the different
API's I could call andhow I could call them and
I settled onthe /public/comics API.
And if you take a look,
you can give an optionalrange of characters, so
return only comics which featurethe specified characters
that accepts a comma separatedlist of IDs, good enough.
So for demonstration purposes,I'm gonna grab the real
Spider-Man, the ID forSpider-Man is 1009610, and
I'm gonna limit the numberof comics returned to ten.
And so let's try that out.
All right, it looks like I haveall the data that I need there.
Let me see if I can just grab,I need to grab that out,
let's go all the wayhere to the bottom.
Probably should restrictthis actually, let me make
the call again, but I'm justgonna limit it to two comics.
Why two,because I don't want just one,
I want it to show a collectionand I don't want ten
because it's just too muchto give to json2csharp.
So let's scroll up andgrab all this stuff,
we've done this before, right,we're just doing it now for
comics instead of characters.
Great, okay, we'll go ahead andcopy all that.
We'll go into json2csharp and
I'm gonna paste all that in,I'll click Generate and
then I am going to scroll tothe bottom and copy it all.
Ctrl+C to copy to my clipboard,then what I wanna do is come
over here to my Models folderin my Solution Explorer and
I'm gonna go to the Projectmenu and select Add Class.
And I'm gonna call thisclass ComicDataWrapper,
because that is what theycall it on their side and
I want to use the same term.
Then I'm going to highlight theComicDataWrapper class stub that
they give us and just Ctrl+V andpaste in all of our data and
I'm going to rename this toComicDataWrapper like so.
Now you'll noticeas we go up here,
you'll see some redsquiggly lines under a few
of the items andthe reason for this is that we
already have a class namedEvents in the same name space.
Now I could either add, put thisin a different name space and
it wouldn't be inheroexplorer.models,
it would be hero.explorer.modelsdot I don't know, comic?
Or I could just simplyremove these and
rely on the other definition.
The other definitionto work in that case,
and that's what I'mgonna choose to do.
I'm gonna also remove this Item3because you'll notice that
Stories containsa list of items and
those items would beindividual story items.
So I'm just gonna delete that,we're already accounted for
that, I'm gonnaget rid of Events.
And in this case,the ComicDataWrapper will have
a reference to data which wouldbe a comic data container,
which has a list of results and
those result objects are comics,okay?
So actually, let me go ahead andchange that,
let me change this, andlet me change this to
ComicDataContainer andwe'll change that as well.
All right, so that's how ourclass structure should look now.
And then what I'll needto do is go into our
Facade andI'm going to create something
almost identical to thisGetCharacterDataWrapperAsync,
I'm gonna do the same thing forComic.
So, in fact,I'm just gonna copy all of this,
the entire method,copy it and then paste it.
Now a lot of this will berepeatable so I'm going to pare
these down, take out the commoncode that I need, and
then put that ina helper method.
So, I have to figure outwhat it is I need first.
Let's go back to our call here,
and this is the request URL so
I'm gonna grab allof this here and
I'm gonna use thatas the URI here,
replacing pretty much everything
that I don't need to API key,all right?
All right and solet's trim off the API key here.
And I don't know which, we'llcome back with the numbers.
I'm gonna limit this to ten,
let's hard code ten in here fornow.
And the character, we'll haveto pass that in as well.
So I think that's it, soI'm gonna pass in the character,
that'll be the firstthing we replace.
The API key will bethe second thing we replace,
the time stamp will bethe third thing we replace and
the hash will be the fourththing we replace.
So the only thingwe're really replacing
here is the characters, so
this would be a characteridthat gets passed in.
So we're going to call thisGetComicDataWrapperAsync and
we're gonna pass inan int characterId.
And I see they'repretty much identical
up to the point when wedeserialize that jsonMessage.
So what I could probablywind up doing here is taking
all of this code here andputting it into a helper method.
So private static string,
it'll return the jsonMessage and
this will just beCallMarvel() and
I'll paste all that in.
Now, what we'll need tosend out, let's see.
Is pretty much everythingup until that API key.
So if we were topass all of this in.
We'll call this,the URL then I can make the call
to CallMarvel,let's put it right there
Like that, andwe could do that for now.
We'll come back andreplace that in a minute.
And let's see whatthe problem is.
We gotta return something here,yeah.
We'll return that JSON message.
So we'll just return this.
And we'll make this async.
And, which means I'mgonna name this Async.
Now it looks like I have somediscrepancy here with the URL.
Let's call thisthe completeUrl and
we'll pass that in here,like so.
Obviously we're not going tobe passing in characterId,
what we'll do insteadis pass in the URL.
Okay, now what? Right.
This needs to return a task of
string.
Perfect, and that should work.
So, this is gonna becalled CallMarvelAsync and
what we'll get backis the jsonMessage,
so, var jsonMessage = await.
And then we're gonnawanna compose that URL.
So let's go.
And we'll come back tothat in just a moment too.
All right, so that meansI can get rid of this.
And I can get rid of this,characterId.
And then get rid of all that.
Okay, now we need to make this.
I'm gonna pass inthe URL like that.
And that should work.
So I'm gonna dothe same thing up here.
We'll keep that URL butwe can rip all of that out.
And all of this out.
Okay, we're gonna go here.
Get rid of everything here,except the offset.
And I think I may haveaccidentally deleted the offset.
So let me put that back in,actually right there.
Int MaxCharacters, yeah,that's a int, a const.
And we're gonna get back,we'll make the call.
Okay.
So I realize there's a lotof refactoring there but
this is good because now allthe code that deals with
calling Marvel isin just one method.
But I can get rid of this,
cuz that's only applicableto one case, great.
That should work.
All right, so the next thing weneed to do, though, is because
we copied and paste a lot of thecode from here, let's make this
comic data wrapper, notcharacter data wrapper, right?
Okay and we're going to needto do that here as well,
ComicDataWrapper.
All right, I think we've got it.
Now what we wanna do is, prettymuch, like what we did here,
where we have another method,and we won't need to do quite as
much effort We will
need to do that whole thing withthe thumbnail images, right?
Cuz, some of the imagescould come back like that.
So, I'm just gonna copy this,and I'm gonna recreate it for comics
PopulateMarvelComicsAsync.
And what we want isObservableCollectionComic to
be passed in.
So, instead of MarvelCharacters,it'll be MarvelComics, like so.
And this would bea comicDataWrapper.
So, get characters would be getcomic and it may not have been
worth it to copy and paste andchange all these references but,
at least we'll get someconsistency out of this.
ComicDataWrapperAsync, didI not call it that?
GetComicDataWrapperAsync, okay,I did.
All right, and I gotta giveit the ID that I want.
All right, sowe're gonna also pass in the ID.
So, int characterId.
So we'll give it characterId.
Like that.
All right so, comicDataWrapper.data.results
equals comics.
Here we're gonna go for
each comic, in comics and
then comic.thumbnail. ComicCharacter,
comic.thumbnail.path.
I'm gonna have to make surethat some of these things
are correct.
I'll take a few minutes andlook through these as well.
I'm pretty surethe same thing applies
to comics that applyto characters.
Okay, nice.
All right, sonow we're gonna call
PopulateMarvelComicsAsync whena given item is selected.
So, the first thing that we'regonna wanna do is actually
create a new property.
So prop Tab, Tab, observableCollection
called MarvelComics.
Awesome.
Then I'm gonna want toinitialize it, right?
MarvelComics = newObservableCollectionComic and
then what I'm gonna dois MarvelComics.clear,
cuz I wanna get rid ofany previous items in it
before I make the next call.
And then I'm gonna call it,and I'm gonna pass in.
So, I'm gonna pass inthe character ID so,
let's selectcharacter.id, and
then I'm gonna pass inMarvelComics, like so.
Let's see what the problem is.
All right,we need to add async here.
What else is the problem?
I'm kind of a knucklehead there,
MarvelFacade., there we go.
Now we're cooking.
Okay.
Now since we're makingthe call out to the API,
what I might wannado is go ahead and
reenact the progress ring here.
We'll go ahead and
start it here andend it down here.
All right,let's see if this works.
Oh, I'm a knucklehead.
I forgot the mostimportant part of all.
All right and I see an issuehere, that we already have
a definition for comic andit's dramatically different.
So I'm gonna actuallyname this ComicBook and
the only place I'll need torename it is here, I think.
Well, I guess I'll need torename it a lot of places.
Wherever I wasdepending on it And,
fortunately it's notthat many places.
I will wanna reconsiderits use here,
instead of Comic,we want ComicBook.
We don't need that here as well.
And then when we passin the observable
collection it'll beComicBook instead of Comic.
All right,let's see if that works or
if we have other issues.
All right, so now on theMainPage.xaml, I need to bind
to that new Marvel Comicscollection.
All right, so let's.
Work inside of here.
So, I'm gonna callthis List of Comics.
And I'm gonna put another Grid,and this is going to be the,
actually, it's gonnabe a grid view.
And I'm gonna putthat in grid-row 1.
Lets go ahead and
set the ItemSource
equal to x bind
MarvelComicBooks.
And then setthe IsItemClickEnabled equal
to true.
We'll come back to that later.
And then the ItemClickedequals the event handler,
again we'll comeback to that later.
All right,here what we're gonna do,
Gridview.ItemTemplate andthen DataTemplate.
And then I'm gonna putthe image of ComicBook there.
So, the image,let's go ahead and
set the x:DataType=Data.ComicBook,
and so the source isgoing to be that large,
so X bind thumbnail.large,
and we'll make the.
Actually, we want it small.
We want the small one.
But that does make me think thatmaybe I need a different size.
Okay, we'll come back to thatthought in a second here.
We'll make the Width="100" andthe Height="150",
and that should prettymuch wrap that up.
Bound there, bound there.
That looks good.
Here in the facade, whenwe're populating the comics,
I think I wanna use a differentset of sizes here for these.
So I wanna use portraitin both cases,
cuz comic books are arranged ina portrait not in a standard, so
we'll go medium, portrait mediumand then portrait extra large.
Okay, that should work.
All right let's build it andsee if it works.
It failed.
Hm, I think maybe it's justa naming issue, let's see.
Or, what I'm gonna do?
Yeah, it just should beMarvelComics not ComicBooks.
All right,
very good.
And let's go.
There we go.
Look at that,how beautiful that is.
It looks like it's having a hardtime sometimes with the comics
for the same reason.
So we'll come back andfix that on the next video,
cuz this one's runninga little bit long.
But very cool.
Okay, we'll continue onin the next video and
you click on one of these andwe'll show
the information about a givenitem, give a comic below it.
So we'll do that inthe next lesson.
We'll see you there, thanks.