Hi, I am Bob Tabor with www.LearnVisualStudio.NET.
In this lesson, we'll talk about
the StackPanel layout control, which allows you to arrange
your controls in a flow, by default, from top to bottom.
But then we can also change an Orientation property
to flow from left to right in a horizontal fashion.
We can even change the flow to go from left to right
to right to left if we want to change that property
on a given StackPanel.
And a StackPanel is pretty simple.
Again, it's just a panel, like a div tag almost,
if you're familiar with HTML development,
and inside of that, whatever you put
will be stacked on top of each other or side by side.
And so in this case you can see
that I have a very simple application here called
SimpleStackPanel that you could load up and follow along.
Notice that I use a little plus and minus symbols
here in the left most column to roll up my code
so we can see the overall structure of this application.
And you might be wondering,
well why do we have StackPanels inside of StackPanels?
Why can't we just do something like this?
Well, you'll see that we get the blue squiggly line
and if I hover over the second StackPanel,
we get the familiar exception that the property "Content"
is set more than once.
So a Page only has a Content property.
It does not have a Children property collection.
So that's why we need, I'm just going to Control + Z,
Control + Z, that's why we need an outermost StackPanel
and then inside of that we can put as many StackPanels
or other controls that we want to place.
So inside of this first StackPanel,
notice that I have three TextBlocks
that are stacked on top of each other.
Notice they take up the full width because we haven't
specified a width and by default,
they're arranged in a vertical fashion.
The item at the top will be the first item stacked,
the item at the bottom will be the last item stacked.
So it's done in order.
Furthermore, underneath that third TextBlock,
we have a second StackPanel.
We've set its Orientation to Horizontal.
So it's going to represent, I guess you could call it,
another "row" that's stacked beneath.
And then inside of that, we're stacking things
in a horizontal fashion.
So the leftmost stacked item is a TextBlock
that has the word "Fourth" in it,
the next item that is stacked next to it is a TextBox,
then the next item is a button
with the content, "Sixth", in it.
And you can see the effect that we get.
So we can almost achieve anything that we want to
if we're using the StackPanel wisely,
and as I'll say at the very end of this lesson,
I tend to use StackPanel
actually more than I use the Grid.
I think that it allows me to get the design that I want
and it gives me the flow that I want
regardless of the size of the device
that we're actually running on.
You can also see that I've got a StackPanel
defined beneath it with a simple rectangle.
And the only thing I wanted to illustrate here
was that we can set the height of the StackPanel,
and yet items inside of the StackPanel
can have their own height independent of the parent.
If we were to remove this height,
notice what happens?
Essentially, the Height of the StackPanel is set Auto.
If we were try to set it to star (*), it wouldn't work
but we can set it to a numerical pixel value
or we can just leave it at the default, which is Auto.
Let me go ahead and Control + Z on that
and then save this,
and then let us open up a more intricate example here
that I've created called ComplexStackPanel.
And as you can see, I have changed
from the default viewer, that would be a five-inch phone,
to a tablet, just to accommodate the larger width
of this design that I created.
And notice also, and take a few moments here
just to kind of line up what you see inside of here
with the code, because we have StackPanels
inside of StackPanels inside of StackPanels.
And it can get confusing, however, hopefully,
between the color descriptions,
holding your mouse cursor on it
and seeing the little boundary box that is selected,
you can kind of make heads or tails of how this works.
But the topmost StackPanel defines,
I guess you could call, a row.
And then also, the height of the StackPanel,
this topmost StackPanel, is actually dictated
by the items that are inside of it,
specifically this rectangle with the Fill="Bisque",
it's height is set to 200, so that sets the height
for the entire StackPanel since nothing else
inside of it has a larger height.
Also, you'll notice that I set the VerticalAlignment
of this topmost StackPanel,
and the reason I did that, because if you change that,
it will now get moved to the middle of this grid cell,
and that's just the difference in how
grids work and StackPanels work,
and we'll see an issue with this at the very end
of this lesson.
So let me just go ahead and hit Control + Z,
and that's where we'll bring that StackPanel
up to that top.
All right, since we're stacking horizontally here,
horizontally, I've added a StackPanel
that will be positioned right next
to the right of that bisque color rectangle,
and I'll arrange items now in a vertical fashion.
So inside of that StackPanel, you can see that
I create two other StackPanels
that are oriented horizontally.
So the intricacy continues
until I have the series of rectangles that resemble
something like a Frank Lloyd Wright diagram,
something that he would have been proud of.
Now as we continue through the series,
I will use multiple StackPanels to organize
the various XAML controls, the various XAML elements
on screen, and I've actually grown to the point
where I prefer the flexibility of the StackPanel
to the rigid nature of the grid.
And I guess that is just a personal preference,
but I find that I can usually get what I am after
using StackPanels and margins, all right?
Now one of the things that can help you out
whenever you are working through an intricate
amount of XAML and it's difficult to find your way around
is this little Document Outline.
If you do not see it by default on this leftmost side here,
next to the Toolbox, you can go to the window...
Actually, it's in the View menu.
And if you go to Other Windows, you can see it is here,
Document Outline.
Alright.
So what you can do with this is just kind of
make selections inside of this Document Outline,
and it shows you kind of the hierarchy of items.
We would call this a tree, a visual tree.
And so by selecting each of the items,
we get the little boundary box selection around it.
Furthermore, it is kind of convenient
whenever you want to make changes in the Properties window
and it's difficult to find the exact item
that you are looking for, just by clicking around.
The other thing that we can do is actually hide items
by clicking this left column on the right-hand side
to remove certain items from view.
And then we can also, we can also lock items,
which means that they can't be selected
and therefore they cannot easily be changed
in the Properties window.
I think you can still make changes here though,
if we really wanted to.
I haven't really tried that, but you can see that
it adds this IsLocked="True" to the design time experience.
Remember the d: prefix here that said that this is
ignorable at run time, but it is used by the designer.
Okay?
So that is the utility of Document Outline.
Sometimes, I utilize this whenever I want to
get at or view things isolated from everything else.
Okay, so this last example, I hope,
will illustrate a little gotcha and will help us
to have a better understanding of the difference
between grids and StackPanels,
and something that you need to watch out for
and completely understand.
So let me roll up this code here.
It is almost identical to the first example
that we used in this lesson.
This time, we have a grid that surrounds two StackPanels.
This first topmost StackPanel contains
three TextBlocks, first, second and third,
and then another embedded StackPanel.
Orientation, set to Horizontal, and this time
I just have three TextBlocks that will be aligned
or rather stacked horizontally,
so we got fourth, fifth and sixth.
Below that, we have another StackPanel
with a rectangle inside of it.
Now in this case, you'll look at it and say,
why is there so much space in between this Rectangle
and the bottom of this StackPanel?
How, what is going on here?
And you might think, well maybe what I could do
is set the VerticalAlignment here
equal Top.
And maybe that will help things out here.
"Wait, I lost my first StackPanel."
You didn't lose it, actually.
It is sitting behind the second StackPanel,
the one with the red Rectangle.
And so there's three things going on here at the same time,
and this will hopefully help you to understand
the difference between Grids and StackPanels.
So some controls like image and rectangle controls
that set themselves inside of a grid cell
will be set to 100 width and 100 height by default.
So that is also true of StackPanels.
When you put a StackPanel inside of a grid cell,
in this case the default grid cell, cell zero or row zero,
column zero, then the two StackPanels
are essentially, well, the first StackPanel
has set itself to 100 height and 100 width.
Now the second StackPanel has set itself to 200 height,
but the second thing that you need to understand
that by default the content in a cell of a grid
will be vertically and horizontally centered,
so we have the second StackPanel,
and let's remove the VerticalAlignment.
The default here would be center.
And so you can see that it is actually sitting,
the entire StackPanel is in the center of that cell.
And then the third thing you need to understand
about grid cells is that you can easily overlap items
in a grid cell.
So if two or more controls are set to reside
in the exact same grid cell,
and their HorizontalAlignment equals top
and their VerticalAlignment equals top,
then they will literally sit on top of each other.
So that is what we're looking at here.
We're actually looking at two StackPanels.
This first StackPanel takes up the entire length,
and the items inside of it, however,
are aligned to the top of that StackPanel,
but the StackPanel itself takes up the whole frame.
And then the second StackPanel is set
into the middle of that cell, but it's only 200 tall.
However, whenever we change the VerticalAlignment
and now we move that up to the very top of that single cell
inside the grid, that's when we overlapped.
So I just want you to understand that
about grids and about StackPanels,
that StackPanels will never ever allow you
to put two of them on top of each other
where you cannot see the one that is kind of underneath it.
Whereas grid cells will absolutely allow you to do that.
So there is a couple of different ways
that we could rectify this.
The easiest one is just to use StackPanels
as the outermost container here
in this particular layout.
However, you could also create two rows
instead of just one row and put this first StackPanel
in the top row, put the second StackPanel
in the bottom row, and that'll ensure
that they don't overlap.
You could also set the StackPanels,
you can set its VerticalAlignment to the top
but then use a margin to push it down.
That seems a little more fragile,
I don't know if I like that idea.
There's a couple of different ways
to still make this work even though you are working
with a grid.
But ideally, you'll probably switch to just
using StackPanels.
In fact, like I said a few months ago,
I typically use the StackPanel just about for everything.
I don't use Grids as much as I used to,
except to give the page an overall structure.
And with everything else, I try to use StackPanels.
And so there is this special technique, however,
that I learned when we talk about adaptive triggers
and adaptive layout that utilizes Grids
to adapt from a desktop to a mobile layout,
that wouldn't be possible with a StackPanel.
So it still does have its usage, I just prefer,
in most cases, to stick with the StackPanel, okay?
So that's all that I have to say about the StackPanel.
Hopefully, that was helpful for you to understand it
and how it is different from the Grid.
The next thing, I think, we need to do
is step back for just a moment and review everything
we've talked about up to this point.
Create a little cheat sheet or start that process
that we'll utilize throughout the rest
of this series of lessons,
and then I want to give you an assignment
and force you to write some code
and cement these ideas that we've covered up to now
inside your mind.
And I will give you the solution, we'll talk about all that
in just a video or two from now.
So let us start in the very next lesson
with some review.
See you there. Thanks.