Hi. I'm Bob Tabor with www.learnvisualstudio.net
and this is the solution to the challenge
that I call the "Legendary Layout Challenge".
Now, remember, don't be watching this solution
unless you've already cracked open Visual Studio
and written a line of code or two.
Ideally, you would only watch enough of this video
to get unstuck.
Remember? Okay.
Well, let's go ahead and get started then.
So let's create a new project.
I'm going to call this one LegendaryLayout
and click OK.
And we'll shut that down and open the MainPage.xaml
and I'm going to expose more
of the XAML editor than the Designer,
although I am going to set the Designer to that 13.3 Desktop
just to give myself some more space here.
As you can see, it gives me
quite a bit more horizontal space, especially at 300%.
Let's tone that down to 100%.
That's a little better.
Okay, great.
Now let's take a look at the screenshot.
So I have what looks to be like one row,
I guess you could call it, here at the very top.
And then I have a series of stack panels
that look to be going
in an Orientation equals Horizontal fashion.
And then we'll worry about this last part here
a little bit later, but we know this one is going to be 250.
This one's going to 500 wide.
And this is going to be 300 wide.
We have some margins and things like that too.
Okay, let's get cracking.
So I'm going to get rid of the Grid.
We don't need that.
And we're going to start off with StackPanel.
And inside that StackPanel, I'm going to add a TextBlock,
come back to that, and then another StackPanel
and we said the Orientation is going to be Horizontal.
All right. So far, so good.
Let's remove some of this,
so we can keep this clear in our mind.
I think the text was Lorem Ipsum,
and if I recall, the font size was going to be 48 again.
Okay, and there's going to be some margins and things.
We'll tackle those later.
All right, next up, we're going to need
three TextBlocks inside of this,
or two TextBlocks rather.
They shouldn't be self enclosing.
Let's go ahead and get rid of that.
There we go.
And then I know that final little flag area
with the blue and the red and the yellow squares,
that's going to be another StackPanel of Rectangles.
So I'm just going to add three Rectangles here
then I'll come back to those.
Okay. So that's my basic layout.
You can see kind of what I do.
I get a mental picture of the general layout.
And I can test this theory or this little design
by just looking at what I've got so far
inside of the Designer
but I'm pretty sure I'm close on this one.
All right. So, inside of each of the TextBlocks,
what I'm going to do is go and grab some Lorem Ipsum.
Minimize all this.
Open this file up.
And I only need the first two lines of this
for this first TextBlock.
I'll clean this up a little bit
so it looks better in my code.
Okay, I can get rid of that.
And then I'll put three lines
in this other one.
That's here.
Paste.
That and that.
All right. Good.
And I know that we want the width of this to be 250
and we want the width of this to be 500.
Now let's take a look at what we've got so far
here in the Designer,
and you can see that we've only got one line.
Remember what I said you had to do to fix this?
You have to set the TextWrapping equal to Wrap
in order to get it to kind of flow
through the entire space of that text block.
Do the same thing here.
All right. That should take care of that.
We got some margin issues to work on
but we'll worry about that in a moment.
So, let's see.
We want the Orientation on this to be Horizontal,
and so this will have a fill of blue
and we're going to put the width of it at...
I believe it was 200 by 200.
Height: 200.
And then the fill of the first one, I think, was red
and the fill of the second one was yellow.
And what we're going to need to do here
is actually add another StackPanel
to get these to kind of stack on top of each other.
So let's grab these,
and then we're going to set
their width and height to 100.
Like that.
All right. So now let's see what that looks like.
All right, something not quite right about there.
This, you can see
that the Rectangle wants to center itself
inside of the vertical space available.
So we're just going to set
the VerticalAlignment equal to Top
and that should fix that.
All right. We need some margins now.
Let's go back here and let's view the image.
Looks like there's 20 here, 10 here.
10 here, 10 here?
Maybe 20?
It should be about 10, I think.
So we'll go 20.
Maybe we should use 20.
That does look like a lot of space for 10.
Yeah, it's probably 20.
All right. So we'll just go, for the entire StackPanel,
Margin 10
and then...
Let's see the top.
Do we have some space at the top?
Let's go ahead and put just 20 at the top.
And then we'll put 20 underneath this one.
So, 0,0,0,20 margin
for the text block at the top.
All right.
On this first text block, we're going to set
the margin 0,0,20,0
and we'll do the same thing for the one next to it.
And I think we are pretty much done.
Let's go ahead, first of all,
and get rid of the frame counter.
Save that, and now let's run the app.
All right. I may have too much space here in the top
so I may not have needed that margin there at the top.
However, I think everything else looks pretty good.
So, I think that's the solution to the challenge.
Hopefully you got it.
If you didn't or if you struggle with this one,
go back and watch the video on StackPanel
and then maybe come back to this tomorrow.
All right. Let's move on. We got one more challenge
and it's going to be a little bit more difficult.
We'll see you there. Thanks!