Hi. I'm Bob Tabor with www.LearnVisualStudio.NET
and I'm here with another challenge,
what I'm calling the "Legendary Layout Challenge".
And in this layout challenge, you can only use StackPanel,
so let's take a review of what we got here.
We have a large title here at the top
and then we have two columns.
This column is about half the size of this second column.
It has Lorem Ipsum text, which is just dummy text,
fake Latin text,
has no meaning.
If it does, I don't know what it means.
And then in this third column,
we have a series of squares that almost resemble a flag.
And you can only use StackPanels.
You're going to need multiple StackPanels to pull this off.
Let's take a look at the instruction file.
Let's see what I got here.
All right, again, Legendary Layout Challenge,
only use StackPanel controls.
The designer I set to 13.3 Desktop (1280 x 720) 100% Scale.
That might help you as you're building this.
You're going to need a little bit more
horizontal space to work with.
This TextBlock at the very top is 48 pixels.
The left-most TextBlock will be 250 pixels wide.
And then the next one will be 500 pixels wide,
according to these instructions.
And I also want to say, yes, I know
that I said don't use absolute pixel values,
use relatives whenever you're working
with Universal Windows Platform apps.
However, this is just an exercise
just to flex your layout muscles,
so don't use this in the real world, okay?
You should get the text for these Lorem Ipsum columns
from this file that I'm supplying called loremipsum.txt.
Just copy and paste what you need in there.
The first one, I think, only needs these two lines.
The second one that's larger, wider, needs these three lines
in order to flesh them all out, okay?
Let's go back here
and then take a look at the next instruction
which is most of the margins are either 10 or 20 pixels.
Oh wait, this third area is 300 pixels wide.
It looks like it's split 200 pixels for this large blue box
and then 100 pixels for each of these,
the red and the yellow boxes, okay?
Most of the margins that you'll see used here
between the various columns are either 10 or 20 pixels.
You're going to need to use the TextWrapping property
of the TextBlock in order to get this effect.
If you don't set the TextWrapping property equal to Wrap
then you're only going to see the first line
of the Lorem Ipsum in each of your TextBlocks
and that would not be good.
So I gave you that little freebie.
You can use the image that I'm supplying here,
this UWP-013-Screenshot.png
to reference while you're building the application.
And just like I said before,
try to go through this challenge without my help,
without peeking at the solution video.
Struggle a little bit.
Don't get frustrated.
If you get to the point
where you don't know what you need to do next
then watch just enough of the solution video to get unstuck
and then finally, if you do solve it without my help
or once you solve this on your own
and you're curious as to how I would solve it,
if I took different techniques or whatever,
then absolutely watch the entire solution video,
maybe there's something different about how I did it
from how you did it.
Okay, so we'll see you in the next video.
Good luck.
I know you can do this.