Hi, I'm Bob Tabor with www.LearnVisualStudio.NET,
and this is the solution video
to the Laborious Layout challenge.
Recall, there is no one right way to do this.
Make sure that you are not cheating.
You should actually crack open Visual Studio
and write some code before you get into this video.
If you don't, shame on you.
Okay, let's get started with a new project,
and we're going to call this LaboriousLayout.
Let's take a look at the image
while it's getting set up here.
Keep this handy.
The way that I see this,
let's get that little top area out of the way,
is that we have three Grids.
Each of these Grids are almost identical,
except they have a different title,
and the colors of these Rectangles aren't the same.
I also can see that there are essentially three rows
and so I am looking at this like a Grid,
and yet they're arrayed
with some respect to some stacking.
So I'm going to enclose the entire area with a StackPanel
and create a Grid, get it to look right
and then copy and paste it twice
and change up the colors in the title,
and we should be done.
Add some margins between each of the Grids
and then we should be done.
Okay.
So let's get started and put up MainPage.xaml.
Here again, my recommendation would be
to use this 13.3-inch desktop.
Let's change that to 100 so we can kind of at least
kind of see it.
Move this over here to the right.
So the first thing I'm going to do
is start with a StackPanel, like I said.
And inside that, we're going to create a Grid.
And if you recall, the Grid had three rows and two columns,
so let us go Grid.RowDefinitions
and then below that I'll do Grid.ColumnDefinitions.
All right, and then the RowDefinitions,
let's go RowDefinition, copy and paste that twice
so we have three rows and then we're going to create
two ColumnDefinitions.
One of the requirements was that the width of this
only be 500, so let's go ahead and set that.
I'm going to leave the RowDefinition
set to their default value of auto.
I'm not going to set that, but the ColumnDefinitions,
we didn't really talk about this
but I'm going to set them equal to 1* and 2* sizings,
like so.
That should give us the desired effect of...
You can kind of see, if you split this in the third,
you have this title area as 1/3
and then the content area is 2/3, okay?
All right, next up let's go ahead
and start adding the TextBlocks.
There's going to be two of them.
One is going to be for the title.
So Title 1, and we know the font size of that
is going to be 24.
Equals 24, and it's going to be in the first column
and the first row, so we'll just leave the defaults there.
Here in the second TextBlock, however,
we're going to grab some lorem ipsum text.
We just need that first paragraph.
Let's copy that.
Go back to our project, I'll paste it in right there.
And this needs to be in Grid... whoops.
Whoops.
Yeah, I'm outside the boundary here, sorry about that.
Let me grab both of these guys and put them inside the Grid.
When you are fighting IntelliSense,
in other words when IntelliSense is not giving you
what you think, you may not be in the right place.
I learned that the hard way.
Let's hit Grid.Row="1"
and Grid.Column="1", great.
All right, next up, StackPanel.
So this is going to be that little area below it.
Do we need that?
Yes we do.
We need it because we want it to be oriented horizontally?
And we need Rectangles. We need three of them.
In fact, let me just go ahead and do this.
Fill equals whatever, and then the width will be 100.
Height is 30.
Okay.
And the StackPanel will be in a Grid.Row="2"
Grid.Column="1".
All right let's see what we have so far.
Not much because we don't see some things.
First of all, we need to turn on the TextWrapping.
And then let's set the fills on this one, this first one.
Green,
Black
and I believe, Red.
All right, I know I have some margin issues
but I think we're on the right path there.
Let's see what margin issues we have.
There is no margin there, you don't need any margin here.
So the only margins really along the left-hand side,
which looks to be about 20,
and then the amount of space between the end of one
of these Grids in the beginning of the other one.
So let us put the StackPanel's margin
equal 20, 0, 0, 0.
And then we'll put at the end of the Grid actually...
Yeah, the Grid Margin="0,0,0,20".
That should do it.
Okay, great.
All right, so the hard part is over.
Now let's do this.
Let's just grab the Grid, whole Grid.
I'm going to paste it twice in this StackPanel.
All right, for the second version of our little Grid here,
we'll Title 2.
Let's look at the picture here,
Red, Black, Blue.
And then next one would be Title 3,
and this would be Blue, Black and Yellow.
And before we run it, let me just go over here
to the App.xaml.cs, get rid of the frame counter.
Gone.
And let's run it.
See how close we got here.
Okay, almost right.
Do you see the issue here?
We are centered, and I want to be left aligned.
So let us fix that.
Now I often say that when you write code,
it's more like molding clay than chiseling stone.
So do not be afraid to mold and shape
your applications into place.
Work on them, run them, study them, change them
and repeat the process.
So here we want to do
the HorizontalAlignment="Left",
and that should fix that issue.
Let's see.
Yeah, I think that is the solution.
Runs off to the bottom of the screen,
we'll fix that someday with a whole different control
that'll give us a scrollbar.
But that's the solution, that's one solution.
Hopefully, you got it or got some version of this.
And if not, come back to it tomorrow.
So that is it, now let's move on.
I think you are ready for what comes next.
We'll see you in the next lesson, thank you.