Hi, I'm Bob Tabor with www.learnvisualstudio.net.
In this lesson we'll talk about the ScrollViewer.
I would probably say it's more of a Layout control
than it is an Input control.
But it's not even a Layout control, per se.
It'll just allow you to add a scrollable area
into your application.
Whether for the whole viewable area or just for sections.
We'll use it in this lesson.
We're just gonna add it
to specific Grids or Cells of a Grid.
As you can see, I have a new project called
ScrollViewerExample.
I'm gonna replace the open Grid tag
by adding some RowDefinitions and ColumnDefinitions
which will give us a two by two Grid.
In this first Cell
where the row is 0 and column is 0,
I'm gonna paste in a ScrollViewer control.
You can kinda see it at work here.
There is one little other part of a setup.
You can see here that I've got this Financial.png.
We used this in a previous example.
I just needed an image so I copied and pasted
it into my Assets folder.
Now I'm accessing it in an Image control,
setting it's Height="800"
and I'm setting it's Stretch="None".
This will give us something that we can scroll around
inside of our ScrollViewer.
A ScrollViewer is just that.
It's a viewable area that can be scrolled.
Here we're setting the Horizontal
and the Vertical properties.
The Visibility of those ScrollBars = "Auto"
which means if you need it, show it.
If you don't need it, don't show it.
Now let's go ahead and run the application.
You can see how easy it is to use a ScrollViewer.
(clicking)
This roughly takes up one quarter of the screen.
You can see now I have ScrollBars
vertically and horizontally.
I can move around the entire area.
Great.
That is the easiest case.
Now let's talk about some of the gotchas
with the ScrollViewer.
This took me a little while to figure out
so I want to point this out to you.
If you enclose a ScrollViewer with a StackPanel
you essentially eliminate it.
You can see here that I'm putting
a StackPanel in row two, the second row,
Grid.Row="1" and the first Column.
I have inside of that a ScrollViewer
with it's Horizontal and VerticalScrollBarVisibilities
VerticalScrollBarVisibilities both set to "Auto".
I have the same Image control. All that's exactly the same.
But notice what happens now.
Since we're inside of the context of a StackPanel,
you can see we have no ScrollBars whatsoever.
If I hover over the Grid cell we get something.
But over the bottom Grid cell
we get no way to scroll around.
That is the moral of the story.
The StackPanel kills a Child ScrollViewer.
Having said that, there's one last scenario
that I just wanna show you here.
You can put StackPanels inside
of a ScrollViewer like so.
In this case, I set the ScrollViewer inside
of the second Row, second Column,
and set it's Horizontal and VerticalScrollBarVisibility
VerticalScrollBarVisibility both to "Auto" if you need to use it.
Here I have two Image controls stacked.
You can see I'm using a StackPanel
and then adding two instances of that
Financial.png stacked on top of each other.
This time when we run the application,
you see that I do in fact get a ScrollBar.
Again, because the Parent is the ScrollBar
and the Child is the StackPanel.
In this scenario, the StackPanel is the Parent
and the ScrollBar is the Child,
so we get nothing.
We'll probably never use the ScrollViewer
quite like I did just now.
Typically, we'll use it in the entire viewable area
inside of the Chrome of the application's window
or the entire application itself in the case of
the phone form factor.
The ScrollViewer, very important,
we'll be using this increasingly as we work through
our applications because we'll need to be scrolling through
data potentially when we have lots of it.
Just like we saw in the News, in the Sports,
and the Money apps.
That's all I wanted to say about the ScrollViewer.
Let's continue on the next lesson. Thanks.