The goal of this lesson isto display details about
the character that was selectedin the master list view.
We want to displaythe characters larger
version of the thumbnail image,their name, a description.
And then, eventually we'lldisplay, in the next video,
all the comic books relatedto that particular character.
At least the mostrecent comic books.
Now, there's also another thingthat I wanna address in this
lesson, and
that is, sometimes you're onlygonna get back a small number of
characters that satisfy theconditions that we have here.
Many of them don'thave thumbnails.
We might get an errorwhenever we're making a call
into a resourceacross the Internet.
The Marvel comics APIservers could have an issue.
The JSON that comesback is botched or
isn't quite formed correctly.
The JSON that does come backwhen we try to do that step
that I'm always nervousabout whenever we
deserialize that JSONinto our object graph.
That could go bad.
So, I need a strategy for
recovering whenever ourapplication simply can't
get on the first tryeverything it needs.
So, we'll address that as well.
But let's start offwith the simple stuff.
I'm gonna go over hereto the mainpage.xaml.
And what I want to dois flesh out the grid.
The details grid orthe grid detail.
The detail grid.
All right,let me get into code mode here,
and what we're gonna wanna dois create some RowDefinitions.
And there's gonna bethree distinct areas.
The top row, will be
where we display the detailsof the character.
The second row, will be where wedisplay the list of comics that
character has been in recently,and then finally,
as you click on one ofthose comics, we'll display
the details about a givencomic in the third row, okay?
The next thing we'regonna wanna do,
is now that we have ourrow definitions created,
we're gonna focus on thatfirst row definition, so
we're gonna create anothergrid inside of it.
So, just to make sure weremember what we're doing here,
grid.row = 0, and
I'm gonna make sure to set thehorizontal alignment to left.
Most of these shouldbe defaults but
I'm just not takingany chances here.
And then, inside of that gridI'm gonna create one row
that will display the Name and
a second row, that willdisplay the description.
And then, two columns,
a left column that willdisplay the image and
a right column that will displaythe name and the description.
Okay, so two by two grid.
So, row definitions, and
we'll just set the heighton each of these to star.
Give them equal width there.
And we'll do the samewith column definitions.
The first column,I'm gonna set to auto, And
the second column widthI'm gonna set to star.
Now, all of this issubject to change, so
this is just where I'm starting.
All right, on the left sideI want the image to appear.
So I'm gonna set thatimage Grid.Column = "0".
But actually,I want it to span both rows.
So, Grid.RowSpan="2".
And then, we're gonna need to
populate its valueprogrmatically.
So, I'm gonna set the name ofthis equal to DetailImage.
Next up, we're gonna havethe text block that will contain
the name of the characters.
So, DetailNameTextBlock.
We're gonna setthe column equal to 1, so
the second column,and I'm also gonna
make the font size a littlebit larger than before.
So, we'll set the fontsize at like 32.
And then finally, we'll createanother text block that will
contain the description,if there is one, and
just like the thumbnail,
many of the characters donot have descriptions.
So, that's fine, we just want todisplay it if there's not one.
So, we're gonna set thatin Row="1" Grid.Column="1".
And I'm also gonna go ahead,while I'm thinking about this,
and set the text wrapping.
Because this mightbe a paragraph, so
I'm gonna set the wrappingequal to wrap.
Let me put these ona separate line, so
you can see thema little bit easier.
Great.
All right.The next thing that I wanna do
is go back to our list view,and I wanna make it,
so that you can actuallyclick on one of the items.
So, IsItemClickEnabled="true".
And then,ItemClick="NewEventHandler".
I'm gonna go to thatnew event handler
using F12 on my keyboard, and
what we wanna do is to getthe selected character.
So, the item click event argswill actually give us the item
that was clicked, and that willbe an instance of character.
It's just unfortunatelysaved as an object.
So, we're gonna have toa casting back to character.
So, var selectedCharacter =
Then, I'm going topopulate the easy stuff.
DetailNameTextBlock.Text =selectedCharacter.name.
And we'll do the same thing forthe description.
Now, getting the image todisplay an image will be
a little bit trickier.
We're gonna have to createa bitmap image, and
once we populate the bitmapimage's source, then,
we can set it as the sourceof our XAML image control.
So, this is how you do it.
You might even wannasave this little snippet
to your cheat sheet.
Now, the bitmap image object,we're gonna have to add a using
statement towindows.ui.xaml.media.imaging,
like so.
And we're gonna needto create a new URI.
And we're going to give itthe location by giving it selectedCharacter.thumbnail.la-
rge.
And then, we're gonna giveit the URI kind of absolute.
Cuz it's gonna be a URL.
All right, it doesn't like,oh I didn't spell it correctly.
There we go.
All right, so
largeImage.uri.UriSource = uri,obviously.
And now, it should haveeverything it needs to be a real
bitmap image.
And so, we can do thisDetailImage.Source = largeImage.
That should work.
Let's go ahead and try it.
Okay, so this is an errorI run into occasionally.
I'm not exactlysure what happens.
In this case,I believe this to be
an issue withthe deserialization process.
This is one of thosethings I seek to resolve
by adding some some code,in the very next step.
And we hit thisa couple of times.
All right, buteventually we get data.
Okay, so now,
this will kind of show whetherwe got this right or not.
I'm going to click onone of the items and
you can see the image andthe name.
The image and the name.
Like I said, most of these itemsdon't have descriptions, but
Pete Wisdom doeshave a description,
which is awesome for us,
because now we can kind of workwith the spacing of things here.
If you take a look.
First of all,I gave each of these rows equal
space by giving them both starbut I think I'm just gonna make
this top row auto, andthe bottom row, star or auto.
Probably, star.
And then,
I'm gonna add some marginsaround the size of this guy.
I'm actually gonnapush everything off
about 10 pixels there.
Okay.
So, we've got a littlebit of work to do.
I'll push that up, or that downa little bit as well, okay.
So let's get started in here,in the MainPage.xaml.
I'm gonna go to the DetailImage,and
I'm gonna set its verticalalignment equal to top.
I think that have might havebeen the issue with that.
I'm gonna go to the grid,actually, I think what I'll do,
is go to the entire detail grid,and
I'm gonna add a margin thereon the left-hand side.
So, margin 10, 0, 0, 0.
Actually, I might add 10 fromthe right as well just to
make sure that nothing bumpsup against the right there.
All right,the next thing I wanna do,
is in this inner gridI want to set the.
RowDefinition ofthe top row to Auto.
That should fix that issue.
And then,I also want to set the margin
to the right ofthe text to maybe 10.
And the same would be true then,for the other text block.
So now I'm going to runthe application again, and
I'm going to keep refreshinguntil I find a character that
has a description
Okay.
So, I'm very happywith the results.
Still, wish that the textwas up a little bit higher.
I guess it's finethe way that it is.
We'll just go ahead andgo with that for now.
But do you notice,
we only got three itemson that particularly try?
So, that leads me to somethingI wanted to talk about here.
Which is,
making the call into thisPopulateMarvelCharactersAsync,
it just might not returnas many items as we want.
So, I want at least ten itemsin the list, maybe more.
So, what I'm gonna do is adda while condition here so,
here let's do this again,while Tab Tab, and
what we'll check for
is the number of itemsinside of marvel characters.
So, MarvelCharacters.Count.
While it's less than 10 items,
then we're gonna continueto go through this loop.
And inside of herewe're gonna call await MarvelFacade.PopulateMarvelChar-
actersAsync.
Now, the challenge here, is thatan asynch method might take
awhile to return, so we couldbe looping here a billion times
while this is still tryingto run the very first time.
So, it could be a lot ofcalls out to that method.
That's just the waythat this works.
It works as a promise, and then,
it continues on withthe next line of code.
But that promise may not comeback to us before we actually do
an evaluation on the currentcount of Marvel Characters.
So, to fix this, what I wantto do is make sure that PopulateMarvelCharactersAsynch
returns a task.
And then, we'll just checkthe task, or we'll just wait for
the task, before we continueon with another run of
our while statement, or check onthe while statement's condition.
So, let's go tothe MarvelFacade, and
take a look at whatwe return here.
We do indeed return a task,so that's great news.
Let's go back tothe MainPage.xaml.cs.
And instead of usingthis await statement,
I'm just gonna say, hey,give me a task of T.
Woops.
Task of T, I'm going toneed to add the task
by adding a using statement tosystem.threading.tasks, and now,
we should see it.
Great, and then,we'll just do this.
await t.
So, this will force us to waitfor the first call to finish
before it loops back, and doesthe conditional check, right?
So, let's go ahead andrun the application.
One, two, three, four,five, six, seven.
And now, I'm waiting for it,it's still going, notice that.
And now, we have eight, nine,ten, and a bunch more, okay.
And then,there's one last thing that I
wanna do cuz thiscould still die,
if we're not doing thisjust right, so let's,
I wanna wrap try-catches aroundany code that's gonna make
a call out to a dependencythat I cannot control.
In this case, I can't controlthis call out to Marvel.
A bunch of differentthings could go wrong.
So, in that case,
I'm going to wrap the try-catcharound this line specifically.
Now unfortunately,you can see that when I do that,
I'm going to out of scope withsome other things here so.
What I'll just do is justgrab everything else,
just to make thiseasy on myself.
You shouldn't haveto do this always.
Really, the only thing youneed to wrap the try-catch
around is for this line.
But since everything elsebelow it depends on it,
we'll just do that.
So, essentially,
what we're doing here isswallowing the exception.
We're saying,if there's a problem, so
let's just ignorethe problem and go on,
which means that we'll return tand we'll try to evaluate and
say, oh we still don't havemore than ten or ten or
more items that means we'regonna try calling it again, and
we'll just keep tryinguntil it can't try anymore.
Maybe I should add a counter andsay after ten attempts maybe we
should just give it up butI won't do that just yet.
So let's watch as thesethings filter in.
Okay, so we've got one,two, three, four, five.
And then we got more.
Okay, so you can see that itmade two calls because it
started off with the Bs andit went off to the Fs okay.
And let's just make sure thateverything is still getting
returned correctly.
I just wanna see an itemthat has a description.
Unfortunately, none of theseitems have descriptions.
All right, well that's okay.
I'm pretty sure it works.
So we're gonna stop right hereand we're gonna move on and
we're gonna display a list ofcomics for every item, for
the character that was selected.
So we'll do that next.
We'll see you there.
Thanks.