Okay, so as we get started,
let's focus on creating the Project, copying the assets
and then focus the majority of our time
laying out our application.
We're going to take a slightly different layout approach
than we've taken before,
maybe use a couple different techniques as well.
So without any further ado let me turn off the webcam
so I can focus.
We're going to create New Project.
And I'm just going to call this UWPSoundBoard.
We'll do what we always do here,
we'll remove the Frame Counter completely.
And then what I'm going to do is add assets,
and there's a couple different types of Assets
for this project. You can download these
from the previous video or this video.
Look for the download associated with one of those videos.
Now you'll notice a pattern here,
that there are categories of Audio
and then Icons that belong with those Audio .wav files.
So each of those subfolders have two .wav files
and if we go back to the Images, they'll match.
Just with a .png extension instead of a .wav extension.
The next type of folder we have here are Icons.
These will be used in the SplitView in the Pane
where we display usually a ListView of options.
Each of those represent a category.
Finally, here's the PackageAppXManifest.
And these are logo icons,
icons that are used for splash screen.
Things that are going to be required
as we submit our app to the Windows Store.
Okay, so unfortunately, the way that you copy these in,
not as easy as, personally, I would like.
You'll see that there's a little bit of a weirdness here.
So Audio has a subfolder and inside of there you have files.
So when you drag and drop, for example this,
into your Assets folder, you'll notice
that there's no subfolders in there
and there's supposed to be.
Huh, okay well I guess it didn't copy them in.
So you go to those subfolders and you drag and drop those
and it'll say, wait a second, they're already there.
Like, what? (laughs)
So let's go ahead and just hit Apply to all items.
Yes, and it'll stick them all in there.
So we should have four categories
with two .wav files per category in the Audio subfolder.
We'll take that same approach here in the Icons folder.
I'll just drag and drop that Icon folder,
says it doesn't have anything in there.
We know better, it just didn't add them to the Project.
So let's go and grab, drag and drop, it'll say,
are you sure? We already have them in there. No you don't.
Add them. And we'll do this again for the images,
for each of the audio files.
No subfolders, but we know they're there.
We'll drag and drop, stick them in.
"Are you sure?" Yes, do it.
Then finally let's go
to the PackageAppXManifest folder
that I created, and go through this little dance again.
Alright, so that's out of the way.
We'll come back and we'll use those a little bit later.
I'll go ahead and pull this out, there.
Close up assets, and pop open MainPage.xaml.
So I'm going to take a slightly different layout approach
this time, we will have a Layout Grid
and that'll give us the topmost row,
which will contain a RelativePanel
with the HamburgerButton, back button, and the search,
whatever it is, the AutoSuggestBox.
And then in that second row, we'll put a SplitPanel.
So let's start that process.
So here we go, RowDefinitions, Grid.RowDefinitions.
RowDefinition Height="Auto".
And we've done this at least a dozen times already
so this shouldn't be too hard.
Here we're going to put a RelativePanel.
And this, again, will contain that top matter.
And then below that we'll put a SplitView.
That'll contain everything in the main body.
So in this RelativePanel, I'm going to want to put,
first of all, the HamburgerButton.
I'm going to add a back button
and then I'm going to add an AutoSuggestBox.
Let's just put RelativePanel.AlignRightWithPanel = "True".
Here I'm going to give this one a name
of HamburgerButton.
And then this one would be RelativePanel.AlignLeftWith...
I'm sorry, AlignRight of the HamburgerButton.
And this one would be RelativePanelAlignLeftWithPanel.
That should be pretty much self-evident,
but I'll put it there anyway.
I'm going to add a Click Event here
because I know I'm going to need it.
Go ahead and space these guys out.
I also know I'm going to need to put
for example, FontFamily is going to be Segoe MDL2 Assets
and then the Content will be, let's see if I remember,
"&xE700;"
If I got that right from memory,
I will be impressed with myself.
Which just goes to show, I don't memorize this.
Most people don't memorize these obscure little things.
That's why you have a cheat sheet.
Or you have the cheat sheet called the Internet
you can always reference.
Yep, I got it right. Wow, I'm impressed.
With myself. (laughs)
It's the little things, right?
Okay, so next up I need a name for this Button
so let's give it the name of BackButton.
That's necessary because I'm going to give it the
Click equals NewEventHandler.
Here again, I want FontFamily equals Segoe MDL2 Assets.
And then Content="&#xE"... something or other.
You know I got to the point where I decided
I'm going to put the Character Map right here
on my task bar. And I think this is the one I want.
There's a bunch of these back arrows that have various uses.
But I'll use this one, 0A6.
That should be sufficient. 0A6.
And then the AutoSuggestBox,
there's really not much I need to do here,
I would need to give it a Name though.
So let's give it the name of search AutoSuggestBox.
And I'm going to put PlaceholderText equal to
to "Search for sounds".
I know I want the Width to be 200
from that previous exercise that we did together.
And I know the QueryIcon I want defined QueryIcon.
Then I know that I'm going to handle the TextChanged Event
because we're going to filter the list based on that.
I also know that I want the QuerySubmitted Event
to handle that one as well.
Everything else though, I'm going to leave for now.
We'll come back to that in a while
when we try to actually get that functionality working.
Let's see now, that's the RelativePanel.
Now we haven't touched the SplitView yet
so let's see what we have first before we move on here.
See if there's anything glaringly wrong
with anything I've done up to this point.
These look awfully small, I'll probably change the Height
and the Width of Buttons themselves
and then change the Font.
So I'm going to use Height and Width of 45
like we did in the previous exercise for these Buttons.
So Height="45", Width="45"
I like that, that feels good to me.
And then also I want to set the FontSize="20".
Alright, so that should be good enough for now
with that RelativePanel area.
Okay great. Need some padding,
but we'll come back for that later.
Alright next up, SplitView. Let's give it a name
because we're going to have to reference it programatically.
So MySplitView, DisplayMode,
I know I want that to be CompactOverlay,
I also know that I want the CompactPaneLength equal
to be 45, that would be the Width of the buttons
that I have above it, so I like that.
Then the OpenPaneLength, I don't know, 150 should be fine
but let me just put 200 here.
I seem to remember it's going to be a little bit larger
for some reason
having gone through this once already.
So that's good, so we got that.
And now inside of this I need the SplitView.Pane
and I then need the SplitView.Content.
In the Pane, we're going to have a ListBox
like we've always had, or actually, I'm sorry.
I'm going to do things a little bit different this time.
I'll use a ListView this time.
I'm going to Bind to the items and just use Data Binding
and Bind to a List that I'll create in the code behind
for the MainPage.xaml.
I guess I will work on that in this lesson.
Anyway, I know that we want the is ItemClickEnabled
equal true on this, I know I'm going
to handle the ItemClick event on this as well.
Probably should give it a name. Bummer.
So Name="MenuItemsListView".
And so, let me regenerate that.
And I know I need a Template, and I know I need a Source.
I'll come back to that in a minute.
Now, in this area, I'm actually going to add,
in the Content area I'm going to add a Grid
because I'm going to actually split this into two Rows.
There will be a top Row that'll contain
what's being displayed in the main area
and then below that I'll have the items
that will be displayed.
So I'm going to need some RowDefinitions.
So RowDefinitionHeight="Auto".
So I know, whoops, let's not get here in the wrong spot.
Okay, there we go.
In this top Row I'm going to add a StackPanel
and it's just going to contain TextBlock.
I don't even know that I need the StackPanel, honestly.
I could probably do without it, in fact,
I will do without it. Just get rid of it.
Let's just go straight with the TextBlock.
And we'll set Name="CategoryTextBlock".
Text="All Sounds".
That will be the default text in there.
I'm going to make this kind of like a header,
so we'll set the FontSize="24".
Okay. And then in the lower area I'll add the GridView
beneath that and that'll contain all of our items.
And we'll set that Grid.Row="1".
And I'll call this Name="SoundGridView".
Alright, this is really the key one we want to focus on.
We want to set the SelectionMode="None".
All I want someone to be able to do is click on a sound
and it play the sound, I don't need selection.
I do want to set the is ItemClickEnabled that goes true
because I do want it to be clickable.
So then the ItemClick Event should be handled.
Now I know I'm going to need an Item Source
and all that business and I'll come back to that.
So let's go GridView.ItemTemplate
and then set the DataTemplate
and then let's put an Image inside of there.
And I happen to know that the Height
and the Widths are kind of weird
because when gave the specifications
to the guy who was working on it,
I just gave some arbitrary number
based on a mock-up that I'd created.
As I look at my notes here, I see is it 101 Width.
And we'll have to set the Source on that as well,
we'll come back to that later
whenever we do the Data Binding
in the next lesson.
But there's one other interesting little thing
that I want to stick here as well in this area.
And that is the MediaElement.
The media element allows you to play sounds
and we'll become very familiar
with that two videos from now.
Let me go ahead and give it the Name MyMediaElement.
And I'm going to set a property called AutoPlay="True".
And that just says, whenever I give you a Source,
so Assets/Sounds/Cow, whatever,
just go ahead and play it,
I'm not going to programatically tell you
to start and stop playing, just play, auto play.
Alright, I think that's all that I'm going to do here
in this first video. We covered a lot of ground.
There's a lot left to do.
But we'll come back and get them
on subsequent passes at this.
So at this point there's really not a lot to this app,
it's just kind of the shell
and we'll come back and we'll fill in a lot of this stuff.
Okay, pick it up in the next lesson, thanks.