Wow, can you believe that this
is the 80th video, it's crazy!
This is the largest single video series
that I've ever created for Microsoft,
and I don't know about you, but I am worn out.
I hope you enjoyed it.
The fact that you got to this point means
that you're probably pretty good at sticking with things,
and that quality will serve you well,
because it takes time and patience
to create a successful app.
I mean, I created these tiny little apps in about an hour,
maybe an hour and a half.
However, you're going to likely spend a couple of days,
at a minimum, and maybe a couple of weeks,
really testing and tweaking
and asking beta testers for suggestions,
and making sure it's just polished,
and it's not going to throw an exception at any circumstance.
And you really want to do that,
to make sure that you get a great first impression
and good reviews in the Microsoft Store.
So if you stuck with me through all 80 videos,
then wow, you deserve some sort of medal of honor,
in addition to having a pretty good idea
of what you're doing and how to go about creating apps
using the Universal Windows Platform.
I wouldn't blame you if you never want
to see my face or hear my voice again.
But, if you do like me, and like this style of training,
then make sure you let Microsoft know.
There are Microsoft and Channel 9 forums
and Twitter accounts.
There are plenty of ways to tell Microsoft
what you think about this series.
Now, assuming that you just can't get enough of Bob,
--and I don't understand that,
but let's just go ahead and assume that's possible--
Then, I'd recommend that you check out
the other video series that I've created.
Search MicrosoftVirtualAcademy.com for my name,
or Channel9 for my name.
There are several free training series
out there that you might like,
including HTML5 and CSS3 for Absolute Beginners,
Javascript and jQuery for Absolute Beginners,
there's like a hundred Azure videos
across four different series that I've created.
And a bunch of others.
Maybe those would point you in the right direction
on those technologies, as well.
If you're looking for additional resources on top of that,
then I direct you once again to this series
that was created by Andy Wiggly and Shen Chauhan,
called the Developer's Guide to Windows 10.
And then, furthermore, there are,
I know there are tons of great videos
from the Build Conference in the Spring of 2015,
Those sessions are all available on Channel9,
you might have to do a little peaking around,
but you can find them.
Also, one resource that I didn't tell you about,
and perhaps one of the best,
is available from the developer.windows.com site.
So go out to developer.windows.com site,
and then choose this link, "Design and UI."
This really helped me to start thinking
like a Windows 10 developer,
so I highly recommend the "Design UWP Apps" sections
in the Windows Dev Center.
Now, I hope you already have an app or two in mind
that you want to build,
and hopefully some of the things that you learn
in this series will help you get started.
Now, if you're looking for meaty code examples
that go way beyond what I was able
to demonstrate in this series,
then you'll definitely want to check out this link here.
That will take you to Github,
where there are several dozen samples
that were created by Microsoft.
And there's an exhaustive list here.
Just about any feature that you can possibly think of,
they've got an example of it.
And then, within those projects,
there are multiple examples of it there
of the very advanced concepts, so it's an awesome resource.
You know, I've been perusing the Microsoft Store a lot,
in the past few weeks, both just snooping around
and sometimes because I legitimately needed
to find the solution to some problem or some need that I had
There's a lot of low-hanging fruit
that needs somebody to pluck it off the opportunity tree,
I guess you could say.
In other words, I think that if you look around
and you think hard about the kind of apps
that are successful on other platforms,
then you take a look at the Windows store
and ask, "Of the apps that are available
"to do sort of the same thing,
"are there any features that they're missing?"
Think about how you can introduce apps
that work great on any Windows 10 device,
and the benefits to having the user of those apps
work across an ecosystem of Windows 10 devices.
Not just one specific, either desktop or phone, app.
Think about how you could add Cortana integration,
in order to enhance the experience.
Think about live tiles, and how you can use those,
periodically updating the content on those tiles,
in order to inform the user
without them having to explode the application open.
And just think about how you can
improve the user's experience.
In the end, you know, don't shoehorn features in
that you don't need, advocate for the user.
Make it simple, and then give them the tools
that they need to achieve the end result that they're after.
And keep in mind that you'll be
running a company, essentially.
At least, that's how it's going to look
to those who are actually using your apps.
So, you'll need to grow thick skin,
I'll tell you that from experience.
There are lots and lots of nice people out there,
who will give you great feedback
and will thank you for your work,
and then occasionally you're going to run into
someone who's a little grumpy, having a bad day, right?
And so, you'll want to respond politely to everybody,
even the people who are a little bit mean.
You want to fix the issues in your app,
and you want to get the issues fixed
and uploaded to the store.
So that the users can update
and get the benefit of those updates as quickly as possible.
From my experience, whenever I treat
a grumpy customer kindly, then they usually
become my greatest advocate and my greatest cheerleader.
So, I'd recommend that you do that, too,
Be mature about this.
And, kind of moving on from there,
as a famous motivational speaker was known to say,
"You can get what you want out of life
"if you help enough other people get what they want."
And I truly believe that,
and I think that there's great opportunities
for you to find your niches, to find your customers,
and then deliver solutions that they're looking for.
Alright, before I close, let me put in
one more plug for my website.
Let me show you the url here on screen,
http://www.LearnVisualStudio.NET
where I teach beginners the skills that they need
to get their first software development job
building Windows and Web Apps
for the world's best companies as quickly as possible.
There, you're going to find more comprehensive series
than what I've done on Channel 9
or Microsoft Virtual Academy.
On topics like C# and ASP.NET, ASP.NET MVC,
application architecture, data access,
and just about everything you're going to need
to get an entry level software development job
at a major company.
So, once again, I want to sincerely thank Andy Wiggly.
I feel sorry for him, that he actually
had to watch all these videos and review them,
but he really, really helped me fit about,
I don't know, maybe six months or a year's worth of effort
into about six weeks.
So, thank you very much, Andy.
And again, Clint, thank you, sir.
Thanks to Larry Lieberman,
and others I've worked with in the past,
especially Dan Fernandez, to whom I am eternally grateful.
And finally, I hope, if nothing else,
you've gained the confidence to feel like you can do this.
It's not out of your reach.
Don't get discouraged if success doesn't come easy.
If you hit roadblocks, just take your time
and work through them methodically, and be patient.
I try to make all this look easy,
and for the most part, it really is.
But not everything is simple at first glance.
I have the benefit of editing out my mistakes,
reshooting if something doesn't work the first time,
working off a script.
But real life software development is a little more bumpy,
and there's more struggle to it, no matter who you are.
Everybody has to go through the struggling at some point,
as they begin to learn software development in general,
and then specifically this stuff.
The only difference between you and I
is that I've been doing all of this for 20 years.
I just took tiny baby steps on a daily basis.
Frankly, you already know more about software development,
by watching these videos
or the Absolute Beginner videos on C#,
than I knew in the first couple years
that I was writing code,
so you've already got a great headstart.
But, you can do it.
And when you do it, when you finally finish,
go ahead and send me a tweet
and let me know what you came up with.
I'd love to encourage you, and to just take a look
at what you came up with, it would be exciting for me, too,
and I'd love to see it.
So, I sincerely wish you the best
as you begin your career writing apps for Windows 10.
Good luck, and thank you.