We're almost at the point where we are
going to submit our application for ingestion
to the Windows Store.
However, before we get to that,
let me just show you what I did to resolve
the issue that we left in the previous lesson.
What I did was, I created a simple helper method
called GoBack that contains
all of the functionality necessary
to put the application in a valid state
after we move away from the,
the Search functionality or whenever we hit the BackButton.
So that's the purpose of this GoBack method.
We're going to grab all the Sounds,
we're going to set that title, that CategoryTextBlock
to AllSounds, we're going to set the MenuItemsListView
to no selection,
and then we'll set the BackButton.Visibility to Collapsed.
Then I'm going to call that,
whenever you click the BackButton,
or whenever the text changes in the SearchAutoSuggestBox.
So, if you clear it out completely,
or if you hit the little X in that AutoSuggestBox.
We're going to, first of all, check and see if
that AutoSuggestBox is empty.
And if it is, then we'll call GoBack
and then we'll continue on.
So that's how I resolve that issue
that we left off with in the previous lesson.
Okay, so the next thing we want to do
is talk about deployment for a little bit,
and how your applications will actually be deployed
on the end-user computer.
So as a developer, you don't write
any installers in your routines to install or uninstall
your Windows runtime app, the app that you're building.
Instead, you package your app and you submit it
to the Store, like we'll do in the next lesson.
So, users will acquire your app from the Store
as what's called an "App Package."
The operating system uses information that you supply
in an app package to install the app
and ensure that all traces of the app are gone
from the device whenever they choose to uninstall that app.
So, there's a file called the Package.appxmaninfest file,
as you can see I have it highlighted here
in the Solution Explorer.
Here let me get it up for you so you can see it.
Alright, and if I double click it you'll see that there's
a beautiful designer, but actually what this file is,
is just XML, it just has a nice Visual Studio
interface on top of it so you don't have to
deal directly with the XML.
But essentially that Package.AppXManifest file
is just a document that contains the information
that the system needs to deploy,
to display, or update a Windows app.
So this information that it contains
will include things like the identity of the Package,
any dependencies that it has on other DLL's
or other resources, any capabilities,
capabilities that it requires in order to run.
So, I need GPS to run.
I need to access the file system to run.
Any visual elements, like we're going to demonstrate
in this lesson and extensibility points,
which we're not going to talk about.
So every app package must include
at least one Package.AppXManifest file.
So, the package manifest is digitally signed
as a part of signing the app package.
After it's been signed, then you can't modify the manifest
without invalidating the package signature.
So there's a certain amount of security then
for the end user to ensure that they're getting
the application that you built
and that somebody didn't hack in
and make some changes to it
before it gets installed in their computer.
So after the package has been installed
and the package manifest file appears
in the directory for the install package.
Okay so, as you can see, there are
a number of tabs in this designer.
Things that are related to the Application as a whole,
any 'Visual Assets', that's where we're going to spend
the majority of our time,
'Capabilities', here's where I say,
"hey, I need the internet, I need the microphone,
"I need to make a phone call."
That's what my app needs.
Any 'Declarations'
These are things that I intend to change or provide
as a service to the device or the system I'm running on.
'Content URIs', I'm not all that familiar with honestly,
but the 'Packaging' is important
from a Window's Store perspective,
nothing that we really need to change,
unless we update the version number of our application
and obviously, we'll want to change who the publisher is.
I'll go ahead and change that right now.
So, let's go over to 'Application'.
I think the only change I want to make is
how it's actually displayed in the Store.
And then, I might change the description as well.
'Plays fun sounds
'to amuse and amaze friends.'
Alright, probably need a better description than that,
but that should suffice.
The 'Supported rotations',
we haven't really tested it a lot,
but I'm going to go ahead and select
all of the rotations since we've programmed it
in such a way that it should be able to handle it,
but ideally, we would test this a little bit more
before we just went off and made those selections.
We're not going to do any Tile Updates.
We'll talk about those in just a moment.
But we are going to do is spend time
talking about 'Visual Assets'.
So, let me go ahead and
add in the short name of the application: UWP SoundBoard.
And where I want to show that name,
which versions of the logo, alright.
And it's going to say, hey that's great,
but you don't have a 310x310 logo.
We'll fix that in just a moment.
Now before we get too far into this,
let me talk about, first of all,
let me show you a good page that you need to take a look at.
It's bit.do/tiles-badges
and so, you can see here, on the the screen right now,
this is a documentation from the user experience.
Guidelines that talks about the various ways
that visual assets will be used on the device
on the start screen or on the start menu.
And, I'm not going to take the time to cover all of these.
There's actually quite a long list,
but let me give you a few definitions to begin with here.
A tile is anything, and unfortunately,
it's going to be off to the left hand side
of the screen here,
but you can see, like, this is a tile,
this Movies & TV tile, this Groove Music tile,
this News Tile, okay.
Different orientations and what they do
are a little bit differently, because you can see
that there are some, the News Items has a photograph,
but ultimately, those are all tiles,
in a very general sense.
Now, there is something called a 'Live tile',
which is, that which typifies that what they called
Metro or Modern User Interface,
where there are, there's information that gets flipped.
New information, different information,
so if you have a news application,
you might show three or four news stories
in sequence or give some sort of an update.
But this, too, is kind of a general heading for
specific types of live tiles.
For example, there are 'Tile notifications'.
And these are usually, like, if you see a mail program,
you have six new emails, okay.
There's usually a little badge at the bottom
with a number that tells you how many
items are new and updated and require your attention.
Then are things called badges,
and that will show, actually badges
show you the number of items.
Tile notifications are pieces of information
that are specific on a per user basis.
So if I'm playing a video game,
and my ship actually lands at a planet three hours later,
after I sent it there, then I might get
a notification, a tile notification that says,
"Hey, it's time to come back and play now,
"there's action that you can take."
Then there's 'Badges', like we talked about,
number of six messages that need your attention.
And then there's a 'Peek template',
where you can actually see portions of the content,
like, maybe a photo that will be utilized
if you were to then launch the application from that tile,
so you get to peek at the content inside of that tile,
using a peek template.
And, again, you can take a look at these guidelines,
probably the biggest one that is pertinent to us,
for our application is that we should only use
a small and medium tile.
So there are different size tiles, as you can see here,
there are different size and shape tiles,
and one of the guidelines is you shouldn't use a large tile,
if you're not using tile notifications
and if you're not using badges,
so we should only use small and medium,
not the larger ones, okay.
Now you'll notice that by default,
there are a number of assets that are already,
kind of, predefined for you.
For example, this square 150x150 logo.
You can see that,
that by, well first of all, let me go to All Image Assets,
then that'll give us a longer list,
that usually what you can do is just
choose one of the recommended sizes
or two of the recommended sizes and the other scales
will be automatically generated for you.
Now what I've gone off and done,
because I wasn't really entirely sure
what I needed to provide.
I went off and told my graphic designer to,
"Hey, give me my little logo here
in all these different variety of sizes that they ask for."
And then, I might come back and then
remove the ones that don't make a whole lot of sense.
So, I'm going to take some time here and change out,
like for example, the square 71x71 logo.
I might go here to the little ellipses
to actually select an image file to copy in this slot.
I'm going to go into the Assets folder,
into my PackageAppXManifest folder,
and I'm looking for the 71x71 image, like so.
Now it says that it doesn't like my naming convention
and that it has to provide some scaling
information, kind of, sandwiched between the 71x71
and the .png, do you want to proceed?
Absolutely, go right ahead.
Okay and, so you can see that it puts it there now.
I can also add a background color.
I think we'll just add a background color of,
well, in the case of the tiles,
we want the background color to be transparent
because we want to use whatever the system colors are,
but for the splash screen, let's use red.
Let's see if it'll accept that.
We'll come back to that in a little bit.
All right, so let's go ahead and continue on here.
I'll choose a 300x300.
Okay so, I think that's pretty much everything
that I want to change about this.
So let's close this now and what I want to do
before we leave this topic,
is actually right-click the Package.AppXManifest file
and just say, Open With,
and I'm just going to open with the Text Editor,
or maybe just the XML Text Editor and click OK.
And then you can see all of the settings that we made
in that designer and you can see how they're manifest here
in the XML, alright?
And so, that's really all that I wanted to do.
Let me do this, though.
Let me save this and now let me run it.
I'd like to see if the splash screen pops up.
All right, and you saw the splash screen briefly there.
That's really cool.
Looks like I'm going to need to also add a little space there.
I forgot about, let me do that real quick
before we conclude this video.
And if you recall, I said this several times
how I wanted to put a Margin around this thing,
maybe: "0,5,10,0".
Now let's run it one more time.
There's our cool splash screen,
and that looks pretty nice, okay.
Alright, so ideally we would test this a little bit more,
maybe run it on some friends' computers,
other devices, test with the various mobile emulators
that are available.
But I'm going to wing it
and I'm actually going to try and submit this
in the next video to the Store, so we'll see you there.
Thanks.