OK, we're almost at the end of the core functionality.
Let us focus then on what happens
whenever we get to the end of a round.
We present the user with a play again button.
What happens when they click it?
We'll want to clean out essentially, and re-stock everything.
Grab new songs, refresh whatever
the state of the application is.
So lets go ahead and begin that process here.
So the first thing I know that I want to do
is we're going to hit, lets see...
The play again button click event.
So, what I want to do here is...
We kind of set ourselves up for PrepareNewGame()
by creating a helper method that would do this.
So we're going to add the await keyword
in front of PrepareNewGame() and then
I'm going to make this an async method.
And then I want to take that PlayAgain visibility,
button visibility equal to Visibility.Collapsed;
So now it all really comes down to
whatever we do in the PrepareNewGame.
We've already cleared out the songs,
we've already picked new random songs,
we've already populated the song list.
I think we're good to go there, right?
Yeah, Yeah good.
OK, so now the only thing I think we
need to do is to start the cool down process.
Its StartCooldown(); and I want to fix whatever is
in the... the current... all those TextBlocks, right?
So InstructionTextBlock.Text = "Get ready ...";
and then the ResultTextBlock, I want to set its
text equal to an empty string.
TitleTextBlock.Text, empty string.
ArtistTextblock.Text equals an empty string,
and AlbumTextBlock.Text equals an empty string.
Also I want to set the the _totalScore = 0,
and I want to set the _round to 0.
And that should take care of that scenario.
Alright, is there anything else that I
can think of that I need to do?
Ideally I would come back through here
and I would split all of this code up
into a bunch of little helper methods
and use this kind of as a controller of sorts
that organizes and orchestrates the various events,
but I'm going to leave it the way that it is here.
Just long passages of code, at least for now,
and I think we're pretty much done.
So I'm going to run through a round and play this,
and test it and I'm going to pretty much pause
the recording of the video, just cut out a lot of this
so you don't have to watch me play for five whole rounds,
but when we get to the end with the play again round...
(music plays)
Alright, when we get to that point,
then I will un-pause and we can
see what happens to reset the game.
(music plays)
Alright, so I hit the end, I actually
got three outta five right with a total score of 80,
and I'm going to go ahead now and hit
Play Again and it reset everything.
Lets just watch it play to make sure
that everything got zero'd out.
(music plays)
Alright.
Alright it looks good.
(music plays)
Alright, anyway, lets go ahead and quit.
OK, so I feel good about that.
The next step for us now is to add in
some new functionality where we can
actually try to monetize this game.
So we'll start that in the next lesson.
Thanks.