Hi, I'm Bob Tabor with www.learnvisualstudio.net,
and it's time for another cheat sheet review session.
Let's start with Lesson 37
where we talked about utilizing the VisualStateManager
to create the AdaptiveTriggers.
We said that the VisualStateManager will utilize
triggers in order to manage the states
of the various elements inside of our XAML
and allow us to modify properties
of those elements based on the screen size.
Here I've given you a little cheat sheet that you can copy
and paste every time you need a VisualStateManager.
Yeah, you can get rid of the AdaptiveTriggers,
you can rename the VisualStates,
you can change the Setters to whatever you need
in order to make this work for you,
but essentially here you go.
You've got a great little start here.
Remember that we're creating a VisualStateGroup,
which will contain one or more VisualStates.
We can give the States any name we want.
We can set the Triggers at any size, Height,
and Width that we want to manage or to handle
for our specific application's needs.
I think I said this a couple of times already,
I'm not aware of any specific break points or view
port sizes that we should be using in every single app.
It really is up to your specific application
and what you need.
So you can modify the StateTriggers
and the Setters for each VisualState.
You can see here I've got two States: a Narrow and a Wide.
Anything lower than 600 pixels will
trigger off these Setters, and anything
over 600 pixels will trigger off these Setters, okay?
A pretty simple concept, just need to expand on that
and change things about your application
by adding more Setters based on what you need
for you specific application's layout.
Alright, then in the very next video,
in Lesson 38, all I did was just kind of show you
a technique that I stole, that I credited to the guys
at Wintellect, Jeff Prosise specifically,
that allowed us to create adaptive triggers
that listened for screen sizes and then set
the Grid.Row and Grid.Column
on specific StackPanels that contain the actual content,
moving them over from a more wide layout
to a more narrow layout that requires a ScrollViewer.
And so you want to review that or even riff on that idea.
That's probably a good way to go about it.
Now, we said this isn't necessarily a completely
different way of approaching it,
but you can also create device specific views
in addition to your adaptive triggers.
This would allow you to create views for specific devices.
In this case we can create two folders
at the root of our project.
One would be called DeviceFamily-Mobile.
The other would be DeviceFamily-Desktop.
Then we can add in a series of Pages,
and at run time, it will determine which device
we're running it on and use those Pages appropriately.
You can also leave the Pages in the root
of the Project directory, and just depend on these suffixes.
.DeviceFamily-Mobile.xaml or DeviceFamily-Desktop.xaml.
That might be helpful if you only really have
one or two Pages and you don't want to
complicate it by adding folders.
Then I gave you a good resource to learn more
about this approach from Igor's website.
Okay, next up we talked about Data Binding.
I said that basically Data Binding allows you
to Bind a List of data, so a list of POCOs,
into a control that knows how to render that content.
Now, I just demoed the GridView and the ListView controls,
but ComboBox can also be utilized this way as well,
and maybe a few others.
Let me paste in the code example.
Here I have the XAML that would be required.
First of all I'm adding a name space called Data
that points to a sub-folder called Models in my project,
where I'm going to keep the classes
that will be utilized throughout the rest of this project.
Then you can see that I've created a GridView down here,
and I've set the ItemTemplate
equal to a StaticResource named BookDataTemplate.
Now each instance of Book in the Book's collection
will be rendered using this DataTemplate
that's defined here in the Page.Resources section.
Here I just have a StackPanel
with an Image and two TextBlocks.
You can see that I referenced individual properties
of a given POCO object, in this case the Book object,
in order to Bind those properties to the given
XAML control that I need.
So in this case in Image control,
I'm going to want to give the path to images,
and set that equal to the source,
and for the TextBlocks I would want to grab,
for example, Title and Author,
and set them as the Text properties for the TextBlocks.
Okay.
And then one other thing
that I want to point out here is actually
what kind of you need to do in the code behind.
I wanted to show two things here.
First of all, how I went about
actually getting a List of Books.
I created a BookManager class in that project
that we looked at, and it's responsible for
returning back instances of Book in a List of Book.
And so then by having it as a property of my Page,
I can then Bind to it here in the XAML.
The other thing that I did, you'll remember,
is that in the GridView itself, I wanted to handle
a click event for a specific item so that when sombody
clicks on an item, I want to be able to handle that event.
First of all, I have to enable the click event.
And then I want to set a handler for that ItemClick.
Here I'm actually handling that ItemClick event.
I'm going to use the ItemEventClickArgs
to get that item that was clicked on
and then cast it to type Book.
Now that I have it as a type Book,
I can grab off into the properties that I need
and work with them that way.
And now the final, well actually not the final lesson.
Let's talk about this simple lesson first.
I said that List of Book is great,
but really if your contents are going to change
inside of that collection, you need to use
a different type of collection.
You need to use the ObservableCollection, okay.
Now, finally, we talked about kind of
combining some of these ideas together.
For example, if you intend to use Data Templates
in your application, for GridView, ListView, ComboBox,
whatever the case might be, and you think you're going
to want to modify the sizes of items and Data Templates,
then you need to break out of defining it in the Page itself
and put the Data Template into its own User Control,
and then inside that User Control you can create
a VisualStateManager with the various States
and Triggers and so on.
So we demoed this, and it was I think a five step process.
Let me just kind of copy and paste all of this down here.
Okay, so step one is you're going to
need to add a User Control to your Project
and give it a good name.
Then you're going to cut the content
out of the Data Template in like your MainPage.xaml
and paste it into that User Control.
Then you want to reference that User Control
from inside the Data Templates.
So whatever you remove from the Data Template,
now you're going to replace it with the name
of the User Control that you created.
In this case, I called my User Control the ContactTemplate,
so I would want to reference it like so.
And I added these other properties as well.
I'm not sure you need them, but you can reference them
in case you need to make sure that
your Control stretches the entire available area.
All right, next up then, in the User Control we need to
make a change to all the x:Bind statements
that your previously already had.
You need to add on the Object.Property notation.
So if it's a Contact class that you're working with,
or a Book class, then you need to put Contact or Book dot,
and then the name of the property
that you're going to actually Bind to.
Then the last thing that you need to do,
back in the User Control's Code Behind,
is to make a public property that you can reference
from the User Control that would be
an instance of the POCO itself, right?
So in this case, a Contact property of type Contact
from the Models folder that I created.
You're going to return the DataContext.
The DataContext is whatever is being passed in
from MainPage.xaml to your User Control,
and providing the context of data
that it will actually utilize.
It will be of type whatever it is that's being passed in.
In this case it's the Contact.
Could be a Book, whatever your POCO object is.
Finally then, in the constructor for the User Control,
you want to add this line of code, which will
essentially handle the DataContextChanged event
for the User Control and it will call,
using a lamda statement to call,
the Bindings.Update, which will tell it,
"Hey, refresh yourself, we've got data."
Okay, and you can use all of this,
or most of it actually, as what I've been calling
boiler plate code, and that's a great reason
to have this cheat sheet laying around
so you can just grab the code you need
and paste it into your Project
and make a few modifications to it.
Okay, so that's all we talked about
in the what, previous six lessons or so.
Pretty meaty stuff but not terribly hard right?
We took it in bite-sized pieces.
You're going to use many of these concepts in the challenge,
and it will be challenging.
It will probably take you a couple of hours at a minimum,
to pull this off.
There's no excuse for not going through the challenge.
You need the challenge to force you to struggle to really
cement these ideas in your melon, okay.
So we'll pick it back up in the next lesson.
The next challenge.
Thank you.