Hi, I'm Bob Tabor with www.LearnVisualStudio.NET.
In this lesson we're going to talk about XAML schemas
and namespace declarations.
So, up to now, we've kind of avoided all of this ugly code
here at the very top of our MainPage.xaml.
Take a moment to look that over.
And I want to remind you of some things
that we said at the very outset, when we began talking
about XAML.
We said that XAML is actually just a flavor of XML,
or rather that XAML uses XML
to implement its syntax.
And then secondly, we said, in order to use XML,
or at least use it properly, you have to create schemas.
And a schema's like a contract that both the producer
of the XML and the consumer of the XML agree upon
so that they can work together.
So if that's the case, then where do we find the schema
for XAML, for the page that we're currently working on?
Well, actually, you might have guessed it,
that's lines number three through seven, specifically,
here at the very top of our file.
All right, there are actually five schemas
that the MainPage.xaml adheres to.
It promises that it will follow the rules set forth
in those schemas.
Now, you can see that not only do we define
the schema itself, but we give the schema a namespace.
And a namespace is just like we would use in a C# namespace.
So we say that, for example, if you take a look at
this example that I have right here.
I'm saying that for this particular attribute
of this object,
this attribute is defined in
the namespace
associated with the letter "x",
and that adheres to a schema defined here
at this URL.
Okay?
So the namespace, it allows us to say that a given element
or a given attribute is defined at a given,
at a given schema location.
And before I forget, just so you know,
you won't see this in the code that you create
or that's automatically generated for you.
I added this because this is the way that you used to
have to reference the name attribute of any control.
You don't have to do that any more because I think
they changed the schema, and so now the name attribute
is actually part of the default schema,
not part of this schema that defines
the rules of XAML in general, okay?
Just wanted to make that clear.
Now that means that everything else in this document,
everything that doesn't have any prefix in front of it,
whether it be the "x", the "local", the "d", the "mc", and so on,
that means it adheres to this default namespace
that's defined here at the very top.
So while I have that copied to my clipboard,
I'll just, actually just Control + C copy it.
And then let me open up a new Internet Explorer
and paste it in and try to see what that schema looks like.
Wait a second, I got a 404 error.
Yeah.
You know, actually the schemas
are not really defined here
in the sense that you can go out
and you can look at the schemas.
It's more of just a unique place,
just like namespaces are unique names,
just intended to disambiguate,
the same thing is true with these schemas.
You can't go out and look at them,
but Microsoft, when they implemented their software,
both Visual Studio and Blend
and the XAML parser and compiler,
they adhered to these unwritten rules,
or they might be written somewhere,
but we can't get to them, at least not
from this particular URL.
In fact, it's not really even a URL, it's more of a URI,
a Uniform Resource Indicator that's used as a namespace,
in a sense, to define schemas that we can use
in our document, okay?
I realize that that's kinda confusing,
but there's really just one main takeaway of all this.
And that is this, that everything in our document
does follow a namespace, or rather a schema,
an XML schema that's defined in one of these places.
Now you might wonder what each of these schemas
are used for.
For example, what's really the difference
between this topmost schema and the second schema?
Well, the difference is really subtle, but essentially
this schema defines
all of the UI elements,
so the grid view, the button, and all their attributes
are defined in the namespace that adheres
to the schema here at this location.
Okay, this URI.
Whereas, just all of the rules for XAML in general
are defined here at this schema, okay?
Next up you see that we have a local namespace.
And this is actually not a schema, per se.
It's actually a namespace just like we would use
a using statement, so that we can reference classes.
So say for example I create a Car class in my application.
I would be able to reference it inside of my XAML
because as long as I prefix that
with local:car,
I'd be able to reference it here in my XAML document, okay?
Now the last two are actually used by designers.
So you can see that this actually says something
about expression/blend/2008.
These are actually used to represent the design view
that you see here.
And that you would see if you opened up Microsoft Blend
like we'll do later on.
However, if you look at this little
line number 8, it said that these are ignorable.
So at runtime, we'll just ignore this namespace.
We don't need it.
Furthermore, the only reason why this ignorable
attribute exists is because of this namespace.
This openxmlformats.org/markup-compatibility, okay?
So, yeah, you know, now that you kind of understand
what these do, you can completely forget this.
They have no actionable result
until we get a little bit deeper
into our software development.
Like we'll have to use these namespace prefixes,
especially the local one, and we may have to create one
when we get into working with data,
when we get to working with custom classes
that we've created that represent data.
But that's a little bit a ways off.
Just know that you should never ever modify this code here
at the very top of a XAML file unless you have
a really good reason to do so.
And you almost never will, okay?
The moral of the story is that, yes, XAML is XML.
These are the schemas that it adheres to.
Don't make any changes to this.
But it's what makes everything kind of work together
seamlessly between Visual Studio and the parser
and the compiler, okay?
So, that's about it for talking about
the syntax of XAML, that's all I have.
But we're going to move on to, now,
actually using XAML for the design of our application
and how do we lay out our application using XAML.
We'll start that in the very next lesson.
So we'll see you there.
Thanks.