Okay, so let's get started.
You know that I like to tackle the most difficult
part of the application first and in this particular
application I think the process of retrieving all of the
users files from their hard drive or their device,
other music files from their Music Library and
then finding random songs, like 10 random songs
and their associated, the album cover and the other
meta data, retrieving that off in some capacity will
be the most challenging aspect of this, it's the part
that has I guess you could say the biggest question mark
in my mind and that's why I want to tackle that first.
So in this project, what we're going to do is begin
by setting up a new project and then instead of
going to the user interface first, what I'm going to do
is just do some nominal work in the user interface,
just enough to kick off this process of searching
in the Music Library, grabbing all the songs out,
make sure I have access to them all, and then
plucking off 10 random songs and their associated
albums and then being able to access the various
meta data about those songs.
So let's go and get started, I"m actually going to
turn off the web cam and create a new project,
and I'm going to make sure to create a new
Blank App universal Windows project called
AlbumCoverMatchGame
great and get rid of that,
the frame counter, gone,
and let's open up the MainPage.xaml and I just
want to do one little thing in here and that is to add
a Button Control and I'm going to delete this at some
point, but for now this will allow me just to kick off
the whole process by clicking a button that says
"Click Me" and again, the only purpose of this is
just so that I can have somewhere to kick this off
before I give a lot of thought to the user interface.
Okay, so we're only going to accomplish a couple things
here, first of all I want to get access to the Music
Library and then I want to
choose random songs from Library
and then I guess the third thing I want to do is pluck
off the parts of that song that I need so the metadata
from selected songs, okay and if I can accomplish
that in this video I'd be pretty happy.
Okay, so to get started I'm just going to put
everything here and then as time moves on
I'll start splitting things out on their own methods
and it'll become obvious where things belong and
the responsibilities that will delegate to different
methods in our application, so let's begin by accessing
our Music Library, now for the purpose of this, this
demonstration I have a very large and eclectic music
collection, however, we didn't want to pay any royaties
for all that music, so I asked a friend of mine, actually
I just put it out there on Facebook, "Hey, any of my friends
"out there, could you help me out, I need like 15 songs
"that are like 20 seconds each?"
Okay, and my friend Boyd, he just did some, strummed
the guitar a few times and I copied those files multiple
times for each album, I, as you can see, I edited
the metadata for each song to make it look like
it's its own song and make sure it has the correct
album and artist and the I asked a graphic designer
to create some album, fake album art for all of these
so actually if you go to View and Extra Large Icons
you can see some of the cover art that he created
for me, and so these albums will be, the cover art
will be displayed for a given random song that's
selected from the list of all my songs, but what I
want to do is be able to iterate through all the
folders inside my Music Library and grab out a list
of all the individual mp3s not the pngs, that's only
we're going to work with mp3 files so to get started
in that process I'm going to access
something called
KnownFolders
and it's in the Windows.Storage namespace
so I added that namespace here as you can see.
Windows.Storage and I want to get out a specific known
folder, I want to get at the MusicLibrary so this
will give us access to that special folder that and
on every device and every Windows 10 desktop
called Music Libary so we get a reference to that
it's going to be, I can do var folder equals ... but what's
going to be returned from this is actually a type
called StorageFolder and I'll just type this in
because it's going to be important to remember
that StorageFolders are classes that give us information
about a folder and then StorageFile will be classes
that give us information about a given file on the file
system, we'll see how these all work in a little bit and
so what I want to do is get a list of all of the songs
across all the subfolders inside the Music Library
so I know that I'm going to need a collection and
I want, that collection might change over time so
I'm actually going to start off with an observable
collection so let's go var allSongs equals
ObservableCollection so we'll add
System.Collections.ObjectModel
and then the type that we'll be storing off
are StorageFiles, great.
So we're going to create a new ObservableCollection
of StorageFile, great.
And now what I want to do is get all of the files
in all of the folders and right now I see an opportunity
probably to farm that off because we're going to need
a recursive method and a recursive method is a method
that can call itself as many times as it needs to to like
recurse through folders, subfolders, subfolders, subfolders,
subfolders until it gets everything and kind of it
traverses an entire folder structure so I'm going to
create a private,
private void retrieveFilesInFolders
something like that and I'm going to pass in an
ObservableCollection of StorageFile
and I realized I typed this in the wrong spot,
and we'll just call this the list
and then I'm also going to pass in
the StorageFolder called Parent, this will be the
top level storage folder so in this case for us it'll
be that KnownFolder.MusicLibrary, okay, and here
what I want to do is just go do a foreach
so foreach item in parent.GetFilesAsync(), so this will
give us all the files that are currently in the parent
folder, now the first time we pass in a folder it's going to
be the Music Library folder that we just looked at
a moment ago here on my Windows Desktop but
then we will actually pass in any subfolders and
recursively call this retrieve files and folders.
Now we get a red squiggly line, why?
Well, because this is an async operation ...
remember the formula for async operations,
we can await their completion and in order for
this to work we're going to have to adorn this with
an async keyword and what we would expect back
is a promise that whenever it's finished that it will
it's basically a promise that when it's finished it will
it'll continue on, so we're not going to give it a Task,
just a regular old task but it will still add
the using System.Threading.Tasks namespace like so.
Okay, great, so now what we want to do is we're looking
at every single file that's currently inside the current
folder, now if that item has a file type of .mp3 then
we're in good shape, we want to add that one so
list.Add(item) to our ObservableCollection of
StorageFiles, again our goal here is just to get a list of every
mp3 file in all subfolders inside of our Music Library.
Now the next thing that we need to do is to actually
say, "Hey, not only do we want all the files, but let's take
"a look at all of the folders inside of that parent folder."
So any subfolders, so we're going to call GetFoldersAsync
and this, too, is awaitable so we'll add that so each
item now represents a subfolder in for that we're going
to call the very method that we're currently in,
RetrieveFilesInFolders and pass in both the
ObservableCollection of StorageFile and we're going to pass in the
current parent which in this case would be item.
And why are we getting the green squiggly?
Because this is awaitable and that should fix that,
all right, so what we've done here, just a couple
of lines of code is recursively worked our way through
all of the subfolders inside of my music collection
and inside of any of those subfolders and then and
we continue on until we can't find anymore subfolders,
we'll just grab out a listing of all of the individual mp3
files and add them to a list ObservableCollection
of StorageFiles so each of these songs will be
in our collection, great, so far so good.
So the next thing that we need to do now that we have
a collection of all of our songs, well actually we need
to call it, so let's call and this is awaitable, right?
Because it's Async so await retrieve files and folders
and we're going to pass in all songs and then
we're going to pass in the parent folder.
Now the reason we're getting a red squiggly
is because we've used the await keyword however
what we need to do is add what?
async, and I think that's all we need to do there,
okay, good, all right, so next up what we need to
do is choose random songs from the library and
let's think about how this should work, let's create
another private helper method to help us do this
so we don't have it all there just in that one method,
so private void pick random songs and I guess what
I would expect back from this actually it's not going
to be void at all, it's going to be a list of StorageFile,
okay, so that's what we're aiming for here and we're
going to pass in that ObservableCollection of
StorageFile called allFiles or allSongs
all right, and we get a red squiggly because
we haven't returned anything just yet,
we'll fix that in just a moment here.
All right, so if we're talking about choosing a random
list, and that means we need to use the random object
so Random random equals new random, I want to,
I want to make sure to find random songs
but I want to make sure two things don't happen,
first of all I want to make sure
I don't pick the same song twice and
then I want to make sure secondly that I don't pick
a song from an album
that I've already picked.
Don't pick a song from an album
that I've already picked,
okay, that makes sense, all right, so, in other words,
I don't want two songs from the same album because
every icon that I present to the user should be a different
album cover, all right, that would be counter productive
if I did that so in order to do this, what I'm going to do
is create a while statement and I'm going to continue
looping through this until a certain condition is met,
until I get the correct number of songs, until I collect
the correct number of songs into a list of random songs,
so here let me create var random songs, and these are
the ones that I'm aiming for here and then I'll actually
return at the end of this private helper method so
create new list of StorageFile like so and then at
the very end here, like I said we'll return random songs.
Great, all right, so now what I want to do is just say
I need 10 songs, so whenever we get to the point where
random songs that count is 10 or more, then I want to
break out of this while statement, until then we're just
going to keep looping through there until we get the
all the songs that we need that satisfy our criteria.
So, the first thing I want to do is grab a random number
out so
randomNumber equals
Random.Next()
and then I need to give
it the maximum number
that I'm willing to accept here,
so what I need to do is actually get the maximum
number of songs or a count,
so songCount = allSongs.Count
and that should give me the number of songs and
so I just say, "Hey, give me a random number between
"zero and the song count."
All right, so far so good and then go ahead and give
me the random song, and the random song will be
allSongs sub random number, okay.
Now that would work, we would find the random
song and then we would want to go randomSongs.Add
and then whatever that random song is, but wait,
we can't do that yet, we got to do some checks.
This is where we would do all of this right here.
So let's make sure that these things are not true before
we get too far here, the first thing I need to do is
I want to grab off all the properties of the song and
I need the properties so that I can figure out which
album a given mp3 belongs to, so in order to get
that, I'm going to go randomSong.Properties.GetMusicPropertiesAsync()
randomSong.Properties.GetMusicPropertiesAsync() ... do you see that?
So depending on the StorageFile we can get at special
properties, special metadata attributes of the file
depending on the type of file it is, now we know that
we're working with music files so that's why we're going to
call this GetMusicPropertiesAsync() and it doesn't look
like we need to give it anything but what we get back
from this is something called MusicProperties so let's
go MusicProperties randomSongMusicProperties =
and this is awaitable so let's go ahead and add that
equals await
randomsong.Properties.GetMusicPropertiesAsync
all right, now unfortunately we need to add that
data type Windows.Storage.FileProperties, so far so good.
And then I think we got an awaitable situation here so
let's go async and then we need a task that promises
to return a list of StorageFile when it's finished so you
see how I just wrapped task of t around list of t where
t is a StorageFile, okay, it's a tangled web but it all
makes sense just let's continue on here.
So now we have the MusicProperties for the random
song we picked and we're going to forage our way through
so for every song that we currently have in our
randomSongs, these are the ones that we have already added
to our collection that fit the bill, what we want to do
is look at every existing song that we've added so far
and compare the album name of the new random song
to the ones that have already been added to the randomSongs
collection, so:
SongMusicProperties = song.Properties.GetMusicPropertiesAsync()
and that's awaitable
so now that we have that we're going to do the comparison so
string is null or empty SongMusicProperties.album
actually that's the wrong thing we should be checking,
in this case, what I'm going to do is actually do random,
that should be "random" not "ransom",
muscle memory is killing me right now.
All right, so if the album for the new song
IsNullOrEmpty(), then we don't want
it because that's going to mess up our whole plan
or and this is the check we wanted to do
if RandomSongMusicProperties.Album is equal to
the SongMusicProperties.Album in either case
we're going to flag this as a duplicate, as a duplicate
and so here let me outside of that create
a bool isDuplicate = false
and so now if this is true, however,
then we want isDuplicate equal to true,
does that work?
Yeah, and so then after we've looped through every
song that we've determined that we've got a duplicate
then if it's not duplicate then, and only then, will we
add that random song to our list of random songs,
phew, okay?
And that should do it for that.
Great.
So let's call that pick random songs here,
let's call pick random songs and we're passing in all songs,
easy enough, and what we'll get out this are our random
songs and that's awaitable so let's do await
randomSongs, okay, great, so far, so good and we know how
to pluck off the meta data it's just a matter of where
are we going to put that and this is where some of
the game logic is going to come in, I know I'm going
to want to store off some additional information
and I can't simply or easily add additional properties,
like for example, I want to see if the
given song has already
been clicked on by the user or if it's currently
the selected song so I know what I'm going to want
to do is actually convert the random songs or actually
the StorageFiles into a new class of a different type,
so I'm actually going to add a new folder called "Models"
and I'm going to add a new class to that so Project
Add Class and we're going to call class "song" and it's going
to be a simple POCO and it's only going to have just
the bits of information that we really need for our app
so I need the ID,
I need the title of the song,
I need the artist,
I need the album name
and I need, I'm going to go ahead
and hold onto the StorageFile itself
and so this'll be song file and I need
some other properties that I know for example whether
it's already been selected by the user and there might
be one or two others that we're going to come across,
let me make sure to add Windows.Storage using
statement here, okay, so we're going to come back to that
in just a moment but what I want to do now is pluck
off all the metadata from random, from each of
the songs, the randomSongs, create a new instance
of the Song object that I have here and add that to
a collection as well and so I'm going to create
an ObservableCollection called songs here at this
level so private ObservableCollection of song called
songs, and song is going to be in the models
namespace so I have to add a using statement for the
models namespace here for our project.
Okay, and so what I'm going to do is go ahead and
do that conversion I guess you could call it to grab
off that data
so I'm going to create another
private helper method
and we will pass in a list of StorageFile
called files.
All right and so let's do this, let's go
so these are all the random files, so, like the 10 files that
we plucked off, so I'm going to go for each through
each file in files
and I want to grab off the MusicProperties
for each one of those, so MusicProperties
call it:
songproperties = File.Properties.GetMusicPropertiesAsync
and we know that's awaitable, all right, good, good.
Now one of the things that I want to do is grab off
the album cover so let's focus on that specificially
here, what I'm going to need, I think, is something
called, yeah, I'm going to need a bitmap
BitmpapImage that I'm calling AlbumCovers
so I can save it off, great, as a property.
So, let's grab that first.
So I want a thumbnail
and so I'm going to go
File.GetThumbnailAsync()
and I have to select a thumbnail mode
and this well select it based
on the purpose of the thumbnail and in this
case it's for the music view and then the requested
size in here I guess I'll select 200 as the selected,
as the preferred size, I think I'm actually only using 75,
so I may change that but we also can set thumbnail
options and I'm going to say use current scale, don't
resize the thumbnail, just use the current scale that
we have there, okay, all right, now why are you not happy?
Let's see, oh yeah, here we go.
async and this would be a task, great.
All right, what this is going to return to me is
a StorageItemThumbnail so instead of the var,
I'll just go ahead and type that in, it's:
StorageItemThumbnail and this is just a fancy
name for an image that is associated with the file
and I think this is awaitable as well, go ahead and
put that and make that awaitable, great.
Great, okay, so let's go var song equals new Song object
and now we want to start populating things like
the ID equals
we need to grab an ID so let's just create
int id equals zero and then we'll just increment that here
at the bottom of every iteration like that so the song ID
will be just that, ID, Song.Title equals SongProperties.Title
song.Artist = SongProperties.Artist
song.Album = SongProperties.
And you can see here all the information that I can
get at about a song and this is just all the type of meta
data that we can get to usually from an mp3 file.
I'm just going to pluck out the ones I want,
.AlbumCover ... but hopefully you get the idea here
and that's going to be a type BitmapImage so
how am I going to do this?
So let's go new Bitmap--
BitmapImage, we'll add
the Windows.UI.XAML.Media.Imaging and we're going to
pass in URISource which will be the current thumb
hopefully, no, doesn't like that, hmm.
Oh, I know what I need to do here, ah bummer,
okay, here, this is what we'll do:
var album cover equals new BitmapImage
bitmapImage.
Okay, so far so good, and then you've got to
do it like this, AlbumCover.SetSource then you
can get it the CurrentThumbnail like that and
then I can just say hey, albumcover equals albumcover,
like that, okay, kind of crazy but then it works, and
then finally for now at any rate, I'm going to add the
SongFile as just the file itself that we're iterating
through and then since this is a collection that has
visibility inside this class, I'm just going to go straight
to instead of passing it in so Songs.Add and then
the song itself, okay.
All right, so let's see how if this all works.
Let's actually then call this PopulateSongLists
PopulateSongList passing in randomSongs
and this is awaitable, okay, great.
All right, so what I'm going to do is actually set my
breakpoint right there and let's see if I can build
it first of all, we've been writing a lot of code.
Typically what I would try to do here is break
this down into smaller parts but I've already
been through this once and I already know
the process so I just wanted to rip through and
talk through it and if I ran into problems then
I would stop down and fix it, all right let's click
the button, uh-oh, all right we hit a problem,
let's take a look at the call stack to kind of figure out
what the last thing that happened here, hmm, that's
not very helpful.
All right, so here's what we're going to have to do,
stop, we're going to set a breakpoint
here and start stepping our way through this thing.
All right, so here we go, one big debugging session.
Not really what I wanted to get into, I was hoping
it would work on the first try but sometimes,
whoa, didn't like something right off the bat,
oh, ha-ha, okay, here we go, can you figure out why
it may have crashed on this very first line of code?
Well, there wasn't really any logic, we really didn't
do much, could it be that we didn't declare a capability?
I think that's what it is.
So let's go to the package.appxmanifest and see
if there is a capability
for getting at the Music Library
and there sure is, look at that.
That's how one little mistake can ruin everything.
Okay, hopefully that works, and we can get rid
of that now, it builds, great, let's try it now.
All right, we hit another issue here.
I'll tell you what, let me, let's stop for now
and let me dive in to see exactly, oh, it looks
like an object reference not part of an object,
probably I just forgot to new up something,
so let me figure this out and we'll pick it back
up in the next video, because this one's getting long.
All right. We'll see you there.
Thanks.