Hi, I'm Bob Tabor with
www.learnvisualstudio.net,
and it's time for another challenge.
We're going to work on the Hamburger Heaven Challenge.
This will force you to create
a hamburger-style navigation for a Windows 10 application,
a fictitious application.
Let me walk you through it,
and then we'll go through each of the requirements
just like we did in the previous challenges.
So as you can see here, I've got two main
navigation areas across the top.
To the right, you see the search area.
To the left, you see the actual hamburger button.
When I click it, it opens up the SplitView panel,
or the split panel, rather.
And I can select one of two
primary sections of my application.
When I go to the Financial page, you see that
that's kind of the Homepage for the application.
When I change over to the Food page,
notice that not only does the title change,
but also I get this little icon
that allows me to go back to the Financial page,
the Homepage.
Alright, so you might be thinking,
"How am I gonna do this center area?"
Don't worry, it's all an image.
I just wanted it to look finished, you know?
So, we'll talk about that in just a moment.
But, as you select one of these options,
you're going to load a,
one of two XAML Pages into the Frame,
just like we talked about.
This doesn't do anything inside of here.
It's just an image on that page.
There's going to be a Financial.xaml,
and a Food.xaml.
Each of them hosts a single Image control,
and I'll give you those images here.
Okay, so let's walk through all the requirements for this.
I'm just gonna leave this running so we can reference it.
You can see that I have quite a few resources
for you to consider.
Here are the Food and the Financial PNGs.
These are what you see in those main areas there.
Also, I have this Instructions.txt,
we're going to look at that in the rest of this video.
And then, here are some screenshots that will give you
some guidance on what it should look like,
so that you don't have to rerun the video,
and pause it, and all that stuff, okay?
And I'll mention that in here.
Alright, let me drag this into the recording area here.
Alright, looks like I have two number 9 instructions.
Let me fix that while I see it here, great.
Alright, going up to the top here,
you're gonna need the two images available
with the code for this lesson,
the Food.png and the Financial.png.
And you're gonna add them to the Assets folder
in your project.
Then you have to add two Pages to your app,
a Food.xaml and a Financial.xaml.
And each of these pages will host a single Image control
set to Food.png or Financial.png.
So again, this is an entire Page,
and it just has one Image on it.
We're gonna create a Frame inside of this outermost
MainPage.xaml, alright?
Number 3, you have to create
an app featuring the hamburger style navigation
using a SplitView.
It must display a Search bar in the upper right-hand corner,
a hamburger button,
button on the upper left-hand corner,
and a back button next to that,
and the title of the Page.
So this, we're talking about the Search area here.
It doesn't do anything, don't worry about that.
it has the hamburger button, and,
if we move to the Food, it opens up this back arrow,
and we can see the title here at the very top.
Great.
You have to create two navigation options,
Financial and Food.
So that's what I'm talking about here, okay?
And whenever,
each navigation option will have both,
an icon and text.
And the icon doesn't seem to match Financial and Food.
Pick any icon you want.
Try to match up a Financial and a Food icon.
That would be great.
Just go through the character map
to find something that looks like it might fit.
Number 5, in the main area, you're gonna use a Frame.
Okay, we already talked about that, this main area here.
And when the application starts,
the Financial.xaml page will be loaded into the Frame.
The back arrow should be only displayed
when you're not viewing
the homepage, the Financial page.
So again, only should show that arrow
when I'm on that second page.
And the arrow should actually work,
so when I click it, we should be able to go back
to the Financial page, the homepage.
So the search button and the text box
have to be aligned to the right, like you see here.
And the button has to have the search icon.
So you're gonna need to find that one
in order to complete the challenge.
Try to figure out how to set the placeholder text
in this text box as well.
We didn't talk about this, but there's a special property
that allows you to set that word "search" in there.
But as soon as they start typing, that word will go away.
Try to figure out how to set that placeholder.
Number 9, the back button must use a back arrow icon.
We already talked about that, right?
Font sizes that I used include 24, 28, and 36.
The colors that I use will include LightGrays,
alright, and maybe a MediumGray.
And you should use these images as your guide.
So here's the A, and the B, and the C image, right?
And that will help you out.
And so, just like all challenges,
try to solve this without my help.
Also only watch enough of the solution video to get unstuck.
So, I'm going to supply the solution video,
please feel free to watch it, but struggle a little bit
before you just jump in and watch that video.
I don't want you to just
go right from this video into the next one,
and not actually try these things.
So, if you actually do solve it,
then that would be also a great chance to go
to the solution video and see
how I solved it versus how you would solve it, okay?
Maybe you'll learn a technique.
Maybe you took a different route.
That's great.
There's many different ways to solve this, I'm sure.
Alright, so we'll see what you come up with.
Struggle, that's how you learn.
And this is gonna be a valuable exercise because it
is going to be helpful throughout the remainder of the series.
Alright, so we'll see you in the solution video. Thanks.