Hi, I'm Bob Tabor with www.learnvisualstudio.net,
and in this lesson we're going to talk about
keeping your DataBoundControls updated
whenever the underlying collection
of poco objects changes out from under you.
So previously, up to this point,
whenever we were binding to data,
the only scenario I showed you
was binding to kind of a static set of items.
And so we would bind once whenever the Page
first loads or whenever the App first loads.
However, we need to discuss another scenario,
and that's in what happens whenever we update
that collection of data out from under
our DataBoundControls.
So what happens when I need to programmatically
add new items to the List
or remove items from the list?
Well I want you to take a look at this example.
It's the simplest possible contact manager
application you can build.
Here I'm just going to add my first name, my last name,
and then choose an avatar from a list and click Add.
Now my intent here is to create a new instance
of Contact, add it to a collection,
a list of Contact called Contacts,
and then I'm hoping that my GridView control
in that large white area below my form
will actually then display the new contact.
But as you can see, it doesn't do that,
and I'm left to scratch my head here
and wonder why isn't that working?
Well the reason why that's not working
is because nobody told the GridView
that something changed.
You have to let it know that there
is new information to bind to.
The way you do that is to use
a different type of collection.
So here you can see that I've created
a collection, a List.
And we've done that up to this point,
but it's not going to work for us anymore.
What we need to use is a different type of collection
called ObservableCollection.
Alright, so let me comment out some things
and un-comment out some things.
So now you can see that I've changed
from my List to an ObservableCollection
ObservableCollection.
So whenever you see the term "Observable"
in the .NET Framework Class Library,
that means that your DataBoundControl,
whether it's a GridView, ListView,
whatever the case might be,
will be listening or watching
the collection for changes.
Whenever a change happens,
the collection, the ObservableCollection,
will say, "Hey, anybody who's watching me right now,
I have a change so you might want to go
off and re-bind yourself to me." Alright.
And so let's take a look now.
Let's build the application, and uh-oh,
we get an error.
Why do we get an error that we cannot convert
from ObservableCollection
to a List?
Well the reason is because of the way
that we're binding to our data.
You can see that we're using x:Bind statements.
I didn't really say much about x:Bind
when we actually started using it.
It's actually the newest binding statement
that's available.
It was just introduced with the Universal
Windows Platform, and what it does is it
pre-compiles the bindings before
your application runs even the first time,
whereas in the old style just the binding syntax
that was available previously before the Universal
Windows Platform, it would do this all at runtime.
Now why would you pre-compile?
You pre-compile to improve the performance
of the application.
So what's happening here is when I first wrote
this application against a List,
Visual Studio went out and generated
some source code for me behind the scenes
that I can't easily get to from the Solution Explorer.
I can get to it, it's just not easy to get to.
Now the way to fix this is to tell Visual Studio,
"Hey, go off and re-generate that code."
And the way you do that is you go
inside of your data template
and you just hit, you select everything
inside the data template, you hit Control+X,
you give Visual Studio half a second to think
about it, and then you go Control+V
to paste it back in.
When you do that, it should now re-generate
what we're binding to.
In this case, we're going to bind
to an ObservableCollection instead of a List Collection.
That code should be generated now
when I go to build the solution again.
Bam, it works.
Okay, so let's go ahead and run the application now
and see the app actually working this time
as I type in my name and I choose an avatar.
And there you go.
Our ObservableCollection said, "Hey,
I've got a new contact,
Bob Tabor with the bearded guy icon.
So if you're binding to me,
anybody who's binding to me,
you need to know that I've changed."
And so the grid view says, "Hmmm,
well yeah, I was watching you and I see
that you changed, let me go ahead
and update what I'm displaying on-screen here."
And so there you go.
If you like anthropomorphic explanations of code,
then hey, this was right in your wheel house.
Okay, so one last thing that I want to say
before we move on off this topic,
and that is whenever you're reading articles
online or watching videos, you might come
across a term called MVVM related to binding
to data with your Universal Windows Platform app,
your Windows 8.1, or Windows Phone 8.1 app,
or even the Windows Presentation Foundation app,
all of these XAML-based platforms.
So MVVM stands for Model View View Model.
It is a designed pattern for writing code
on the user interface that binds to data.
Now what I'm showing you in this example
with the ObservableCollection is really
a building block, a first step foundational concept
towards learning more about MVVM,
and I actually cover that topic in depth
in the previous version of this series,
the Windows Phone 8.1 Development
for Absolute Beginners series on channel 9.
So if you want to learn more about MVVM,
you'll want to take a look at all of those lessons
that have something to do with ObservableCollection,
or MVVM, or this interface called
I Notify Property Changed.
Okay, look in the descriptions for the videos
or the titles to see that.
And like I said, this apply that MVVM concept applies
to all XAML-based user interface technologies.
Okay, so that's all that I want to say about that,
but we're going to revisit our little simple
contact manager application in the next couple
of lessons, so we will see you there.
Thanks.