Okay, so this fourth and final project
that we'll work on together is
in my opinion the coolest
and was the most fun to work on.
Marvel was kind enough to allow us
to use their API in this tutorial series,
and build a really cool example
to help us all learn development,
learn development against the Marvel API.
So we'll show you how to create an account on their site
and how to use their interactive documentation
to learn how to make calls and get information back,
how to retrieve their images and work with them as well.
So we're building an application
that I call the Hero Explorer,
and it allows you to, first of all,
just get a random collection of characters
from their database of, I think over 1500 characters.
And so we're just going to like, select one of the characters
by clicking in a master list on the left-hand side
to view the details about that character
on the right-hand side.
So let me find, not all characters have all information,
but typically characters will have a name
and a description below them,
a large image, and then also
the comic books that they've been in recently,
and then clicking on one of those
will show you the name of the comic,
or actually the title,
and then the description of that particular issue.
And so there's a bunch of stuff that we're going to learn
by going through this example.
First of all, we're going to learn how to call
a public API, web API,
interpret the documentation,
create classes based on JSON examples in the documentation,
then de-serialize live data that we request
into those classes.
We're going to learn this master detail
kind of user design experience pattern,
and we're also going to learn how to create
and utilize some of the adaptive layout stuff
that we learned how to do earlier in this series of lessons.
We're going to do a ton of data binding
and working through real world issues
that you're going to probably experience
when building a similar style application.
You'll notice that over here I'm using
an Ellipse and a special brush,
not a SolidColorBrush, not a GradientBrush,
but an ImageBrush as the fill for that Ellipse.
We're going to call special APIs
that require some form of security.
So in the case of the Marvel API,
we're going to learn how to create a cache
using our public API key and a private API key
and then some timestamp value to ensure that, well,
to authenticate the request first of all,
and then also ensure that nobody's tampered with the request
as they inspect it from the client to the server.
And so we're going to learn how to employ
special cryptography classes
in the Universal Windows Platform,
and then finally we're going to integrate our application
with Cortana, and tell Cortana,
say hey, Cortana, refresh the characters in our application
and we'll see it work
and learn a little bit more about how easy it is
to integrate Cortana.
Okay, so this was so much fun,
so exciting to work on,
I hope you enjoy this.
We'll get started in the next lesson.
See you there, thanks.