Hi, I am Bob Tabor with www.LearnVisualStudio.NET.
If you recall from the C# Fundamentals
for Absolute Beginners series that I created
for Microsoft Virtual Academy a year or two ago,
-- it's also hosted on Channel9 --
near the end of that series, I wanted to demonstrate
how events work in C#.
And so, to demonstrate that, I created two
very different types of applications,
but I followed the same workflow and got a similar result.
So I created a ASP.NET Web Forms application,
and then I turned around and created a WPF,
or rather a Windows Presentation Foundation application.
And again, I took the same basic steps
to create those applications, and I got basically
the same result, even though one result
was presented in a web browser
and the other was presented in a Windows form.
I put a button on the form,
you click the button, and we would handle the click event,
and we would programmatically change the value
of Label control to the words "Hello World".
And so, that was a great way for us
to not only learn how C# events work,
but it was also great because, again, it gave you
that confidence that, "Hey I know how to build
one type of application.
I can use the same techniques and workflow
to build another type of application."
And the good news is that you can re-purpose
that knowledge to create Universal Windows Platform apps.
And so, in this lesson, I want to do just that.
I want to recreate that same application
a basic "Hello World" application,
but this time, I'll do it creating a simple,
Universal Windows application and I encourage you
to follow along.
Now, before you can follow along,
you're going to need to make sure that you already have
Visual Studio 2015 installed.
Any edition will do.
Express, Community, or one of the paid editions,
that's great.
And then, secondly, you're going to need to make sure
that you have the Emulators installed,
just like we talked about in the previous lesson.
And so, make sure you have that.
I'm not going to demonstrate how to do that.
There's plenty of resources online
that'll explain how to do it.
But, assuming that you've got all of that installed
and we're ready to go, let's go ahead and get started
by creating a new project. There's a bunch of different ways
in Visual Studio to do this.
But I'm going to create a new project by clicking
on the New Project link in the Start page.
That'll open up the New Project dialog in Visual Studio.
We want to, on the left-hand side,
select Installed templates, Visual C#, Windows,
Windows Universal, and then, in the center,
we'll see a series of templates.
We want to choose the top one, a Blank App.
Windows Universal Application template.
And then I'm going to change the name
from whatever the default is to simply "HelloWorld",
and we'll click the OK button in the lower right-hand corner.
And it's take Visual Studio a moment or two
to get it all set up for us.
Okay, so what we want to do first of all
is go over to the right-hand side
and to the Solution Explorer window,
and I want to double click the MainPage.xaml file.
It'll open up that file in a special type of designer
that has two panes.
The top pane is a visual designer, and the lower pane
is a textual code-based designer.
It allows us to edit the code that will be used
to generate objects on screen.
And so the language that we'll write
in that lower pane is XAML.
So I'll refer to this as the XAML editor.
We'll talk about XAML in a video or two from now at length.
But, in this top pane, you can see that we get
a visual representation of our application.
And you can see that we're actually looking at
a kind of a rendering of how it would look
if we were to design our application or run our application
on a five inch phone screen
with a resolution of 1920 by 1080.
Now this is a 300% scale, so it's, it blew it up really large
so we can see it.
A little bit too large, actually.
We'll change that in just a moment.
Notice that we can also view what our application's
user interface would look like in portrait
or in landscape mode by toggling the little buttons
here at the top.
But again, this is a little bit large,
we have to scroll around on the screen just to see
the entire design surface.
So we can make it a little bit smaller by going
to the zoom window in the lower left-hand corner.
And I'm just going to choose like 33%.
Now that won't completely compact it down
for our viewing pleasure.
However, it makes it much smaller and manageable.
What we're going to do is start off by adding some controls
onto this designer surface, just to kind of break into
exactly how this all works.
So, over on the left-hand side, there should be a little tab
sticking out called Toolbox.
And if you click it, the Toolbox window will jettison out
from the right-hand side.
I'm actually going to use this little pin
in the upper right-hand corner of that window.
And I click it once, and that will turn off auto-hide.
So now that Toolbox window is automatically docked
over here on the left-hand side.
And if you don't like the way that it's positioned,
you can just, again, position it any way you want to
using your mouse and the little border area between
the Toolbox and the main area.
And you'll notice that if we were to roll up here
to the very top, that there are a couple of categories
of controls that can be added, common XAML controls,
or all XAML controls.
We'll go through a bunch of these throughout this series.
We basically want to work with just some common ones
to start off with.
So I'm going to drag and drop a Button control
from the Toolbox, onto the design surface.
So here we go, dragging and dropping.
And notice when I do, it drops it right where
my mouse cursor was.
And, hopefully you notice also, here, in this XAML editor
that it added this line of code in line number 11.
It created a tag,
which is an opening and closing angle bracket.
Very similar to what you would see in HTML,
and yet this is not HTML.
But similar in the sense that you use HTML to lay out
the design of a web page.
Same is true with XAML.
We'll use the XAML programming language
to easily lay out the various controls
and the layout for our application.
Notice that we created a button control
and it has a number of different properties
like the name of that control,
the content of that control.
Also the alignment, the horizontal alignment
and the vertical alignment, and then margin.
And that margin, as you can see, is based on,
here, this little visual view of it.
It's 10 pixels from the top and 68 pixels from the left.
And so, that's where the alignments come into play,
the horizontal alignment left, that's what we're aligning to
68 pixels, however, from the left side,
and then 10 pixels from the top.
And then, for the right-hand side and the bottom,
well, those are set to zero because we're really not
worried about those.
We'll talk about this a little bit more later on.
However, just notice that there are attributes or properties
of the elements that we add in our XAML editor.
So now if I wanted to change the name of this button,
the programmatic name that we'll access it with,
I can just call this the Click button or Click Me button.
Maybe I'll change that.
ClickMeButton.
And I can also change the content here as well,
by typing in Click Me to the Content area.
Notice that when I do that, it changes the visual attribute
of the button to "Click Me" instead of
whatever was in there before.
Now there's also a third way that I can make modifications
to this object, to this button object.
We see it here in the designer.
We see it here in the XAML editor.
But then also here in the right-hand side
of the Properties window, we can make changes
by finding a property that we want to modify like,
for example, the text property or some common properties
like the content.
And we can change it by just modifying
the little Property editor and hitting enter
on our keyboard.
Notice when I did that, it modified not only
what we see here in the designer, but then also
what we see here in the XAML editor.
Change the content property to the value "Click This".
And so I guess that's really the first thing
that I wanted to demonstrate, was that these are essentially
three different views of the same object.
One is visual, one is textual,
and the other is a Property editor.
But we can make changes in any of these and they'll show up
in the other one, so they're all connected together.
The other thing that I want to do is I'm actually going to
change the font size.
So I'm going to go to the Text section of the Properties window
and I'm going to change this from 11.25 points
to, oh let's scroll down and it's off the screen here,
but I'm going to change it to 48 points.
And when I do, you can see the Click Me button
is very large.
Now that's not actually what I wanted to do.
Let's change this back to like 12 points.
All right, that seems reasonable.
Instead, what I wanted to do was actually go over here
to the TextBlock control in the Toolbox.
I'm going to drag and drop that onto my design surface as well.
You can see now that it also
is represented on the visual surface.
It's here in our XAML editor, and now we can also
make changes to it and, for example, change the name
to ResultTextBlock.
And here's where I wanted to actually change
the text property to 48 point.
And you can see that it made that font very large.
And it's showing, currently, the text value "TextBlock",
but I can type anything here and it will be displayed.
Whoops.
It'll be displayed in that TextBlock.
And that TextBlock is just basically like a label.
Somewhere where we can put static text.
But actually, I'm going to clear this out completely.
I'm going to go to the end of this line.
And notice that the font size is set to 64.
And you might say, "Wait a second here.
I see that it's 48 point over here in the Properties editor,
but it's 64 units here in the Font Size attribute
in the XAML editor.
I thought those were supposed to be the same."
Well actually, they are the same.
The XAML editor is rendering values
in device independent pixels, or rather DIPs.
The Properties window is actually representing values
in points, which are a fixed size of 1/72nd of an inch.
So, it's a very complicated topic,
but we're going to revisit this when we take into consideration
the various screen sizes and resolutions
on the various form factors that Windows 10 will run on
as we're building our applications.
As you know, you can have a large screen
with a low resolution, or vice versa.
And so, units of measurement like inches
are kind of irrelevant.
Instead we need a new unit of measurement that accounts
for both screen size and resolution to determine
the sizes of things like controls that we add to our apps.
All right, the next thing that I want to do
is actually select the button control
and then, over here in the Properties window,
I'm going to select this little bolt of lightning
button over here, and that will show us
all of the events that will be handled for the button.
And the very first one is the Click event.
So I'm just going to double click inside of that text box
in the Property editor, and we'll open up
the MainPage.xaml.cs file.
Now notice here in our Solution Explorer,
that the MainPage.xaml is related
to the MainPage.xaml.cs file.
They're actually two parts of the same puzzle.
Two pieces of the same puzzle.
We'll talk about that more later.
But here, what I want to do is, whenever somebody clicks
the Click Me button, we want to change the value
inside of the Result Label.
So let's set the ResultTextBlock.Text
equals "Hello World".
All right.
And now what I want to do is actually
see our application running, so I'm going to go up
to our Toolbar
and, there's a little green arrow
that indicates that we can run the application
in debug mode.
Notice that I'm going to be running it on my local machine,
but if I use this little drop-down arrow,
you can see that there are some other options as well,
including a Simulator, and an Emulator,
as well as an actual physical device.
So the first time that we run this,
I'm going to actually just run it on the local machine.
And it opens up our application, and it's actually
quite large, but I'm going to resize this down.
All right.
And if we click the Click This button you can see the text
"Hello World" appears, as we would expect.
And so, working in debug mode is great because we're able
to set break points like we learned about
in the C# Fundamentals for Absolute Beginners series,
and inspect values as the application is currently running.
We're able to also see our app,
our Universal Windows Platform app running
without having to deploy our app
to an actual, physical Windows device.
It's just running on our desktop.
Now for most of this course, I'm going to be running the app
on my local machine, like we've done here.
Because really it's the fastest way to test what we've done.
However, at times I'm going to want to test on emulators.
And so, an emulator is a virtual machine that emulates,
or mimics, a physical device.
And that physical device could be a phone or a tablet,
or even an XBox, although we don't have that emulator
just yet to work with.
Now, at this time, since I'm using the beta,
I can only access, actually, the phone emulators,
and then the simulator that is like the Microsoft Surface.
So, what I want to do is run our application again,
but this time I'm going to choose
this Emulator 10.0.1.0 WVGA
4 inch 512 megabyte.
That specification that I chose,
Emulator 10.0.1.0 WVGA 4 inch 512 megabyte,
it specifies which physical phone
that we're going to be emulating.
So, if we take a look, we can see that our application
has been loaded up in this emulator
that looks just like a phone.
And if I click the Click This button, you can see
that it actually then displays in the main area.
I can also hit the Windows button to go back
and just like a Windows phone, I can view all apps
and even see some of the built in apps
in the phone.
Now, in order to stop debugging using the emulator,
I can do one of two things.
I can click this little close button
in the upper right-hand corner of the emulator.
However, you should get in the habit of just leaving
the emulator up and running, even when you're not debugging.
And there's a couple of reasons for this.
First of all, the emulator is running as a virtual machine
and it takes time to essentially reboot.
To shut it down and then to turn it back on.
And then, secondly, any app data that you save
to the phone between debugging sessions
will be lost whenever you shut down the simulator.
So if you have data that you want to keep around
between debugging sessions, do not close down the emulator.
The other option you have is to actually click
the Stop Debugging button in the Toolbar up here,
and I'll actually click that.
But as you'll see, the emulator is still running.
We just go out to the main Windows screen.
And I know that there's a little bit
of emulator weirdness here.
Eventually these physical buttons on the phone will work
instead of these little software buttons here
that they have represented.
All right.
Actually, I'm going to close this anyway.
Now, hopefully you're able to see the relationship
between the work that we did in the XAML editor
and in the design view and the Properties window
with the work that we did in this code behind file,
this MainPage.xaml.cs file.
And you're then actually able to see the result
of the work that we did when we ran the application,
whether it be in our, on our local machine
or in one of the phone emulators, okay?
And so, what we'll do is we'll come back
in the next lesson, and we're going to investigate further
what we did, why we did it,
and then kind of use this, again, as a jumping off point
for learning more about the Universal Windows Platform API.
Okay.
So we'll see you in the next lesson.
Thank you.