Alright, so this is the last step.
I'm going to submit my app to the Store.
Let's go ahead and get started here.
I'm going to begin by navigating to dev.windows.com.
As you can see, I'm at the en-us, which means
I'm in the English, United States version.
If you're watching this from a different country,
you may see a slightly different URL.
Just navigate to dev.windows.com and it will
direct you to the right spot.
Okay, so what I want to do is click on this link
that says "Submit your app".
Now, these sorts of things are likely to change frequently,
so just look for a link on this page to submit your app.
It may not be right here where I'm pointing right now,
but just look on the page if it doesn't stand out readily,
because again, they change the layout
and the wording on this page frequently.
So, let's go ahead and click "Submit your app".
In this case, I have an old account,
so I have to accept the new license agreement
to use the new dashboard.
Alright, now I have already registered
my company to submit apps.
You may have to go through additional
steps to actually do that.
You can see that here's a previous version
of the SoundBoard that I created several years ago.
Now, let's go ahead and create a new app.
It wants me to login with my Microsoft account.
I'm going to call this "UWP SoundBoard"
and hope that nobody's already picked it.
Okay, so looks like we're good to go there.
I'm going to start my submission process.
Alright, so let's take a look here.
Now I have my visibility turned up,
so it was a little bit larger than the recording area,
hopefully you can still read the text here.
So the first thing, it's going to walk you
through a series of steps, and it'll show you
your progress through those steps.
Let's go ahead and begin with pricing and availability.
Alright, so I'm going to pick a free price, base price,
and no free trial, it's not really necessary.
You could choose a different price,
and then also choose a free trial.
Never expires up to 30 days trial.
I'm not going to add a custom price for a given market.
It'll be free to everybody, no matter
which market you live in throughout the entire world.
There's also no need for sale pricing in my case.
However, we could set a limited time sale price for our app.
We could change the visibility for the
distribution of our app.
This might be useful if we're only distributing it
to a small clientele that we want to
be able to access the app from the Store,
but not just anybody, only our customers
or people that we already know.
We could also change, and let me show those options,
change the device families on which our app can run.
Currently, we're going to go ahead and let it run
on desktop and mobile.
I'm also going to let Microsoft decide whether to
make it available for future device families,
rather than requiring permission.
Not going to create organizational licensing,
so we're not going to sell to large corporations
and then allow them to distribute to their users.
And I'm going to allow
the publish date to be as soon as it passes certification.
Let's go ahead and save.
Alright, great. So, you can see that price
and availability has been completed.
Let's go ahead and move on to the app properties.
I'm going to choose entertainment.
I'm also going to say this store age is 3+.
Now, there are these other age ratings
that we can supply as well, the problem is,
whenever you select it, it requires
some sort of certificate.
Honestly, this is something I know nothing about.
So, I'm just going to leave all of these
to their default setting, and if we can't publish
to those markets, that's just fine with me.
We get to choose the hardware preferences.
We don't really have any hardware preferences for this app,
and we have to choose some app declarations
that apply to us.
So, this app allows users to make purchases,
but does not use the Windows Store commerce system.
Nope, that's not true.
This app has been tested to meet accessibility guidelines.
Let's go ahead and just say it has.
(laughs)
I have not, and we can probably, let's see
if we can learn more about that.
I imagine this is for users with visibility issues,
and we've not tested it, but I'm
going to go ahead and say, assume that we have.
Customers can install this app to
removable media, such as SD cards.
Now, if you're really concerned about your app being
installed to an SD card and then put onto additional
devices, you might want to de-select that.
I really don't care.
And Windows can include this app's data
in automatic backups to OneDrive, sure.
We don't really need that feature, but okay.
Moving on to packages.
Alright, it says, if you're using Visual Studio, be sure
you're signed in with the same Microsoft account associated
with your developer account as some parts of the package
are specific to this account.
Drag your packages here: the .xap, the .appx, the .appxbundle,
.appxupload, or browse your files.
So, let's do this.
Let me just go ahead and I'm going to
choose a different configuration, the release configuration,
and I choose to build a solution,
and next, with my project selected in the Solution Explorer,
I'm going to go to the Project menu and select
'Store', 'Create App Packages', and this opens up
the 'Create App Packages' dialogue,
and says, "Do you want to build the package to upload
to the Windows Store?" Yes.
Here, it wants me to sign in.
It wants me to use an authenticator app.
I don't have an authenticator app at the moment.
So, let's just send me a text message.
And I'm going to block this out, so you can't see it.
And I get to select an existing App Name.
I'm going to leave all the current selections alone,
just the way they are, and then I'll hit create.
Alright, after a few moments,
I got the package creation completed.
Alright, so now I'm going to switch
back to Internet Explorer.
I'm going to go back to the submission process,
click on packages, and now I'm going to go and browse files.
There will be two versions of this that
I'm going to submit, the first one will be for the
x64 Architecture, and then the
other will be for the ARM Architecture.
So, I'm just navigating through,
looking in the app packages, and you can see
that there are two files that I can select.
So, here's the one for the 64-bit Architecture, and I'm
going to add the one for the ARM Architecture as well.
Alright, looks like they are uploaded.
Alright, so after a moment, we got the Intel Architecture
and the ARM Architecture versions of
the application uploaded.
Now we need to add some descriptions.
Here we go.
"A fun sound board application to play noises for friends."
No release notes, I can add desktop screenshots and
some of these, okay for example,
this app tile icon is only used for
Windows Phone 8.1 and earlier.
I don't need that.
I should add some promotional artwork,
and then a lot of these things, I think, will be
added for me automatically, these images.
So I'm going to work my way through this list
of items and just start adding them here.
So, a lot of this is self-explanatory.
I'm not going to fill in most of it here.
I am going to continue on, then, to notes for certification.
I just want to let them know that they can drag and drop.
That might not be very, an obvious feature,
so I'm going to go ahead and add that.
Okay, I think that's pretty much it.
We'll go ahead and submit it.
And there we go.
Okay, so that's how you submit your app to the Store,
the process that you go through.
Obviously I won't know for a couple of hours
whether it passed or not, but maybe
I'll address that in the first video
in this little section here, to
show you whether it passed or not
and what the issues were if it didn't pass.
So, that's all you have to do.
See how easy it is to build an app
and submit it to the Store?
It's relatively friction-free, there wasn't a lot to it.
We could add a lot more complexity to it
with our pricing, with the markets,
with making sure that it is compliant with laws
and different marketing, text and images,
and things of that nature.
But it's just more of the same
of what we've already done, right?
Okay, so this is great.
Let's move on and build another app together
and we'll start that process in the next video.
Thanks.