Hi. I'm Bob Tabor with www.LearnVisualStudio.NET
and I'm here with the third challenge,
the "Laborious Layout Challenge".
This one's a little trickier
because you're going to use both multiple Grids
and multiple StackPanels
and there's probably
a number of different ways to solve this,
not just one way.
But let's take a look at the challenge itself.
You can see that we've got three sections.
Each section starts with a title.
The title is offset vertically from the text
that it's associated with.
Below each section of text,
there's a little flag-like area
with three rectangles of different colors.
I guess the last thing I want to point out
is that there are some margin space here on the left
and here between each of the titled areas.
All right, so let's take a look
at the rules for this challenge.
First of all, you have to use both Grids and StackPanels.
Even if you think you can just use StackPanels or Grids, no.
I'm forcing you to use both together
just to prove that point that you can use both together.
Secondly, here again I've set the designer
at the Desktop, not the phone size,
just so I get more horizontal space.
The next requirement is that the width
of the entire layout should be 500 pixels.
So from this side over here on the left
to this here on the right,
you'll notice that that gives us a lot of extra space
over in the right, that's okay.
Again, this is just a challenge.
This is not real life.
Number four, the text comes from the LoremIpsum file.
I think all you need is that very first line of Lorem Ipsum.
There's like five lines, or paragraphs rather.
You just need the first paragraph.
Most of the margins are either 10 or 20 pixels again.
The Title TextBlocks have a font size of 24 points,
so here, 24-point.
The Rectangles should be 100 wide
by 30 tall.
The color of the rectangles should be,
as you can see, Green, Black, Red,
Red, Black, Blue,
Blue, and off to the bottom of the screen,
you can barely see it, but Blue, Black, Yellow, okay?
It should be easy enough for that.
Also, use this image,
the UWP-015-Screenshot as your guide
as you're working on this.
And let me see what else I can tell you.
Oh yeah, just, as usual,
just try to do this without my help.
If you need some help, that's great.
But I want you to struggle a little bit
before you sneak peek at the solution.
After you've finished it,
you might want to compare what you did
versus what I did
because there are so many different ways to solve this one.
Hopefully you'll at least be open to another technique
for solving this challenge, okay?
So, good luck.
Again, this is...
Now this one's going to be rougher
but I know you can do it.
If you solved the previous two,
this one, maybe not a breeze,
but you should be able to do it.
So let's see what you come up with in the solution video.
See you there.