All right so I think we'repretty much done here except for
one little piece offunctionality that I wanted
to implement andthat was the auto complete box.
Where are you?
AutoSuggestBox, okay.
And I wanted to beable to do searches and
then also, when somebody submitsthe actual search it would
perform the query andrefine down the items
in the results to just thosethat match the other criteria.
So really just the name.
All right so to implementthis we have two methods, or
two events, to handle the textchange and the query submitted.
So let's go ahead andget started in there.
And what we're gonnaneed is another,
let's stick a nullhere between these two.
Another, I think this time it'sgonna be a list of string called
suggestions And
I'll populate the suggestions
with whatever we get back from,so let's see.
So what we're gonna dohere is actually just set
suggestions =SoundManager.GetAllSounds.
I see that it's not reallyimplemented quite that way.
So what I'll need to do here
is actually change up how Iwas thinking about doing this.
Let's GetAllSounds and
let's pass in justSounds like that, right.
And then we'll go Suggestions =
Sounds.Where(p =>
p.Name.StartsWith) and
then whatever theyhave passed in.
So I think at thispoint we can get
text that has been typedin from sender.Text.
All right, so once we have this,all we really want is
just the name itself,not the entire sound object.
So I'm just gonna projectout just the name
property like that.
And it doesn't like somethingthat I've done here.
And I think I know why.
So let me change this,I can do this one of two ways.
I can keep list and just go,I think to list here.
Yeah, to list, or I could justchange this to I numerable
instead of list, right.
But we'll just do it this way.
So now that I have suggestions,I'm gonna set the. The
SearchAutoSuggestBox.ItemSource
= Suggestions.
All right, yeah, this will work.
All right, so now that we'vetyped in the word and I've hit
entered on my keyboard, I needto handle the query submitted.
So this will allow us
to actually filter the itemsthat we're binding to.
So that list of suggestionsshould be filtered all the way
down, so.
And so,what I think I wanna do here
is make another method on sound
manager to do some public static
void getsoundsByName maybe.
And then just type in a stringname, something like that.
We can do almost everythingthat we've done before.
And then we'll gear upa filtered set of sounds.
Where(p => p.Name
== name).ToList().
And then, I guess whatI probably should do
is Do an observable collection.
So, ObservableCollectionSound,sounds.
I know this isn't pretty,but sometimes when you're in
development you have to thinkthrough things on the fly here.
So, I guess the last stepwould be then to go filter
sounds.do that whole foreach thing, right.
PP null sounds.add p, right.
See if that works.
So then,back here in MainPage.xaml.cs.
I'm gonna callSoundManager.GetSoundsByName and
I'm gonna pass in Sounds, and
then the sender.Text should
give me what was typed intothat auto suggest box.
And I think that'sall I need to do.
Yeah, I might do some ofthis stuff though here.
So I'm gonna set all soundsto whatever sender.Text is.
MenuItemsListView.SelectedItem =null, that's correct.
BackButton.Visibility shouldbe visible, like that.
Okay, so let's see if this worksthe way that I had in mind.
All right, so cat.
It didn't filter the list.
That's unfortunate.
I'm gonna set a breakpoint there and
figure out what I did wrong.
Let's go, Cow.
All right, so let's step in.
You know what I forgot to do?
I forgot to take thatstep right there.
I'll bet you,that's the problem.
So let's add that like there,
and then let's try this again.
All right Cow, and I'm justgonna blow through it and
see if it works.
It does.
[SOUND]I'm gonna hit back,
I got all sounds.
Let's go Gun.
You know, the one thing Iwould like to do is clear
out the box afterI'm done with it.
Let me do that one thing.
It's the query submitted.
All right, sothen I should be able
to go SearchAutoSuggestBox.Text= nothing.
See if that works.
I'm wanna get ridof the break point.
Now ideally, before we move intothe next part of getting ready
to submit,I would do a lot of testing.
Test on physical devices,test on different desktops,
just whoever I could get,to help me out here.
Let's go Ship, Enter.
See the problem here isthat the order of events,
right, it will,by making that change,
it will actually,
it will rerun the querysubmitted a second time.
So I can't put that in this lineof code, I can't put it there.
What I can do however is maybeput it there when we hit
the Back button or
whenever we make a differentselection on the menu list.
[SOUND] Let me putthat there as well.
So those two spots,this is what happens.
State management'susually tricky,
you gotta think okay,what needs to be where and when.
Also it looks like Ineed a little paddling
on the right there ormargin on the right.
Okay.
Here we go.Cow.
Got it.
I use Back button.
See I can see it flicker whichtells me that it's running it
twice.
I'm not sure with the rightanswer to this is.
So watch the issue here.
Okay, cat, good.
Now when I click something else,
you'll notice thatthere is a brief,
it will display everythingthen there's a flicker, and
then it will display everything.
It goes [SOUND] beforeit hit taunts and
it does even all taunts because,again, we've by setting the text
like that we're actuallychanging the logic of the code.
So I might just need to do this,like that and just forget it.
There probably is a wayto suppress that event.
And I tell you what, off cameraI'll try to figure out if I can
figure out a way to fix that.
So, if I were to hit x there,everything, but
it doesn't change that either.
So there's a couplea little issues surrounding
this that I need to figure out.
So I'm gonna stop right here,and
I'm actually going to playaround with this a little
bit more before we goto the next video and
maybe fix some things about it,but overall it kind of works.
Okay.
All right, we'll pick it up inthe next video and we'll start
working with assets and talkabout the package apex manifest.
All right, so thank you.