Okay, so next up in the
Stupendous Styles Challenge solution we're going to
tackle navigation.
And then work on the Donut Page.
So the first thing I'm going to do is
go down to the Button section,
add Click Events for each of the Buttons.
I want to give each Button a name
so I'll set the Name of this one to "DonutButton"
and then we'll go on the Click Events
we'll just create a new EventHandler
and that'll be named appropriately.
So I'm going to put these on different lines.
And I like putting things on different lines like this
it makes things more readable for me.
If you don't then let it go off
to the end of the screen if you like.
Alright so I'm just going to repeat this process.
I'm setting the Name,
so "CoffeeButton",
and then Click equals new EventHandler.
(clicking noises)
Button Name="ScheduleButton"
Button Name="ScheduleButton", and Click equals...
Okay and then,
(clicking noises)
Okay so we should be good to go there.
I wanna make sure that I gave the Frame a Name.
I did. Good.
Alright next up, let me go here
to the DonutButton.
And whenever somebody clicks it,
we'll go MyFrame.Navigate(typeof(DonutPage));
MyFrame.Navigate(typeof(DonutPage));
Great.
Now I'll just copy that four times
and we'll change out the Page.
And I guess I'll put it here too
in the constructor for the Page itself
so it automatically navigates to the DonutPage.
But here in the CoffeeButton
we'll want to put it to the CoffeePage,
schedule to the SchedulePage,
CompleteButton to the CompletePage.
And now let's test this.
Well, it's going to be hard to know
because we don't have anything on those pages,
but let's go ahead and assume for the moment
that it actually works.
And move on to the DonutPage.
So if you take a look at the comp for this.
Here we go, let's open this up.
And then take a look at this.
You're going to notice that we have the logo,
two TextBlocks, and next to the TextBlocks
we're going to have two Slider Controls.
So this looks to me like a two by two Grid,
maybe a two by,
well actually two by three or four Grid.
We'll wanna put a fourth row just to take up
all this extra space and force everything
and push it up to the top.
Alright so to do this,
let us go back here to Visual Studio
and get this back to the recording area.
Okay so let's do this
Grid dot... I know what I want,
one, two, three, four Rows
so let's go RowDefinition Height="Auto"
for all of them except the last one.
So I'll just copy and paste that a couple times.
And then in the last one I'll change that to "*" sizing
and that should push everything up.
And then we'll go Grid.ColumnDefinitions,
and I'm going to create two Columns.
So Grid dot, actually ColumnDefinition Width="Auto"
ColumnDefinition Width="Auto",
so that'll be for the width of the
the labels and then we actually need to do a "*"
we actually need to do a "*" width
on that second Column.
Otherwise, our Slider Controls aren't going to look right.
So let's start with the Image for the logo.
So, Assets,
whoops,
so let's start with the
the logo, so "Assets/white-logo.png".
And then we're going to go with two TextBlocks
for the labels.
Well actually let me go ahead and
set to Grid.Row="1".
I know that the FontSize is going to be 18.
We're going to go with the Text on this one
is "Original Glazed Count:" I believe.
I know the color,
so the Foreground is going to be "White".
And I know there's going to be some padding,
and I'm just going to guess from what I saw earlier
that I originally did something like "20, 20, 20, 0".
Let's see what that looks like
then we'll move on from there.
Alright so the second of these is going to be
"Speedway Special Count:".
Kind of going with branding that
driving or racing theme.
Since after all they are "Gonuts".
Alright good.
Now I need Sliders.
Grid.Row="1"
Grid.Column="1"
I know that the Maximum
is going to be 24,
remember that was one of the requirements.
And let's look at the Margin,
let's go with the same thing as we did with the other one.
I think we need it to go there.
Actually this should be Row 2 here on that TextBlock.
Alright let's see what we have so far.
I know this Image is going to be way too large.
And it's going to be a problem.
So let's set the Width="150"
I think is going to be the right Width.
And I know we need some margin here as well.
So let's do 20 left, 20, and then 0, 0.
Whoa, okay.
This is not bad.
The only thing is I forgot
to set the Background of the Grid.
So let's change it to "Red".
And then rerun.
Okay.
That's pretty much what I had in mind.
Alright so I think that part's complete.
Let's go ahead, stop now,
and we'll pick it back up in the next one
which should be the CoffeePage.
It's going to be a little more involved.