Hi I'm Bob Taper withwww.learnvisualstudio.net.
So up to this point you'vebeen sitting back and
watching me do allthe heavy lifting here.
You're all cozy and relaxed and
might even have your feetkicked up on your desk.
Well, now it's yourtime to struggle and
struggle is goodit's how you learn.
No struggle, and no learning.
So if you're already familiarwith SAMIL this might go
smoothly.
If you're not then this mightbe a little bit more challenging
for you, but challenge is good.
It might take you 30 minutes,an hour.
You might have to go back and
re-watch some videos orreference MSDN for some help.
But I think you can do thisbased on what we've already
learned so far.
There's actually threechallenges in a row and
they're all related to layout,what we've already learned.
And so this first challenge I'mcalling the laudable layout
challenge and you can see thatwe're building a simple app.
Only the user interface,
we don't have any functionalityin this app whatsoever.
It just has, first of allone grid and a grid only,
that's part of the requirements.
We'll talk about them ina moment and you can see that
we're just capturing,in text boxes, the first name,
last name, and the emailaddress for a sales prospect.
And then we have a save button,and
again it doesn't doanything at all, but
you can kind of get an ideaof the layout here.
As I kinda move this around, youcan see that there's one column
here, there's a second columnthat holds the text boxes, and
then a third column herethat just has some padding.
You can also see there'sa number of rows,
so I'm gonna let youfigure that out.
Let's talk about eachof the requirements.
First of all,you can only use a Grid control.
Secondly, this is more of a tip,whenever I was designing
the application, I usedthe designer of five inch phone,
1920x1080 300% scale.
The large text blockhere at the top,
is 48 points, somake sure you use that.
Most of the margins that yousee here on the left and here
between this top text block andall the rest of the text boxes.
They're either 10 pixels or
20 pixels,I'll let you figure that out.
And then the text blocks forthe first name, last name and
email address should be centeredvertically in the row and
I'll show you whatI mean by that.
Presumably, this is a rowhere at the very top and
you can see that the text box isbutted up at what appears to be
the top of the row and thenthere's some spacing below it.
And if you were to kind ofuse your mouse cursor and
trace along you can see thatthe text block in the left most
column is centered betweenthe top line of the text
box and the start of the nexttext box in the next row.
Okay, sofigure out how to do that.
Now, this isthe tricky part here.
Number six, you're gonna needto figure out how to allow your
text block to spanmultiple columns.
So when you have a need to
tell the grid how to dosomething, what do you use?
Use an attach property, so
you should use Intellisense tofigure out the correct attach
property to make your textblock span multiple columns.
All right, if you ever get stuckyou can take a look at this
extra little screen shot thatI've provide as a guidance.
All right, and that's in a filenamed UWP-011-Screenshot.png and
here's the partthat's important.
First of all, you should attemptto solve this without my
help whatsoever.
Now if you get stuck,
I don't want you to struggletoo much and get frustrated.
Watch enough of the solutionvideo, the very next video,
to get unstuck, and thencontinue to move forward on your
own to the extentthat it's possible.
And then, after you finish,and successfully complete
the challenge, you willnot only feel victory, but
you will also then want to watchthe solution video in total, so
that you can compare the waythat you approached this
challenge versus the waythat I approached it.
Maybe you have a more
elegant way of approachingsomething than I did.
Maybe I used a differenttechnique than you did.
So you can compare andcontrast and
hopefully by doing that,learn a little bit more.
And so that's pretty muchall I have to say here.
Don't cheat, don't go on to thenext video and watch it first.
Make sure you struggle.
Half hour, an hour maybe,if it takes that.
Rewatch videos if you have to,okay?
So, we'll see what you comeup with in the next video,
in the solution.
See you there.