Okay, so here we are in
the final of the Solution Videos
for the Adeptly Adaptive Challenge,
and there are two things we need to accomplish here.
Each news item should be 200 X 275 in narrow state,
and 400 X 400 tall when in a wide state.
And here we're defining the wide state
as 900 min window width.
In the narrow state, the Headline should be 18 point,
and 26 point in the wide state.
And then also we're going to hide the AutoSuggestBox
when in a narrow state of 400 or less.
Okay, so this will apply really
only to the MainPage.xaml.
This will only apply to our User Control that we created.
The NewsItemControl.
So let's go ahead and get started here,
and let's open up the NewsItemControl.
And inside of our Grid,
right after the GridRowDefinitions, we're going to
start adding a VisualStateManager,
creating the VisualState groups,
and we'll create one VisualState group.
And inside that we'll create two VisualStates.
The first one I'm going to call the NarrowLayout,
(typing on keyboard)
and then the second one
I'll call WideLayout.
Not that it really matters,
because we're not referencing it by name.
But any rate, okay,
and then, here we go, VisualState.StateTriggers,
and then VisualState.Setters.
and I'll just copy and paste that here as well.
All right, so in the Triggers, I'm going to
create an AdaptiveTrigger where
the MinWindowWidth
will be "0" for the NarrowLayout.
(typing)
And then we'll make this MinwindowWidth
"900" in the WideLayout.
And remember this is really on a per app basis.
Whatever makes sense for your application,
where the logical breaks are.
So there's no like as I've said many times already,
there's no standard way to do this that I'm aware of.
I might be corrected as some point here, but...
(typing)
So we're going to set that
MainPanel.Width,
and let's make sure that we have
that's called MainPanel here.
Here I want to call this...
Give this Name...
MainPanel.
Okay? So we're going to set...
(typing on keyboard)
(typing)
the MainPanel's Width to a value of 200.
And the MainPanel.Height
(typing)
equal to 275.
Now keep in mind, this is just for (mumbles)
the individual newsItems inside of our GridView.
(takes a deep breath)
And then the other requirement was
to...
(typing)
set the...
HeadlineTextBlock
HeadlineTextBlock...
Right?
(typing)
.FontSize,
so the value equal to 18 there.
Let me make sure I have that name set.
Yeah, I do. HeadlineTextBlock. Great. Okay.
HeadlineText, did I say box? That should be Block.
There we go.
Boy, it did not like that.
Oh.
(typing)
That (mumbles), yeah. It just didn't like that.
Okay, good alright, so then we'll change
each of these Setters up
when we go to the wide size.
And so in this case we want 400 X 400,
and...
we'll set this Font at 26.
(typing)
Great.
So that should complete the first of the two...
items.
Now let's go over to the MainPage.xaml,
and we're going to need to add
a VisualStateManager.
In fact, let me just do this.
Because I hate typing all this stuff out.
Just grab all this, we'll strip out the stuff we don't need.
(typing)
Alright, so we'll just get rid of these Setters,
and I think the MinWindowWidth is going to be 400, any rate.
(sighing)
And so in this case what we're going to do
is set the MyAutoSuggestBox.Visibility
MyAutoSuggestBox.Visibility
and we'll set that equal to Collapsed.
(typing)
And then we'll do the same here,
and it should be set to Visible,
I believe is the property there.
Alright. Let's save it, and let's see what we got.
Alright, here goes nothing. Oh yeah, look at that.
Font got bigger. The entire size of the item got larger.
All right, now unfortunately
we can't really go smaller than 400.
At least I can't, so to test this,
what we're going to do...
is change to the Mobile Emulator.
And test it there.
And ideally that SuggestBox will not be visible.
And you can see it is not visible.
I do have a little bit of... a little something
I want to do up there with that TextBlock, up on top.
Let me play around with that real quick,
but other than that, I think we're pretty much done.
Yeah, I think it was too close to the top,
so all I wanna do
is change the Margin a little bit.
Push it down there and then
let's see what the text...
That AutoSuggestBox, I'm going to have a closer eye
at that too, cause I didn't pay attention to that.
Alright, it does sit up a little high.
I might push that down 5px.
So, push it down 5px.
Yeah, I like that better.
Okay, looks good.
Let me just make sure that there wasn't some other item.
Got that. Got that.
Got that. Did all that.
Screenshots, got it, (mumbles) okay, NewsItem, got it.
And I think we did all of that.
For the most part, I think we're in good shape.
Okay, great, that's all there was to it.
Hope you got it, or at least if you didn't get
it fist time around, that this helped you get unstuck.
Alright, let's move on see you in the next video, thanks.