Hi, I'm Bob Tabor with www.LearnVisualStudio.net
and this is the first of several solution videos for
the challenge I call the Adeptly Adaptive Challenge, whew.
Alright, so let's go ahead and get started by creating
a New Project.
I'm also going to turn off the webcam here so
we can focus on just the screen.
And I'm going to call this FakeNews.
You can call it whatever you'd like to.
And so in this first video all we're going to do
is setup the Project and get the MainPage.xaml laid out.
And the first thing I want to do is open up the Assets
from the previous lesson.
I'm going to copy the Food and Financial PNGs
into the Assets folder.
So I'm just going to drag and drop them into Assets, great.
And while I'm here in the Solution Explorer,
I'm actually going to open up the Instructions.txt
and I will keep those around and available.
And let me pull this back out here.
Also, since we're opened up in the App.xaml.cs
I'm going to remove the frame counter.
And then we'll open up the
MainPage.xaml.
And I know that I'm going to create two areas,
a top area that will contain
the SearchBox
and the Title of the current Page that we're on
and then in the second Row of the Grid
we're going to add a SplitView with a pane
and a content area.
The content area will then contain a GridView
ultimately with all of our news items.
Okay, so let's go
Grid.RowDefinitions.
And we'll set this one Auto.
And the second one will be just "*" sizing.
So in the top Row, what we'll do is just add
actually a RelativePanel.
And I'm going to create first of all a Button
that will be used for
our HamburgerButton,
the TextBlock which will be used for the
title, that bold title,
and then I'm going to use an AutoSuggestBox
for the search.
Now we're not going to implement search
but I'm just going to use that and set it up here.
So the Button, we're going to set that to the
RelativePanel.RightOf
RelativePanel.AlignLeftWithPanel,
True.
And while I'm here I should probably go ahead
and just flush everything out here.
This is going to be HamburgerButton.
And let's go ahead and we know that we're
going to use the FontFamily of
Segoe MDL2 Assets
Segoe MDL2 Assets.
And if we take a look
in our little help file here,
I know that we're going to use
that character.
And let's set the FontSize="20".
And I think we'll just go ahead and set
the Width and the Height="45".
That should be sufficiently large.
And I'm going to set the alignment of this item
to the Center,
and I'm also going to go ahead and create a
Click event for this guy.
We'll come back to that, great.
All right, so now the TextBlock will be
RelativePanel.RightOf="HamburgerButton", great.
And I'm going to set the FontSize="18".
The FontWeight will be Bold.
I'm going to go ahead and give it a name as well
because we're going to need that.
So TitleTextBlock.
We're going to set it programmatically, right?
I think the only thing we'll need to do is probably give it
some Margin so I want it like 20 pixels from the left,
and I know I'm going to probably want to set
some of it on the right as well,
or at least on the top.
Alright, the next stop, let's go to the AutoSuggestBox
and give this just the Name
"MyAutoSuggestBox".
I probably should give it a different name than that
but I'm lazy right now.
And we're going to set the QueryIcon="Find",
give us a little magnifying glass.
And then the PlaceholderText, we'll type in Search.
Now if you'd like to do this, I would recommend that you
go off and you build this functionality.
You should have the tools already to do that sort of thing.
So I want this aligned on the right-hand side
and I'll set the Width="200"
and I know we're going to need some Margin as well
so I'll just go ahead and take a stab at it.
A "0" on the left.
I know I'm going to need some on the top.
I'll come back to that one.
Let's just say "10" from the right, and "0".
That should do it.
Okay, so that's in the top row.
The next Row, that's SplitView,
and we'll set the Grid.Row="1".
And I'm going to go ahead and give it a name as well
because I know we're going to want to
control it programmatically from the
HamburgerButton, right.
So MySplitView.
And I'm going to set the
DisplayMode="CompactOverlay".
Whoops.
Go ahead and do that.
And I'm going to go ahead and do this
while I'm thinking about it.
SplitView.Content, great.
I'll come back here and finish this idea up.
I know I'm going to need the OpenPaneLength.
I'm going to set it to like 150 to start
and see if that works well.
And then I'm going to set the
CompactPaneLength="45".
I'm setting it to the same Width as my
HamburgerButton.
Okay, now we have a SplitView
and inside that we're going to add the ListBox
like I've been working with here.
And I'm going set the
SelectionMode="Single"
and I'm going to set the
SelectionChanged equal to a NewEventHandler.
That should be good.
Okay, good.
Inside of here, I'm going to need a few ListBox
or at least two ListBoxItems.
So the first one, I'm going to create a StackPanel.
And we've done this so many times already,
hopefully this isn't foreign to you.
So the Orientation="Horizontal"
and we'll use two TextBlocks, right.
The first one will be that Segoe MDL2 Assets
so FontFamily.
And I think I'm using FontSize="20" for those assets.
And I think, if memory serves me correctly,
I put that in here as well,
and yeah, we'll use that as the Home.
So we'll set the Text.
Go with that.
And the second one, TextBlock, will just have the Text.
Financial.
This is the Font, actually
FontSize="18".
And I know that needs some Margin on the left,
so I'll go ahead and just use 20 there.
I'm also going to name this, the first item,
Financial.
And so that should pretty much wrap up
that first ListBoxItem.
Tell you what I'm going to do.
I'm just going to copy the whole thing
and actually let me copy the whole thing ListBoxItem.
There we go.
And I'll replace this one.
I'm just going to replace this with Food.
And this will be Food
and then the icon should be the Star, I believe.
Great.
Alright, that should take care of that.
Now inside of the Content area,
I know I'm going to have a GridView.
Just trying to figure out what needs to happen
inside of there.
Let me just try a GridView by itself
and see where that takes us.
I may have to come back and revisit this
but we'll start here.
I'm going to give this the Name
NewsItemGrid and I'll set the
HorizontalAlignment="Stretch".
That should take up the entire Width
of the available area.
Margin, I'm going to give me a little Margin
on the left-hand side.
And I know I'm going to need
an Item.Source Property
and I'm also going to need to do things like the
GridView.ItemTemplate.
And I had to do like a DataTemplate.
We'll come back to that in an upcoming lesson.
So I'll just get kind of set up for now.
Let me see what this looks like to see if it started here.
Again, I want to emphasize that in these videos
I blow through writing this code because I've already done
it once, it's fresh in my mind, and I have some notes
as well to help.
If this were a real application development effort,
I would probably take my time.
Okay, you can't see anything because we haven't wired up
that button yet.
I'll tell you what, let me go ahead
and get that part working
So I'm going go into the code behind for the
MainPage.xaml here.
And in the HamburgerButton_Click event,
we'll go
MySplitView.IsPaneOpen != MySplitView.IsPaneOpen
Alright, let's go ahead and run it now.
Whoops. What don't you like?
Oh, sorry. (laughs)
That's what it should be.
Sorry about that.
Alright, there you go.
Alright, so we're off to a good start.
Next up, we're going to work I think
on the data, I forget.
I'll look at my notes.
But that should at least complete the first setup steps
and the general layout.
Okay, so let's pick it up in the next lesson.
Thanks.