Alright, so you know I like to
get started by tackling the most difficult part
of an application first.
And in this case there is going to be a couple
of rough spots along the way that I foresee
and so I want to start tackling those first.
I think the first thing that we're going to run into
is just we need to make sure that we know how
to make calls out to the Marvel API
and get information back.
And then, deserialize anything we get back
into instances of classes,
that we can then work with inside of our application.
So here are the general steps that you're going
to need to go through to work with the Marvel API
in your own application.
First of all you're going to need to sign up
for a developer account, and you can see that
I am already at the URL developer.marvel.com
and you'll see a link here to get started
and it will walk you through the process
of creating your own account.
Very simple, they don't ask for very much.
They just want to keep tabs on
who's using their API and why, okay?
Cause they do have some restrictions
on monetizing and I would just want
you to read that and make sure you know
what you are getting yourself into
if you ever think about utilizing the Marvel API
in an application that you intend to distribute
in the Microsoft store.
So, I'm not a lawyer, I'll leave that
between you and Marvel.
However, after you create your developer account,
the next thing that you are going to want to do,
is then kinda learn how to use it,
and fortunately the interactive documentation
is awesome.
You can take a look at the various ways
in which the API can be called, and what you can retrieve.
And so, for example, you can get a list of characters
or just get a single character,
or get all the comics for a single character,
or all the events, or series, or stories
for a single character.
You can get a list of comics.
You know, you can filter them in certain ways.
You can get a specific comic and find
all the characters in that comic,
and those who created that comic,
and the events and the stories associated with that comic.
Okay, so you get the idea.
Now, what you see here,
this high level overview of API calls,
you can click into one, and you can learn a little bit more
about what it does and what it gives you back.
In this case, these are the, I guess you could say,
this is the model.
The classes and the properties of information
that will be returned to you whenever you make a call
into this particular API, alright?
And you can even see that they have
an interactive environment were you can test out
the input of parameters.
So in this case, for example, show me all characters
that start with the letters S, P,
but only give me ten characters back, alright?
And then you can click the Try it out button,
it will show you the request URL,
so in this case it's that URL
that we saw at the very top here,
of /v1/public/characters,
you know, appended on
to their API URL
gateway.marvel.com:80/v1
and then you pass in as query string parameters
those filter key value pairs,
so namestartswith=Sp, limit=10, and then,
you also need to supply an API key
and we'll talk about that in just a moment.
And then, you get back this long passage
of JSON, and you can see there's some information here
at the very top, which is just, you know,
that we succeeded, and it gave us a success code of 200.
If it failed we 'd be able to see that there are
various reasons why it could potentially have failed.
Attribution text and HTML that has to be added
if you're using this in the context
of a web application, again, that's between you and Marvel,
you need to kind of work through that
and understand what the legalities of this are.
But then, ultimately, we get to the
actual results themselves.
In this case, we have ten characters that have
been brought back with a total of 33
that match the criteria.
So, we say just bring back the first ten
that start with the letters S, P.
And you can see here this first character
Spacker Dave and doesn't have a description,
it does have a thumbnail image.
In some of cases the characters just don't have
a lot of information.
They might be a fairly obscure character.
In other cases, there might be a lot more information
about a given character.
Let's see, here we go,
Speed is a good example.
Description: Tommy Shephard might be the son
of Scarlet Witch and The Vision. Hmm.
Alright, thumbnail; a resource URL so you can get more
information about this specific character.
Then the number of comics that
this character was in.
So we have a collection of two items,
two individual comic books
that this character was featured in,
the number of series that they were featured in,
the number of stories that they were involved in,
and so on, and then we move on,
to the next character Speed Demon and so on, okay?
So first of all,
let's talk about this API key.
When you sign up for a developer account,
you're going to be able to view
this My Developer Account link here at the top,
and you're going to be given
a public key and a private key.
And any time that you make a call to the API,
you're going to need to pass along
either just the public key,
as you saw we did a moment ago,
or, some combination of public and
private key hashed together.
We'll talk about that in just a moment.
Now if you're using this in a web application,
you need to list the URLs that you plan
on calling the API from.
In this case, developer.marvel.com is one place
we were able to use our public key
to make a call into and grab data from the Marvel API.
However, if you go to the How To section,
under Authorization,
you'll learn that this only works only
for client side applications.
If you were to create what they call
a Server-Side Application, or in our case,
like a client application, you're going to need to
supply a little bit more information to them.
In fact, what you're going to have to do,
is provide a hash.
And a hash is listed here as a MD5 digest of
the time-stamp parameter, your private key,
and your public key.
So, a hash is basically an algorithmic computation
based on a public key and a private key
that's known to only two parties.
So, basically, there are many different hash algorithms
that are available, and md5 is actually
one of the weaker algorithms,
but the stronger the algorithm, the more computational power
it requires to actually calculate the hash,
so there's a trade-off there.
But essentially what this is going to do,
is ensure that nobody has tampered with the request
from the client to the server, and
you essentially take, again, the time-stamp,
the private key, the public key.
You run this md5 algorithm
against those values,
and you'll come out with a hash
that'll be appended at the end of every call
that we're going to make into the Marvel API.
So, we just have to figure out how to do that
in C#, and fortunately,
there are classes in the Universal Windows Platform
that will help us to accomplish that.
Okay, so what we're going to do is
go back here and in the Interactive Documentation,
let's talk for a moment about what it is
that our application will accomplish.
What we're going to do is create
the hero explorer application, which will just,
show us randomly a number of
characters from the Marvel universe,
and so that we can click though and learn
a little bit more about them.
I mean, I never knew that there was a character
named, what was it, Speed a moment ago. (laughs)
That's interesting, I mean, if you're into the
folklore of Marvel and most of us geeks
have been at some point in our lives, right?
So what we want to do is just say hey,
I just want ten random characters
from the Marvel database.
And, what I'm going to do is generate an offset,
so I know that there are approximately 1500 characters
in the database.
What I'll do is just randomly get a number from one
to 1500, or 1490, and say hey, that's my offset.
So, a random number might be 520 for example,
and I'll say, beginning at number 520,
return me the next ten records
from the Marvel database.
So I typed in the limit: 10, and the offset: 520,
and let's see what we get back as the result of that.
They're in alphabetical order, whoops, okay,
sometimes this will happen where you get
a 500 response code.
That's a problem on their side,
so you can try to run it again,
or maybe change up some of the properties here.
Let's go with 350 instead and try that out.
Okay, and that seemed to work.
So, I'm not really sure what the issue was,
but you gotta just kinda work through
some of these things, right?
So in this case, we start with the letter E,
so we are looking at Earthquake, never knew that character.
Then there's the one after that.
It's Echo, alright, and then the one after that,
Eddie Brock, okay, and we could go on and on from there.
Alright, so what we want to do at this point,
now that we kinda have a game plan of
how we are going to make a call into the API,
what we need to do is
take the resulting JSON,
and convert it into C# classes
like we did for the weather app,
when we made calls in the OpenWeatherMap API.
So what I want to do is get a good representative
set of JSON that I can use
to get the JSON to C#.
If we get some results that don't
have a lot of results in them,
then we may not get the right results
when we go to JSON to C#,
and so, I guess what I'm trying to say is
what I want to do is just type in like,
Spider, whoops, Spiderman,
and say give me just two results.
Now I know that they'll have,
it'll be fully fleshed out, right?
And that will give me a good representative JSON sample,
that then hand over to JSON to C#.
Now let's get rid of the offset,
and let's go and try that out.
And, yes, see I get the name, a great description,
I get a good thumbnail.
So there are all of this information is populated,
and I feel really good about taking this snippet of code,
of all of this that's been returned.
Highlighting it all, getting it onto my clipboard
by hitting ctrl + C,
and then going to json2csharp.com and pasting in my JSON,
and then clicking Generate.
And, again I just want to emphasize the reason
why I wanted to get good representative sample
of JSON for a character that had a lot of data,
was because when json2csharp.com looks at that JSON,
it's going to parse it all out,
and figure out the classes to create.
And so if it's missing information,
then it will use something generic like object,
instead of character, you know,
it may omit certain classes where there
just wasn't data in the representative JSON
that we pasted in.
Okay, hopefully that makes sense.
So I'm going to copy all of this to my clipboard,
and then I'm going to open up Visual Studio
and actually create a new project,
called HeroExplorer.
And, one of the first things I'll do
is I'm going to add a new folder,
called Models,
and in that folder, I'm going to add new class
that I'm going to call,
well here's what I'm going to do,
let's go back here to the Marvel Developer Portal
and go to the very top,
and we can see the response classes.
At the topmost level there's something called
the CharacterDataWrapper and
CharacterDataContainer,
So the CharacterDataWrapper will contain data,
and the CharacterDataContainer will contain results
which is an array of Character class.
So let's call this CharacterDataWrapper.
Alright, and what I want to do is paste in
everything that I have on my clipboard
from json2csharp
and I'm going to look through this closely
and look for these instances where we have,
for example, something very generically named,
like "item", for example.
I see that "item" is actually a single instance
from this Comics class.
So what I might do is this instead,
I might rename this from item,
to comic, so now, the Comics class will
have a list of items called,
a list of items of type: Comic.
Same thing would be true for Series,
now unfortunately Series, the pluralization of that word
is a little tricky.
So I might say,
I might call this a SeriesList,
and then name this a Series,
and then name this
a SeriesList will have a list of Series.
Alright, same thing with Stories.
So this would become a Story class.
And we would have a list of Story called
items in our Stories class.
And then, we'll do the same thing with Events,
so we'll just name this Event,
and then we'll have a list of Events called Items.
But as we get down here to these bottom items,
what I want to do is actually reuse the names of things
that Marvel used.
So, we're going to call this top-most object
not a rootObject, but instead we are going to call it
the CharacterDataWrapper, alright?
And then we're also going to use CharacterDataContainer,
here.
And, furthermore, I can see that each
of the individual characters is of type Character,
so I'm going to change that as well.
It's not a result, it's a Character, right?
And so we should have a list of Character,
and this should give us--
change from data to CharacterDataContainer.
Now I just want to kind of look through this
and make sure everything is good,
like this shouldn't be Series anymore,
this should be SeriesList, alright?
And I'll take my time and kind of work my way through this,
and I need to be pretty careful here
because once I go to deserialize some JSON
into these classes, it needs to work.
(laughs) It will be difficult to
hunt down what's not working.
Okay, so far so good.
And, I think the next thing that we are going to do here,
is, well actually let's stop,
and what I want to do is actually create a class.
So here, let me just set this top-most level.
Add a new class and, I need a way to access
the Marvel API progammatically
and so what I am going to do is create
a MarvelFacade,
and facade is a special name
in software development that
is a design pattern for creating a layer of code
over a dependency that you don't have control over.
So we want to create a nice friendly way to
call into the Marvel API from C#,
and behind the scenes the MarvelFacade will
be delegated the responsibility of going out
retrieving results, parsing them, putting them into
our model class and then delivering them back, alright?
And so, the MarvelFacade will also
have private helper methods to create,
construct that URL that will wind up passing into
Marvel, that will include not only the API call itself
plus any filtering parameters, but then also
it'll contain the MD5 hash that we need to pass along
with the public and, private keys,
and then also the time-stamp.
Alright, so let's make this a public static--
well, there let's make it a public class,
and then we'll create a single method
called public static void for now,
GetCharacterList(), alright.
And I know i'm going to need to make a call into
HTTPClient, so I'm going
to add that to my project
by going into the Manage NuGet Packages.
And I'm going to search for--
what am I searching for here? HTTPClient.
Alright.
And we'll go ahead and install that.
Alright, we're good.
And, I think that's all that I'm going to do,
just to kind of keep these videos kind of scoped,
small, and not too long.
So, let's stop right here and in the next video,
we're going to actually make a call out to Marvel
and grab characters in JSON and then,
deserialize them into our CharacterDataWrapper model.
Alright, so we'll see you in the next video.