Okay, so next up, we want to get the data and deserialize
it into our classes in our model.
However, to do that, we're going to need to
make a call out to Marvel, and to do that,
we're going to need to figure out how to make a MD5 Hash,
and I'm not going to lie to you, I have no idea.
I wouldn't have been able to figure this out had not
somebody posted some code online.
That's the beauty of learning software
development in 2015, 16 as opposed to learning
it back when I did before the internet,
if you can even imagine such a thing.
Okay, but at any rate, I could show you where I found
the answer and if you want some more information about it,
I'd be happy to point you to there.
So let's get started by outlining what it is
that we need to do in our GetCharacterList().
We're going to need to assemble the URL that we want to call
and part of that's going to be making a call
to get the MD5 Hash
and then we're going to make a call out
to Marvel and we're going to get back a response
and we're going to need to get that response
into a string, so response to string
and that string will represent json, and then,
we want to deserialize that, right?
And if you recall the way that we deserialize data
that JSON data is to use the
DataContractJsonSerializer, right?
Alright, so that's going to be a little bit tricky
and we're just going to need to work our way through it.
So, assembling the URL will be pretty easy.
We're going to come back here to their interactive
API documentation and we're going to
re-run the sort of query that we expect
to do, like we want to limit to 10
and we'll just give a random offset of 100, right?
And we'll click try out and that should give us
the request URL format that we need to work with.
And what we want is this request URL.
I'm just going to highlight it and copy it and then go back
here and we're going to create a string URL
equals String.Format()
and then we will paste in that long URL.
Now, this is a good time for me to make some more room here.
Alright, what we're going is we're going to hardcode it to 10.
If you wanted to, you can make and replace that value
to grab 15, 20, 100, whatever you wanted.
We are going to, however, change the offset.
We're going to change the API key as well,
and then we will append on the end of this
the hash as well, when we get to that point.
Alright, so, the first thing we'll need to do
is to create an instance of Random,
and we're going to get a new offset.
Now I happen to know there are 1,500 characters.
I'm going to hardcode it now, but I probably should put
this in a constant at some point.
So let's call this var offset
equals random.Next and I want to give
the max value of 1,500.
And once I have that offset value,
if I can provide that there.
The next thing that I'm going to need to do is provide
the API key and so what I'm going to do for that
is actually create a couple of private constants.
private const string PrivateKey
equals and then private const
string PublicKey equals.
Alright. Here, I'm also just going to create one for this.
private const int MaxCharacters
equals 1,500, and we'll just do MaxCharacters.
Alright, and then we'll put the public key here.
Alright and then the next thing we're going to need to do
is actually populate that private public key.
This is where we get up close and personal with my
personal information, however I'm going to remove my
account once I finish recording this series.
So, this key will not work. Get your own.
Don't try to copy mine.
Put the public key in the public key spot
and we'll put the private key in the private key spot.
And the next thing we're going to need to do
is actually get the MD5 Hash and so here's what I do know
what I can do is, I'm going to need to
create a private static method that'll
return a string called CreateHash() and what this will do,
let's, let's
do var toBeHashed equals
we'll need a Timestamp and we're going to need a private key
and we're going to need the public key.
We're going to concatenate those three things together.
So for a Timestamp, if you take a look at the documentation
in that How To area under Authorization,
it says that for the Timestamp you can use any long string
which can change on a request by request basis.
So you don't have to get crazy with this.
I'm going to use DateTime.Now.Ticks,
which should give us a pretty unique string of characters
representing how many milliseconds
since a certain date in the past.
So we'll call var timestamp equals
DateTime.Now.Ticks.ToString()
and that should work, okay.
The next step what I need to do
is actually get the computed hash.
Now, this is where I had no idea how to do this
had it not been for somebody on the glorious internets
who already figured this out and was kind enough to
post it in response to a question on Stack Overflow.
So I give you the URL where you can see where
this was originally sourced from.
I basically spent about three days trying to learn
how to create my own hash and I learned a lot,
but ultimately, at the end, I was unsuccessful of actually
creating one that worked, so I just stole five lines of code
that this kind soul posted out on the internet.
I'm just going to make sure all the references are added
with using statements here and what I'd recommend
you do if you really want to learn how all this works,
There's probably some good content out on
MicrosoftVirtualAcademy.com about security.
Probably some good books out there.
Obviously go and look at each of these objects
and each of these methods out on MSDN to learn
a little bit more about what they do and how they work,
but at the end of the day, all I really care about is
I want to pass in a value to be computed as a MD5 Hash
and what I get back is a MD5 hash, alright, so.
var hashedMessage equals
computeMD5() and I'm going to pass in the to be
hashed and then I'm going to return
the hashed message, like so, okay?
So, here we're going to get that hash.
So, var hash equals
CreateHash
and what I want to do is
append to that existing URL so
the hashed value and the, yeah,
just the hashed value and the time stamp,
because it should have everything else it needs.
So, I'm going to go string--
I could-- guess I could
do this a number of different ways.
Let's just go ahead and do this all in one shot.
Actually, I changed my mind.
Alright, we'll do that first, and then we'll create the URL.
At the very end of this URL, I'm going to have to add in
a timestamp equals and we'll substitute that in,
and then also the hash itself equals, alright.
And so, I guess I need to pass in the
timestamp in order to get at it.
Unfortunately, so, I need to change this just a little bit.
String timestamp,
and then I'll pass that in.
But I'll have access to it here,
and then I'll be able to pass it in here.
Timestamp, great. Okay.
Alright, next up I'm going to use the
HttpClient
called http and I need add a using statement for it,
so I'm adding using System.Net.Http
equals new HttpClient,
and that'll allow us to do this,
http.GetAsync() passing in the requestURI,
so give it the URL, and what I should get back
from that and it's a waitable.
What I should get back from it is a response
and that response will be of type
HttpResponseMessage.
I notice you get the red squiggly.
That's because I have to go through this little dance here
and add the async keyword and
I think that's all I need to do right now,
go back to that in a minute.
Alright, so here we go.
We got the response and now with that response
what I need to do is read it into a string
so var jsonMessage equals
response.Content, whoops, Content
.ReadAsStringAsync(), that'll give me back
just the json message now.
I have it in hand, and since this is in async,
I'm going to have to make it awaitable.
Now I need to take that JSON and I need to
deserialize it into my classes and
to do this I'm going to use the
DataContractJsonSerializer,
right, and we should already have
that referenced in our project.
I'm just going to hit control period and add the
using System.Runtime.Serialization.Json namespace.
That should get it recognized there,
and I'm going to create a serializer
which is really just a new DataContractJsonSerializer,
and specifically the type is going to be
this character data wrapper.
CharacterDataWrapper.
Now why isn't it seeing it?
Because I haven't added the using statement for models.
So using HeroExplorer.Models should resolve that reference.
And then I need a MemoryStream, so, whoops.
ms for Memory Streams, so MemoryStream.
Let's make sure we add the using statements for that,
System.IO and the idea here is that we're going to pile
a bunch of stuff in a memory stream and the memory stream
will sit there holding onto stuff and then we'll give it
to the serializer, the serializer will suck all the stuff
out of that straw and it will deserialize it and
give it back to us as an object graph
beginning at the root with CharacterDataWrapper.
So we have to start out with
Encoding.UTF8,
which is what we would expect that JSON to be in,
and then we're going to say, "Get the bytes out and
"basically just take that string
"that we got here, that json message and then turn it
"into an array of bytes based on the UTF8 encoding
"and then put that all up in a memory stream."
And this should be new memory stream, like so.
Alrighty, and then, if we've done everything right,
which is a big if, we're going to read the object
that's sitting there in that memory stream
and we're going to read it into a
var result and what we'll do,
here is go, what should be brought back to us is
a CharacterDataWrapper object, if we did that right.
Okay, and that.
Now, we probably, in order to get this to work,
what we're going to need to do is actually return
a task of CharacterDataWrapper and so
we'll want to return the result here.
And why is everybody not happy,
oh because yeah, you're in the void, right.
Everything looks good, everybody happy? Good.
Build the solution.
Okay, great. That worked.
The next thing that we're going to need to do is now,
let's see, in our MainPage.xaml,
I'm just going to add a button and when we click it,
we'll kick off this whole process.
I just want to see if it's bringing data back.
Once we get data, and we get it deserialized,
then we can move on with the user interface,
but in the meantime, all I really want to do
is just to make sure that we can
get that far.
And so we want to make a call into the MarvelFacade. --
whoops, why don't I see...
Oh, because I wanted this to be static. Alright.
I wanted it static so I didn't have to
create an instance of MarvelFacade.
I mean, all of this is really doing is
bringing me back something it doesn't,
I don't need it to have a reference to it.
It doesn't have any state, you know.
Alright, and so that should work there.
var, let's call it "data" equals that.
That's all I really need to do.
So let me put a breakpoint at a spot where I know,
whoops, spot where I'm concerned about.
I'm pretty confident everything will work.
I'm a little concerned about this right here
and I can't explain why. (laughs)
Let's just see if this will work.
If we do hit a problem, it's probably a mismatch
between the JSON that's being returned
for the items that we want to work with.
Oh, I got a tiny button here, but this should work.
I'm mismatched between the data types and the jsons.
So I'm going to have to, you know,
put my thinking cap on and figure that part out.
We haven't hit the breakpoint just yet.
And we haven't hit an exception,
so it's really thinking about this.
Okay, so far so good. Let's take a look at that URL.
Can't see it off to the right hand side of the screen,
but it looks legit, looks legit.
Alright, so let's keep going here and see what happens.
So it made it on request, we got it back,
and now we're going to create our serializer
in our memory stream, and here's where I'm nervous.
And hey, it actually worked. Oh yeah.
Lists 10 results. Let's drill into one of these guys.
"Frankenstein's Monster".
Here, I want you to see what I'm going to do next.
I'm very happy about this. Okay.
So, great. We got data back from the Marvel API and
I'm so excited about that that it worked on the first try.
Okay, so, we're going to piggy back up here in the next lesson
and then we should be able to bind to that data and
start showing stuff on screen.
That's going to be exciting.
See you in the next lesson. Thanks.