Allright, so the next thing
that we're going to do is work on the
Data Model, and then we'll do some initial Binding,
and then re-work it a little bit in another video.
So the first thing we do is add a Model folder,
so I'm just going to select the project name,
go over to Projects and Add New Folder,
and call it Model.
And inside of there I'm going to add another Class called,
I'll call mine NewsItem.
You can call it whatever you like, but ultimately,
I'm going to be creating a new POCO
called NewsItem.
And I'll create an ID, although we won't really use that.
Create a Category,
Headline.
Also create
Subhead,
DateLine,
and the Image Path.
All right, so the next thing we're going to need to do then
is to create a,
a class I want to call the
NewsFactory, I guess.
I could call it NewsManager,
either of those I think would apply in this situation.
And that's,
and when I use the word Manager or Factory
I'm invoking patterns,
design patterns for software developers.
Factories are classes that allow you create instances
of new objects, so whenever there,
the creation of an object's complex,
you can delegate that to another class entirely.
I might call this a Manager instead, though.
Manager really denotes
the ability to interact with the POCO object
against any persistence,
and we would probably have,
if this were a real application some sort of persistence,
so I'm going to go with NewsManager instead,
now that I think about it a little bit more.
Naming things is hard.
I think I've said that before in this series.
And you want to connote the right idea
of the role that a given class or property
or variable is playing
inside of your system.
Okay, so what the plan here is that
I'm going to pass in an empty,
or even a populated ObservableCollection
of type NewsItem,
and then I'm going to use this method
to remove what's already in it,
and populate it with all the items that fit
the given category that you're passing in as well.
Alright, so let's go ahead and get ObservableCollection,
I'm going to hit Control+"." on the keyboard,
pops up IntelliSense.
I'm going to grab that Using statement there at the top.
And we should be good now.
Great.
And so, I think what I'm also going to do
is actually delegate the actual creation
of this master List of items
to another method.
So I'm going to go private static List,
,
called getNewsItems.
And this is just a helper method.
And it's going to do the hard work here.
Okay.
And ultimately we will return this items.
And I've been fightin' the telesense because I
spelled items incorrectly.
There we go.
Alright, and now if you'll excuse me,
well I'll go ahead and type in the first one.
We're going to paste in
everything that I've done here,
and I'll walk through it so you can look at it.
So I'm using an object initializer syntax
inside of the Add for the collection,
so I'll do something like add ID = 1;
Category equals,
I probably should use an enum for this,
but I'm going to be lazy
and just use a hard-putted string.
And then
for the Headline,
I'm going to set that equal to Lorem
Ipsum
Subhead, I'll set that equal to
some other fake Latin
that I have no idea what it means.
Set the DateLine equal to...
And then I'm going to set the Image equal to
Assets/Financial1.png
Assets/Financial1.png.
Alright, so you can see that I fumbled through
and typed all of that out.
Now here's what I'm going to do.
I'm going to copy and paste
all the rest of the items
from work I've done previously from my notes.
And I tell you what I'm going to do.
I'm going to give you,
I'll actually, I'll tell you what.
Before you actually take possession
of, here, actually, I'll give you this whole thing.
I'm going to put this
in our little instructions, here.
So I'm going to add this to the bottom, like so,
and you can just copy and paste it all out,
and I'll make a note right above it like right here.
So by the time that you receive this,
you'll get all of this extra stuff in there
that'll help you create all of the newsItems, okay.
So that should make it easy for both of us (laughs).
Alright, so now what I want to do
is just call into that,
call into that helper method to grab all the items
and then I'm going to get a filtered List of the Items,
so filteredNewsItems = allItems,
where and, so we'll filter by Category,
like so.
And once we have that, I'm going to
convert it to a List, like that.
And now I'm going to take the newsItems
that were passed in and call clear on them.
So empty out everything that's in there.
And then I'm going to go, a filteredNewsItems,
whoa, man, I am spelling Items wrong today.
There we go.
filteredNewsItems, and then,
I need to add each of the individual
items in the list to ObservableCollection.
There's no easy way to convert,
so let me do this.
This is a nice little trick.
This ForEach link extension method will go through
each individual item, in my newsItem,
in the filteredNewsItems,
and it will add that filteredNewsItem
to my ObservableCollection of newsItem, like so.
Whoops, there we go. (laughs)
Okay, that should work.
Okay, so just to explain that again.
Here I'm grabbing all the newsItems that we create
in our List of newsItem.
Here I'm going to filter and only grab those out
from the Category that was passed in.
I'm going to convert that to a List,
and then I'm going to clear out all the items
that are currently in the ObservableCollection
of newsItem.
Now I want to go through and do a ForEach
on every single item in the filteredNewsItems,
and for each Item in that collection,
I'm going to add it to this ObservableCollection of newsItem.
So that should work.
That should be just fine.
Now what I want to do is, in my MainPage,
I'm going to need to
go here and I want to do a private ObservableCollection,
ObservableCollection,
of NewsItem
called NewsItems.
Alright, let's make sure I spelled that right.
Now I want to add using statements to get
both my NewsItem and the ObservableCollection
into this code file,
and then in the MainPage,
in the constructor for the Page,
what I'll do it populate it.
Go NewsItems = new
ObservableCollection,
well at least I'll create a new instance of it rather,
and then
when the Page is loaded,
what we'll do is Page load,
and we'll create EventHandler for that,
and here I'm going to make sure that the
Financial tab is selected.
And then here, I'll go Financial dot,
if that's true, if Financial.IsSelected,
we'll do something else,
if Food.IsSelected we'll do something else.
Like that, okay.
Let's go ahead and get these on other lines.
Like so. Great.
So here I'm going to call
the NewsManager.GetNews,
and I'm going to say give me all the Financial Items,
and I'm going to pass in the newsItems like that.
Pull in the newsItems.
And I'm going to also set the Title Block's Text
equal to Financial, like so.
And then here we'll do the same thing,
NewsManager.GetNews,
whenever the Food Item is selected,
the ListView item called Food is selected.
So Food,
and then News Items,
and then the TitleTextBlock.Text
equals Food.
Great.
And alright, so that should set that all up,
and then the last thing I guess I need to do
is come back over to the MainPage.xaml
and temporarily add stuff for this DataTemplate, so
again, we'll be pulling this out eventually,
but for short term I can make this work.
So let me,
let me actually create a Grid,
and the Grid's going to have two Rows.
And so the top Row
will have an Image,
the Financial1.png, Food1.png,
whatever the case might be.
And then the next Row will actually have
all of the Text in there that we want to store.
Now we'll come back and we'll worry about
how to change the Widths and the Heights appropriately,
but I'm going to go ahead and hard code the Height="275"
Height="275" for now,
and we'll set the Width="200",
and we'll change that based on the Width of the window
and we'll use the VisualStateManager
to accomplish that.
I'm going to go ahead and set the Background="White" as well,
and I'll give it a Margin all around "10".
Alright.
So let's start with
the Image.
So that'll be in the top Row,
so I won't even set Grid.Row,
and I'll set Name, MyImage.
And then here we're going to set the source,
and we'll do the x:Bind statement here.
And that reminds me now,
we need to do some other things here.
Alright, so the DataTemplate. (exhales)
x:DataType equals
data:NewsItem,
of course, we have not defined that namespace called Data,
so let me do that, xmlns:data
equals FakeNews.Model, like so.
Alright, that should take care of that.
And we're going to Bind to
the Image.
Then I'm going to add a RelativePanel,
and in that RelativePanel I'm going to set that
Grid.Row="1".
And there's a bug with the RelativePanel.
I think sometimes it manifests itself,
and the bug is whenever it's used in the context
of a DataTemplate, sometime it whacks out
inside of the XAML editor, so if you get that problem
with blue squiggly lines saying that
it has to be set to Instance of UIElement.
You're not the first one to encounter that.
Maybe they'll fix that, I don't get it
every time it's,
it's an odd little bug, but,
I've seen other people online
say that they've had the same issue.
So let me actually
say that I want this to be Subhead,
and I'll worry about the formatting of this later,
make it look better.
But I think that's all I'm really going to need right now.
Now I still get this little blue squiggly line here,
I think it's because you've gotta build your project.
I had not built the project since I created the NewsItem
class. Seems to work, and the blue squiggly goes away.
Let's see what we have so far.
Huh.
That's not what I was expecting.
Not what I was hoping for.
Alright, I'm missing something obvious, I feel like.
Oh, (chuckles) of course I'm missing something obvious.
Can you see what I'm missing?
I'll give you a hint, it's right in, it's in here.
Yeah.
What I'm missing is the ItemSource Property.
Easy enough.
And I've gotta give it
that ObservableCollection of NewsItem
that I called newsItems that I created here
in the MainPage.xaml.cs.
Right there.
That's how it's going to all Bind itself together.
So now let's see if it works.
Alright, it's not pretty,
definitely have some work to do with formatting,
but I can see there's a lot of text on top of each other.
That's okay for now.
Let's see if that works, yeah,
so I'm getting, I'm filtering correctly,
that's all working nicely.
All right, and I'll worry about the formatting
of these guys later on, but for the most part,
I've done the creating of the Data Model,
and the Data Binding part of it,
and we'll continue on in the next lesson,
as we move on from there, okay.
Thank you.