Okay, so the next app that we're going to build together
is a very simple weather application.
Now I realize there are stock apps that come with
Windows 10 on the desktop and the phone,
however, this one will allow us to express
a little individuality, a little design.
Also, we'll demonstrate some pretty cool features
of both Windows 10 the platform
and then how to work with external services
to get data to update and make your apps come alive.
So I'll go ahead and run the application.
Actually let me run it just on the desktop
and just have to trust me that it works
in the mobile version as well.
And the name of the application I'm calling
UWP Weather.
It's a simple weather app.
It's just going to go out and based on my current location
here in Dallas, it's going to go out and find
the current weather, what the weather conditions are,
where I'm actually at here.
I'm in Plano, Texas and then also will display
an image, a cute weather image with a hot pink background
to convey what the current weather is where I'm at.
So in the process of building this, first of all,
this is a great start to a weather application
that you can take and extend and you're going
to learn how to do that.
You can add, you know, a two week forecast if you want
using online services that I'll point you to in this series.
But one of the main things that you'll learn
is how to use sensors on your device or in actuality
the location services for Windows 10 to determine
the geo position where the device or your computer
is currently at So that would give the latitude
and longitude that we can then take
and we can make calls out to an external web service
like the openweathermap.org,
which will allow us to give in a place,
a latitude, longitude, will give us the weather
for that location and even future forecasts
for the hours and days ahead.
So it's going to also allow us then
to learn how to retrieve data from a web service
in a typical fashion through a file format
called JSON (JavaScript Object Notation),
maybe you're already familiar with that
and deserialize that into instances of classes
that we can work with in C#.
Very crucial skill, outside of this example
and throughout the rest of your life
as a software developer.
You have to know how to serialize and desterialize data
from data formats like XML and JSON
into objects and back.
And then we're going to look at how to work with
the Phone Emulator to test our application,
not just as it's used on the mobile device itself
and the layout, things of that nature, but then also
how to change the position
and kind of tell the location services
that we're actually coming from, Seattle or Washington, DC,
or China, or whatever.
And so we'll look at a cool feature of the emulator
to do that as well for testing.
And then we're going to take a look at how to build
a live tile for our application
that we'll update periodically with the latest weather
for our geo position, our latitude and longitude.
And so that will teach us not only how to build live tiles,
but then also we'll learn how to create a web service
using ASP.NET MVC 5 and host it out as your website
so we're bring together a lot of cool technologies
to build a very interactive application.
So beginning in the next video we'll get started
with the layout and learning how to access that web service
and get back the data that we need.
We'll begin that process in the next video.
We'll see you there, thanks.