Hi, I'm Bob Tabor with www.learnvisualstudio.net
and in this lesson we're gonna talk about
the Canvas Layout Control, as well as shapes.
Now, they're not inextricably tied together,
but you'll see that they are complementary ideas.
We're dealing with absolute placement
of Controls on a design surface.
So, typically, in layout of Windows applications,
we do not want to have absolute layout
or absolute positioning because if we resize
the application we would have to either
do a lot of math to factor out where
things should be, or we really are
just limited the form factors that can consume
our application.
So, typically you wouldn't use this in
any applications that you typically would see
installed in Windows, but there are some
use cases, some scenarios where I thought
this would be helpful, so in the interest
of making sure you have a pretty broad knowledge,
maybe perhaps not all that deep,
but a broad knowledge of your options
with building applications, I wanted to cover
both the Canvas and different shapes.
So you might need to build apps that deal with
music, musical staffs, musical notation,
or perhaps applications that deal with math
and it needs symbols and you need lines
and you need some different places,
you know, math can get kind of hairy
with the formulas and where they're placed.
Analog clocks, so they can create different angles
for lines, and things of that nature,
even a diagram application, or a drawing application,
perhaps you want to create two symbols
and then draw a line between them
that has some meaning inside of
your particular industry, or even applications
that deal with bar readers, or create bars for scanners.
All of those are good scenarios for working with
both a Canvas and with shapes.
Okay, so the first thing I wanna talk about
is the Line shape.
And the Line is pretty simple.
It doesn't need to be put inside a Canvas at all,
you can put it inside of a Grid
and you can see here what we get as a result of that.
Here we're putting it inside of the default Cell,
we're just specifying the X and Y
coordinates for the beginning and the end.
So here's the beginning point.
X="10" and Y="10", so that gives it
this left-most corner here.
And then the second point would be
X="200", Y="10", so that's gonna give us
a nice vertical line because the Y's don't change,
only the X values.
That gives us that point up here on the right-hand side.
You can see that we've said the Stroke="Black"
and the StrokeThickness="5",
and then we also set the StrokeEndLineCap="Triangle"
StrokeEndLineCap="Triangle"
There's a couple different options here,
you can see that we can create a Flat, Round,
Square or Triangle, and let me scroll actually,
just go to 100 here.
You can see, by choosing Triangle we get
that little arrowhead on the end.
So like I said, we can actually,
we don't need Grids, I'm sorry a Canvas
in order to create various Line Objects
and add them to our application.
As you can see here, I created a triangle
by creating three more Lines and making sure
that they intersect at just the right spot,
making sure that their StrokeStartLineCap
is set to Round, and that the StrokeEndLineCap
is set to Round so they have a nice rounded appearance
on the corners and they come together nicely.
Now, I did want to talk about the Canvas,
because the Line, you can see that we're
doing absolute placement by choosing
an X,Y coordinate.
If we were to change this to Canvas,
nothing about the Line changes, but now
we'll be able to get that same treatment
to any other Control by using an Attached
property syntax.
So let's recreate, first of all, before we go further,
this triangle using a different type of object.
Instead of using three Line objects,
we can just create a Polyline object.
Here you can see that I'm setting,
I am using Attached properties actually,
to set the left and the top of the Polyline,
and then I start creating a series of Points,
so X,Y pairs that define the various Points
of my Triangle, and then I can even
set the Fill color for my Polyline,
if it all joins together.
But notice that I'm placing this entire
Polyline here at 150 Left, 0 Top,
so everything now, all these Points
are relative to that position that I defined.
Next, just to kind of emphasize the
absolute placement of items here,
I'm creating a TextBlock
and I'm setting it to Canvas style Left
and Canvas style Top to 50 and 150 respectively.
And so we can put anything, not just Shapes,
any Control inside of a Canvas for absolute placement.
Alright, and then we talked about,
I think we've used the Rectangle in the past,
let's go ahead and use the Rectangle here
and I'll add it to another example.
So here I have just a yellow rectangle.
Again, setting the Canvas.Top Attach property
and the Left="0", the Height and the Width,
and I Fill it with the color Yellow.
You'll notice that I have this ZIndex Property,
and that'll allow me to talk about
the last thing that we wanna discuss here
with regards to the Canvas.
And the Canvas allows you to place items
on top of each other, but define
which ones will come if you were to stack them up
and you were to look at them kind of
in a different perspective,
what would the stack be?
So which one is visible first?
In this case, I set the ZIndex of the Ellipse
to 150 and the ZIndex of the yellow Rectangle to 100.
If I change that, you can see that by changing
the ZIndex to 15, it puts the yellow Rectangle
on top of the Ellipse.
So, we are talking in terms of X and Y-Coordinates,
but also there's a Z-Coordinate
in 3-D space, and so the ZIndex will set
that stacking order for you.
So just be aware of that.
Okay, that's really all I wanted to say
about Canvas and the various Shapes
that are available, you can combine these
in interesting ways to pretty much
represent anything that you could imagine.
If you need to draw Shapes in your application.
So hopefully that's helpful.
I think they mostly have, all of them have,
like Click or Tapped, yeah.
So if you needed to respond to touch or click,
you would use the Tapped event to handle that event
if the user were to try to interact
with that given Shape as well.
So that's all I wanted to say about the Canvas
for absolute placement, and then the Shapes
for special use cases where you need to draw
on your application.
Alright, hopefully that was helpful.
We'll see you in the next lesson.
Thanks.