Hi, I'm Bob Tabor with www.learnvisualstudio.net,
and in this lesson, I want to talk about a challenge
you're going to run in into if you attempt to
use VisualStateManager and AdaptiveTriggers to
resize items inside of your DataTemplate for
your GridView, List View Control,
anything that needs an item template.
So, you can see here that I have another version
of my little contact manager application.
And, ideally, what would happen is whenever
we have more screen real estate, those avatar
images would grow larger, and I tried a few things,
but I can't quite get it to work right now.
You see, they stay the same size no matter what.
Now, if you take a look at the code that I've
actually written here, you can see that I've added
a VisualStateManager with VisualStateGroups.
I've got two VisualStates, a Narrow and a WideLayout.
When we're in the NarrowLayout, I want the
AvatarImage's Width and Height to be 100, and
when we're in the WideLayout, I want the Width
and Height to be 200.
So, why isn't this working?
Well, unfortunately, this will not work using
the technique that we've used here where
we're defining that DataTemplate here inline.
What I'm going to need to do is actually breakout
this StackPanel that forms the body of my
DataTemplate into its own code file, and then
I can inside of that code file, I can use a
VisualStateManager and AdaptiveTriggers, and
all that good stuff to re-size on demand.
So, that's what I'm going to attempt to do in this lesson.
So, to begin with I'm going to add a new SserControl to
my Project.
A UserControl, it's just like a Page.
It's just smaller.
It can be reused multiple times.
Usually it just has a snippet, as opposed to an
entire Page Layout.
In this case I'm going to add a New Item, and
in the Add New Item dialogue, I'm going to make sure
to choose User Control, and I'm going to give it
the name ContactTemplate, because that's what
I'm using it for, a template for individual contacts.
Great.
Let me go ahead and just get to that point right there.
And now what I want to do is come back over here,
and in my main MainPage.xaml, I'm going to just
rip out everything right there, between the open
and close DataTemplate, and I go to the
new ContactTemplate Page, and then get rid of
the Grid and just paste in that same StackPanel there.
Okay?
So, we're off to a great start.
What I'm going to need to do to reference that
UserControl now is, inside of my DataTemplate,
I'm going to need to reference the local namespace.
Local, as defined earlier, will just be the local
namespace, whatever the Project name is,
UserControlDataTemplate, as long as your
UserControl is in the same root directory as
everything else in your Project, you'll be just fine.
If you want to put it in a sub-folder, you're going to
need to reference a different namespace up in
your XAML header.
Alright, so here we go.
ContactTemplate, and I'm not sure that I need
to do this, but I am going to just set HorizontalAlignment
HorizontalAlignment="Stretch" and VerticalAlignment
VerticalAlignment="Stretch".
Just say, hey, take up everything you give me as
far as the space is concerned.
And that's all that I should need to do there.
Great.
Now, back in the ContactTemplate, if we were to
try to run the application now, it wouldn't work.
It might even give us errors.
There's a couple of changes that we're going to
need to make first.
First of all, let's try to get this all running,
and then we'll come back and add the
VisualStateManager and the different AdaptiveTriggers.
So, the first thing that I want to do is actually
use the name of the object that we're going to
be binding to.
So, in this case we're going to do Contact.AvatarPath
Contact.AvatarPath, Contact.FirstName
Contact.LastName.
Okay.
And then in the code behind for this ContactTemplate,
I'm going to need to add two different things.
The first thing that I'm going to need to add is
I'm going to need to make a...
property, so I'm going to go Models.Contact,
just the Models.
I could define that in a "Using" statement, but
essentially, I'm just going to reference it like this,
Models.Contact, and then...
we want to expose a new property called Contact
for our UserControl, and we're just going to add a getter.
So, this is just a getter of a full-blown
property definition.
So, we're going to return...
this.DataContext as Models.Contact.
So, essentially what this is going to do is, whenever you are,
whenever one of the Controls on the
ContactTemplate.xaml Page, whenever it needs to
get data, it's going to get data of type Contact,
and it's going to get that data from the data
context for this UserControl.
The DataContext for the UserControl will be
passed in from the MainPage.xaml.
It will be whatever gets, basically, passed in
in the DataTemplate.
So, for the most part, what you can do with this
is just treat this as templated code, copy and paste it.
We're going to add it to our cheat sheet.
You don't need to really understand too much
about what it's doing.
Just understand that you have to have this
line of code and then also in this constructor
for our UserControl, you're going to have to
do one more thing, and that is whenever the
DataContext is changed, there will be a
DataContextChanged event, and what we want
to happen is write this landis expression
that will call the Bindings.Update().
Now this Update is actually being generated
for us again inside.
Because we use the x:Bind statement, like we
talked about previously, this will essentially
say, "Hey, go off and update the data that you're
being bound to."
Again, this can be treated as boiler plate code, as well.
We're going to add it to our cheat sheet.
You don't have to understand too much about how
it works in order to use it.
I think that's the key idea here.
But now that we've added these two lines of code,
and we've made the modification to our
x:Bind statement for each of the items that
we're binding to here by adding the actual
data type for the given property, now we should
be able to, at least, see it working again,
even though we've made no significant changes
to the functionality.
We'll get to that next.
Okay, so it still works.
We're still binding to our same ObservableCollection.
We're just defining that DataTemplate here
in the UserControl.
Now we want to take it to the next step, and that is
to define a VisualStateManager, so that whenever
we re-size the window, that the Image,
that Avatar Image, will grow from
100, 100 to 200, 200.
So, I'm just going to actually paste in a bunch
of code here.
It's pretty much the same code that we had that I,
well let me look here.
Yeah, let me just actually do this.
I'll just grab it from here.
Grab all that.
And then hit Control+X to get it out of my
MainPage.xaml, and then I'm going to take it
over here to the ContactTemplate.xaml,
and put it right here underneath the StackPanel,
like so.
Alright, let's see if that works.
Alright, so this should be pretty small.
What happens when we make it larger?
Oh, hey, it doubled the size of
our avatar icon.
Alright, very proud of this.
So, we're going to use this technique for
our upcoming challenge.
Whenever we want to re-size the window,
not only are we going to re-size, or change
the layout, but we may want to re-size
the actual DataTemplate for our GridView Control.
Since we'll be working in a larger form factor,
we would want to make it possible for the Fonts
and the Images to be larger on a larger screen.
Okay?
So, that's all I wanted to say about this.
This addresses the issue of how do I use
the VisualStateManager and AdaptiveTriggers
inside of a DataTemplate?
Well, you add a UserControl, you make a few
tiny modifications in the code behind, and then
you go ahead and you add your VisualStateManager,
State Triggers, and your setters, and they'll
be applied to each item in your collection.
So, just to prove that this works, let's go ahead
and add Beth, as well, and you can see
she's large and now she is small.
Great.
Okay?
So, I think that's pretty much all we're going to
cover in this little round, and now it's time for
a cheat sheet review and to move on to our next challenge.
See you there.
Thanks.