And one of the last big tasksthat I wanna tackle is adaptive
layout for an application.
Recall what we wanted toaccomplish was to take
the details from the right and
move it under the list wheneverwe're in a narrow layout.
But when we're in a wide layout,
then we want it to bewhere it's at right now.
So we'll adda VisualStateManager and
some VisualStates, andwe'll get it to work.
And then we'll do any cleanup on the UI that we need to
before we add our lastfeature in the next video.
So let's go ahead andget started here.
I'm going to, underneath thisfirst grid that I added in
the previous video, I'm goingto start with the visual state
manager and add a bunchof visual state groups.
We'll create one visual stategroup called Visual State Group.
And then I'm gonna create.
A single visual state,and I'll copy and
paste it to create a second one.
So this first one,we're gonna call Wide.
And this one will be valid,with the state trigger.
So VisualState.StateTriggers andlet me go ahead and
create VisualState.Setters,great.
And here are the triggers,
the minimum windowwidth will be 800.
We can test this with our phoneto make sure it looks good,
with the phone emulatorthat that will work.
If not, well, I think itwill be fine on the phone.
It's just a matter ofthe desktop, how it looks.
Any rate, we'll test it.
All right, setters.
Here we go.Setter Target=,
okay, so this is where thingsstart to get interesting, right.
What we really wanna do is take,let's see, we take this detail
grid, everything insideof the detail grid, and
you know it doescontain quite a bit.
And we wanna move it toa different column and
row based on the currentvisual state.
I think I've lost my mind here,there we go.
So I wanna setthe detail grids row and
column appropriately, andto do that, I'm gonna need to
access it through its name, butI'm using attached properties.
So how do I do that?
Well, I think wedo it like this,
DetailGrid.(Grid.Row) and
we set its value equal to 0, and
we'll do somethingsimilar with a column.
So the column value would be 1.
And then let's go ahead and copythis visual state, paste it,
and we wanna set the minimumwindow width for
this one to 0, andthis is gonna be narrow.
And we're gonna reverse it.
The row will be 1 andthe column will be 0,
and the narrow VisualState.
All right,let's see what we have, and
then we may need to make someother adjustments based on that.
Okay, solet's go ahead and select.
Our data, and just go ahead andget all queued up here.
All right,we have one comic book left.
Okay, great.
And it looks like I still havesome issues here on the right.
We'll have to work on thatin the UI cleanup phase.
I'm gonna get to a certainpoint, where it goes off screen,
and you can see it below.
Boy, that does notlook good at all.
So, I think we're gonna needto make one more change and
then a little bitof clean up here.
The change that we need to make,and
let's just pick anotherone of these as well.
Let's pick Carnage.
Let's see if we get anythinginteresting there, no.
All right, there we go.
Okay, gets a littlemore interesting there.
You'll notice that these runoff to the side of the screen.
When we had a description ora title,
it ran off to the sideof the screen.
And I think the problemthere is the width for
this entire column right here.
So, let's set that.
And to do that, I'm gonnagive this topmost grid,
the columns here, names.
And I can do that byusing the x:Name= and
we'll just callthis "ColumnOne".
And we'll do the same thing forthe second column, like so.
So here in the wide state,
what we wanna do is set
the SetterTarget="ColumnOne.Width".
And we'll make surethat's set to Auto.
And then Column.
Two.width.
We'll set that to *.
And then we'll dothe exact opposite.
When we hit the narrow one,so we'll hit the * there and
Auto there, and hopefully,that'll fix the problem.
Okay, let's run it again.
Okay, we'll pickUnion Jack there.
All right.
Great.
All right,
looks like I do still have somethings falling off to the side.
I think I need towrap the title there.
Honestly, I'll wrap all thetitles, and then I need to add
some more margin on the righthand side here for this.
So let's do this.
Let's come down tothe comic detail.
And I want to.
Nope, move thatover a little bit.
I want to add in thissome text wrapping.
So let's go,TextWrapping="Wrap".
And I think I'm gonna goahead and do the same thing,
even though we didn'tsee it happen,
I wanna do the same thing forthe DetailNameTextBlock as well.
That should handle that problem.
Now I'm also gonna want to addsome margin on the right there
in both of these cases.
So I'm gonna put 10pixels to the right.
That will give usa little breathing room.
All right,let's see what happens now.
Let's pick Klaw.
Looks like it's still grabbing,okay, great.
All right, I like that.
It doesn't buttright up against it.
That's good, that's good,looks great.
Let's pick another one here.
That looks good.
You can see that this wasintended to be used in HTML.
[LAUGH] Let's pick Bishop.
It's a pretty coolpicture of Bishop.
We're still waiting forthe comics to roll in.
There we go.
All right, Cable, good.
Good, good, good.
That looks awesome.
Okay, very cool.
All right, and so
now let's see what it looks likewhen we actually scroll out.
Okay, still looks good,looks great.
All right,the next thing I wanna do, and
I'm really enjoying this andenjoying the way it looks,
I'm gonna try it on a phone.
So let's put it in the mobileemulator and run it there,
just to make sureeverything looks good.
All right, there we go.
Let's go ahead andselect one of these items.
You can see it's listed below.
Boy, that description area isgoing to be awfully small.
But ultimately, yeah.
I wish there was an easyway to wrap around.
Well, we might wannathink about that.
I don't really have a goodsolution in mind just yet.
Other than [LAUGH] Icould put this whole area
in a user control, andthen whenever we're in
the narrow width,we could change its layout too.
But that's not somethingI wanna take on.
I didn't even think about theway this would look on a phone.
But that would be the next stepthat I would have to take if I
was wanting to releasethis into the wild.
Okay, but I think it'sgood enough for now.
I have one more cool featurethat I wanna add, and
that is Cortana integration.
So excited about that.
We'll learn about itin the next lesson.
We'll see you there, thanks.