Alright, so we're making great progress.
The next thing we need to focus on is the animation
and the events surrounding the countdown
of the ProgressBar and what happens when we get
all the way to the end of countdown.
We need to fire off an event that we can handle
and then decide what to do.
There's really two scenarios where we need to
worry about countdown.
First is whenever we're cooling off, there's a cooling-off
period waiting for the next round to start,
and then there's the next round itself
that's actually ongoing and we are waiting,
we're playing the music and we're counting down to
determine the value or the score
for the player if he makes a selection
at a given moment in time.
So, to get the animation to work,
I'm going to have to add a Storyboard.
I'm going to add a Storyboard to the Page's resources.
So let's get started with that.
We didn't talk about storyboards and animations,
I only briefly described what they were.
You'll get a little bit more of an insight into
what they are, and Keyframes are Actions that happen
at certain moments in time during
the playback of the animation.
Hopefully you'll get the hang of it here as we get started.
Like I said, the first thing that we're going to do
is actually add a Page.Resources section to our app.
And, I'm going to create a Storyboard
and Storyboard, let's give it a name,
and you can see it doesn't have a name, but I'm going to
use the "x:" from this namespace here, and that will
allow me to attach a name to a Storyboard,
and I'm just going to call it the "countdown" storyboard.
Because we're going to need to access it progamatically
and that's why I want to give it name, and then
I'm also going to handle the completed event.
So, I'll go ahead and add a complete and
we'll come back to that later.
Now, there's different types of animations that I can add.
In this particular case, I want a DoubleAnimationUsingKeyframes
DoubleAnimationUsingKeyframes, and so, a double is the data type,
I want it to have values that are numeric and
using keyframes allows me to identify key moments
in the life of the animation where I change key values
of given properties, alright, so hopefully that will
make enough sense to at least get started with it, and
we're going to give a few important pieces of information.
For example, the Storyboard.TargetName, this is what we want
to affect and I think I've called this "MyProgressBar" so
that's what this animation will deal with and then
the property of that Storyboard, so TargetProperty equals-- and
this we're going to just have to kind of follow this,
essentially, what I want to do is set the value...
So, typically with a ProgressBar, you have a maximum
and minimum, so I think that's pretty much what that's
denoting, just using a based class called range.
Then there's one other property I need to set,
which is called EnableDependentAnimation and
I'm going to set that to "true."
And now what I want to do is actually add another keyframe.
So I'm going to add a DiscreteDoubleKeyframe
and the key time will be, in this first case
at zero seconds, I want the value of my
ProgressBar to be 100.
And then I'm going to copy this like ten times.
Copy and paste.
I'll come back to that in just a moment.
And so, at 001...
actually let me get rid of all this...
Alright, at 001, I want the value to still be 100.
At 002, I want the value to be 90.
Hopefully you can see the pattern emerging.
And so now I'm just going to copy and paste a bunch of these
so at three seconds, four seconds, five seconds, eight, nine
and then at ten seconds, and we'll just keep counting
down the values, 70, 60, 50, 40, 30, 20 and 10, OK.
Back here on the MainPage.xaml.cs I'm going to
create a helper method.
So, we'll start the cooldown and basically, MyProgressBar
Actually I can just call it Countdown.Begin()
Here, let's do this, whenever we load up, finish there,
we'll just call it StartCooldown()
Let's see how this works.
Yup, and there we go, you can see how we're
starting the cooldown, so we'll deliver a message,
something like "Getting ready for Round 1, Round 2, Round 3"
Now at this point we fired off, when we get to the end,
we get to the Countdown_Completed.
So we've got to figure out what we want to do there.
And like I've said, there's two scenarios.
There's one where music is actually playing and then there's
another scenario where there's no music playing.
So, I'm going to actually keep track of the current state
of the app by creating a _playingMusic boolean, and
I'm going to initialize this value "false" and this will
allow us to determine the current state of the app
once we hit the countdown.
So, here, if we're not playing music,
So, if not _playingMusic then what we need to do
is start playing some music and
then we'll do kind of the opposite, the StartCountdown.
So, the cooldown is different than the countdown.
The countdown will be where you're actually playing music
and we're waiting for user input
to determine what the correct song is,
so let's call this StartCountDown.
Here, we're going to set _playingMusic equal to "true"
and then I'm also going to change the...
color of the ProgressBar to red,
so I'm getting ready for that here.
So, MyProgressBar.Foreground equals brush.
Then in the InstructionTextBlock, I'm going to say
"GO" ... it's time to listen...
listen to music...
and I'm also going to set the Foreground
equal to that same red color there,
and then I'm going to call countdown begin again.
So, in the cooldown we kind of want to do the exact opposite
So, I'm going to StartCooldown(), we're going to set
_playingmusic equal to "false"
and actually, let me grab several things here
This will be blue instead of red.
And then in the InstructionTextBlock
So, here's another place where I'm going to have to
keep track of which round we're in.
Let's go up here,
and let's go: int _round equals zero
Yeah, seems right, ok.
So, then here, we're going to go
_round plus one because that'll be the next...
the next round will be round one right,
and, I'm also going to do InstructionTextBlock.Foreground
equals brush, like that.
We're going to call StartCountdown()
And, here what I want to do is...
there's a bunch of things that have to happen,
like, we're going to evaluate the user's selection, and
score it, and all that kind of stuff, and then
eventually, we're also going to...
we're going to want to start the cooldown again.
So StartCooldown() here.
Alright, so let's see how this works.
OK, so we're getting ready for round 1.
Alright, and you can see here now we're playing.
And ideally, I would make a selection here
and it'll reset everything, but I'm going to go ahead
and let it tick all the way down.
OK, so we're just kind of waiting here, you get
minimal points at this point even if you selected it true,
but by selecting a song, it will start the next round,
we just have to increment the round number.
So that's one of the things we'll want to do here.
It's going to be a round like that...
Whoops, what I wanted to do was ++.
Can we do that?
Yea, great.
OK, so we got the countdown working,
got the Storyboard working.
We need to select the next song that we want played,
and that's really going to get kicked off
here when the cooldown is completed
and this fires and we're not playing music
that means we want to start playing music, so
here I want to pick a song, so...
let's do something like this, var song equals pickSong()
and we don't have that implemented just yet, so let's
create private void pickSong
and actually it's not going to be void,
it's going to return a Song.
And what we need to do is
first of all, we're going to need to use the Random class,
and, so here's what my thought process is,
this is what I would like to do.
I would like to have a list of unused songs,
songs that we've not touched yet that are still available
on that list of songs we initially picked out.
So of all the songs, give me all the songs where
the "used" property is "false" so we need to add another
attribute to "song" called "used."
And, obviously by default, that would be...
that should be false, but we'll populate that.
And now what we'll want to do is grab the random number.
It goes Random.Next() give me a random number
of unusedSongs.count like that
and so then we'll get the randomSong...
equals unusedSongs.element at randomNumber
and so that randomSong now is currently the selected song
so I'm going to set it's selected attribute to "true"
and then return that randomSong, like so.
So we pick the song,
and now I need to go "MyMediaElement.SetSource"
and I want to set it to my song.
Now the Song class does contain
the song file, right.
That's of type StorageFile, and in order to call this
SetSource() method I'm going to need to give it two things.
First of all, I'm going to need to give it the stream
from the file itself so basically I need to open up the file
and give it a pipeline into that file,
and then I need to give it the content type, the mime type.
So that's easy enough, I can just
use a property called ContentType.
But, the other one, I'm going to have to do
actually something a little bit nifty here.
Song.SongFile.Open, I want you to open yourself and
I need an access mode just for read-only,
I'm not going to write to you.
Now, obviously this is async, so it's await-able,
I have to do something like that...
In fact, let's go ahead and knock that to the next line,
put that on the next line, and do that.
And so that would make this
async...
(Do I not even return a task to that...)
(I don't know that I do...)
(I'm not going to this time. OK)
So, MyMediaElement.SetSource, and then
I want to start the countdown after I've made that...
after I've made that pick.
So let's see what happens here.
We're pretty close here to a working prototype.
OK, we grab all the song, now let's
get ready for round one.
If we're lucky, at the end of round one,
when this goes away, when we get down to
the end of the cooldown...
Oh, and here we go
[Music playing]
Ok, so it mostly worked.
There's some things after the click I've got figure out,
like, did they click on the right song or not,
if they didn't what are we going to do then.
But we'll get to that.
Actually, I think we're good to go in this video.
We will continue on to the next one where we actually
do that evaluation of what the user clicked on
and what points do we give them as a result of that,
so we'll do that next, we're doing great.