Hi, I'm Bob Tabor with www.learnvisualstudio.net
and this is another cheat sheet review session
covering videos 25 through, I guess, what, 29 or so?
Alright, so let's go ahead and add to what we
previously had here, looking at lesson number 25
talking about some of the additional
common Controls in XAML.
Looked at the TimePicker, we noticed that
it had a special ClockIdentifier that allowed us
to create AM/PM versus military time clocks for selection.
The CalendarDatePicker which just showed a little
representation of an area that can be selected
and then you click on it and it will actually
slow a Flyout with a menu or with
a calendar on it, you can choose the placeholder
text in that little area that you click on or tap on.
Then we looked at the more full featured CalendarView
and this allows us to make single or multiple selections
for our Calendar, here I show how to handle the
selected date change to then and then show
in a TextBlock all of the selected dates
using this little link statement here that
projects out the month and the day.
Put its in Array and then joins them together with a comma.
Next, we looked at the FlyoutMenu,
and we applied it to a Button, but we said
we can apply it to lots of different things.
Actually, just the Flyout in this particular case,
it just would allow us to create a little,
a dialogue on screen, we can put anything
we want to in that dialogue, I think I
styled it up with a StackPanel Label
or rather a TextBlock and a Button
and we can hide it once it's actually shown
by handling an event, like a Button
inside of that Flyout and just called
Myflyout.Hide() or whatever the name
of the Flyout that you've created.
The corollary to this is the FlyoutMenu
which I just accidentally set a moment ago
and this allows you create a contextual menu
from, again, any Control, I just happened
to show it with a Button.
You can create not only FlyoutMenu items
and handle the Click or Tapped event
which I'm not displaying here, you can create
a separator to create visual separation,
a little line between items, you can create a sub menu
by using the MenuFlyoutSubItem element.
Or you can create a toggle menu item by
choosing the ToggleMenuFlyoutItem.
I also, again, point out that this
little technique of the Flyout or the
MenuFlyout can be applied to many
different types of Controls, you can learn
more about it at that URL.
Alright, next up we talked about the
autoSuggestBox and this was pretty neat
and we're going to use this here in an
upcoming challenge, here we have...
The, we can change the QueryIcon
by default, we set it to, here, let me (mumble),
we set it to little magnifying glass,
the Find QueryIcon and we also changed the
PlaceholderText, but the real power is
in this TextChanged EventHandler which
we handle here, you can see.
This time we're just going to go against this simple
Array of Strings and we filter it using a Where link clause,
then we add those items to an array and set them
as the item Source for our AutoSuggestBox.
That, as we type additional letters, it will
reduce the number of options, then we can
use the arrow keys to select one of the items.
Then I'm just going to paste these three
in together even though they're not
necessarily related, we looked at the SliderControl
which is used often in the Settings panel
in Windows 10, the ProgressBar where we
can set the Maximum and the Minimum.
Or, I'm sorry, just the Maximum for the ProgressBar.
Here I created a Binding statement, we'll talk
about x:Bind a little bit later,
we bound it to the SliderValue so that when we
move the Slider, we were also moving the ProgressBar.
If we didn't want to do that, we could just
manually set the Value attribute of the ProgressBar
in C# or whatever.
Then finally show the ProgressRing and we can turn
on that ProgressRing by setting IsActive="True",
or we could stop it and no longer display it
setting it to False.
Alright, next up, in the next lesson we talked
about the ScrollViewer and this is going to
be a crucial item as well, it allows us to
add a number of items that are...
That don't display in the current window size.
And give us scrolling ability, horizontally and vertically,
to look around that window.
Here I'm setting the HorizontalScrollBarVisibility="Auto"
HorizontalScrollBarVisibility="Auto", but you can also say
Hidden or always on and then I said
you can put anything you want to
inside the ScrollViewer, but the ScrollViewer
cannot be inside of a StackPanel, if you put it
inside of a StackPanel, it won't do anything at all.
Okay, next up we talked about the Canvas
and Shapes, I'm going to just paste in
the first couple, let me just paste in the whole thing.
I just wanted to cover this for the sake
of completeness, the Canvas allows you
to do absolute positioning via Attached properties,
so unlike the RelativePanel or even the Grid,
the StackPanel, the Canvas is for
absolute positioning, we said typically
that's not a great thing, a great way to use it,
but it does have its uses, especially when
it combined with some of the Line,
the Rectangle, the Ellipse, for doing drawing
or any kind of diagramming or anything
that has a visual component to it.
Showed you how to use the Line, the Line
we could actually utilize this outside of the Canvas,
but the Polyline, you'll noticed that we used
the Canvas to set the top in the
left-hand corners in offset and then
filled in the Points.
X,Y Point positions in order to create a Triangle.
Then also we talked about the Rectangle and the Ellipse,
I think we've used those before in this series,
just didn't really talk about them.
Then finally talked about the Canvas's
Attached property called ZIndex and essentially,
you think about everything we're looking at
as flat, but what if we were to turn it 3D
and then we were able to see the order
in which things were stacked and sitting
on top of each other and that's what ZIndex does.
The higher the number, the higher up
in the stack it is, the more it covers, okay.
Next up, we talked about XAML styles.
First of all, we started by just looking at
Resources, we created, for example a SolidColorBrush,
gave it a Key and then set its particular Attribute
in this case the Color and so we can use
this everywhere that we want to use this
accent Color Brown just by referencing the Key.
Then if we were to change that color from
brown to red in the future, nothing changes,
all we have to do is just change it in one
little spot here and it changes it for
the entire application.
Styles are like those Resources on steroids,
they allow us to set multiple Attributes
all at once by giving it a Key and identifying
a TargetType, so this particular Style
is generated specifically for a Button.
Now the way that you actually apply these things
is through a Binding statement and the
Binding statement will look like this where
you have the open and closing curly braces,
the word StaticResource and then
the name of the Resource, so it could be
the Style Key or the Resource Key MyBrush
or my Button Style.
Then we talked about creating these ResourceDictionaries
ResourceDictionaries at multiple levels, at the Page,
at the Application, but then also we said
you could create a ResourceDictionary file, I showed you
how to do that by going to the Project,
Add New Item and then Resource Dictionary
was one of the options there, so we added a new file
called Dictionary1.xaml and then we
defined a SolidColorBrush there
and used it in our application.
The way you use it is to merge those
ResourceDictionaries that you defined together,
in this case not only did I add the Dictionary1.xaml
to this particular Page, but then also one I'm
not displaying on this cheat sheet called Dictionary2
and then I can, in the rest of the Page
reference any of the Styles that were
created either at the Page, the Application
or any of the two ResourceDictionaries that we have.
ResourceDictionaries, again, help us manage
lots of styles, we're going to reuse them in multiple projects.
They're great for organization, things of that nature.
Then finally, we just talked about Themes, let me
give you a nice URL for learning more about Theme Resources.
Essentially, if you find something that is a
Binding statement with ThemeResource,
you can take a look at that style by
putting your mouse cursor on it, hit F12
and that'll open up a file called Generic.xaml.
We saw where there were a couple of different
Styles that we could choose from that would
allow us to utilize the colors, the theme colors
that were selected by the user whether on
the desktop or the phone or even an Xbox One.
In addition to that we can also request a Theme,
we saw how by default our application requests
the Light Theme, but we changed it to Dark
and saw what the impact was.
However, in all cases regarding Themes and Styles,
High Contrast Themes will override because
it's really a usability issue.
Finally, we talked about the fact that
there are lots of different Themes not just
for colors, but then also for things like
Font Styles and so to illustrate this we went
to the Properties window, went to the Style Property,
clicked the little designer, it popped open...
A contextual menu that allowed us to select
from several styles that were predefined.
We chose the HeaderTextBlock style and some
of the others and we saw how now it shared,
our TextBlock shared the same Style as other...
Items that we would see typically in Windows 10.
Then finally, many of the Styles that were
defined in the Generic.xaml had this
BasedOn attribute that created a baseline style
and then there would be styles that derived from that style
based on that original style and then it'd add or change
some of the attributes, so it's very much
like Cascading Style Sheets in a sense.
If you're familiar with that in web development,
this should feel pretty similar.
Okay, so quick review, hopefully all those
concepts make sense and we're moving on
and continuing to add complexity,
you're doing great, hang in there.
I don't know that we're about halfway done yet,
but we're getting close, alright?
We'll see you in the next lesson where
we start moving on to some advanced content.
See you there, thanks.