Hi, I'm Bob Tabor with www.learnvisualstudio.net.
Up until now we've only created apps
with a single page, the MainPage.XMAL,
and while that's fine for simple apps,
you might have a use case where
you need to add additional pages,
and so we'll talk about that in this lesson.
So, typically, you'd want to load a new page into your app
whenever you need new functionality,
or new layout, or new content,
so it's possible that you could create
a complex app and change out the layout
and the functionality all in a single page,
but by adding additional pages
it allows you to decompose functionality
into smaller, more manageable units,
and so this will reduce the complexity
of the application's development and its maintenance.
So pages in the Universal Windows Platform
are roughly equivalent to web pages in web development.
So as a web developer you might create several webpages
and create hyperlinks between the pages
so that users can navigate
in between pages in the website,
so then the end user would load up their frame,
their web browser, and would navigate to your home page
and then navigate to each of the pages using the hyperlinks,
or they might navigate then, at some point,
using the back and the forward buttons
on the toolbar of the frame, their web browser.
So in Universal Windows Platform your pages
are hosted in Frame objects,
that's why I keep using that word
instead of the web browser, just to enforce this idea,
so, in fact, you might not even realize this,
but the Frame is critical to the application itself,
so at the very highest level,
as your application starts up,
there's an application object
and then there is a window inside of that,
so that will give you all of the Chrome
in a Window's Desktop version
the X, the minimize, and the maximize buttons
over here in the right-hand corner,
and the title, and things of that nature
along that very top bar.
Inside of that sits that Frame,
which will host pages,
and so as you can see in this new example that I've created,
NavigationExample, I've created it,
and I've loaded up App.xaml.cs.
That's all I've done to it so far.
If you take a look down in line number 53,
see where this all kind of gets set up.
So a lot of hard work is done for you automatically
by using this blank template,
and so you can see here where we get a reference
to the Frame inside of the window,
and they call it rootFrame,
and then in the rootFrame,
you can navigate to a specific page
in your application.
In this case, we're navigating to MainPage,
so we give it a type of a data type
that we want it to navigate to,
and then it creates the instance of that type,
and it will pass in parameters as arguments
and things of that nature, alright?
So while we're here,
I'm actually going to delete this diagnostic,
so get rid of that,
and at some point later on
we're going to learn about
loading new pages into this topmost Frame,
what's called the rootFrame,
but for getting started
I think it would be easier to just talk
about adding a frame to our MainPage.xaml
so that we can load individual pages
in and out of that Frame
that's hosted by the MainPage,
so in your mind think of,
you've got the app, the window, the Frame, the rootFrame.
It loads in MainPage.xaml,
which has a Frame on it,
and then will load in Page One,
Page Two, Page Three, Page Four,
so in that scenario we're going to delegate
the responsibility of hosting other information
in MainPage as well,
like the search bar at the top
or the SplitPanel down the left-hand side
for navigation purposes.
Alright, so enough theory.
Let's go ahead and get started with this.
I want to create a new app,
and the first thing I'm going to do is add new pages,
so let's add three new pages.
We'll go to the Project Menu
and select Add New Item.
Make sure that you select the Blank Page Template.
Don't select XAML view.
It has to be Blank Page Template, alright?
We'll call this first one Page1.
We'll add another one called Page2,
and a third one called Page3.
All right, and we'll come back to those
in just a moment,
but those will be the pages that will load in and out
of our MainPages Frame.
So let's open up MainPage.xaml,
and let's go ahead and lay this out.
In fact, I think I'm just going to go ahead
and get rid of the, let me get rid of the
the designer completely and just go
completely to XAML view,
since we have so limited space to work with here.
The first thing I'm going to do
in the MainPage.xaml
is to add a StackPanel in replacing
that Grid that comes automatically.
Inside of that I want to add
another StackPanel and a Frame,
and I am going to give the Frame a name,
so I can access it programmatically.
I'm going to call it MyFrame.
We'll deal with that in just a little bit.
This StackPanel, I want to make this
into a horizontal button bar,
so what I'm going to do
is just set the Orientation="Horizontal",
and I'm going to create three Buttons,
and I'll set the Bargin in between them
to 20, whoops, whoops, whoops.
"0,0,20,0".
Alright, and we'll copy that
and paste that a couple times.
I'm going to give this first Button a name of
HomeButton.
I'm going to set the Content="Home",
and then I'm going to set a click event
equal to a new EventHandler.
We'll come back to that one in just a moment.
Alright, this one we're going to name it BackButton.
We'll set the Content="Back",
and then get it a click event called
BackButton_Click,
and then, finally, I am going to create the ForwardButton,
set it's Content="Forward",
and then add a click EventHandler,
as well, called ForwardButton_Click.
Great.
Alright, so as our application loads up,
as our Frame loads,
what we want to do is load
Page1 into view automatically,
so let's go into the code behind
MainPage.xaml.cs,
and the very first thing that we want to do
is in the constructor for the page,
I want to access MyFrame,
and I'm going to call its Navigate method,
so just like we saw in the app.xaml.cs,
and we navigated to a typeof MainPage,
here we're going to navigate to a typeof(Page1), like so.
Whoops, let me use
the typeof operator correctly.
There we go.
Alright.
So that should load in Page1.
While I'm here,
I'm going to go ahead and flush out
the Home, Back, and Forward buttons.
Now the HomeButton will be easy.
We're just going to whenever you click it
go automatically back to Page1,
so I'll just copy and paste whatever
I had in the constructor down here
into the HomeButton_Click event.
However, in the Back and Forward buttons
what we want to do is work with the history,
or rather the BackStack, of the Frame,
so the Frame will maintain
the history of pages that the user navigates through,
and it will replay those navigation requests
whenever we go back or forward.
We have to ask the navigation's BackStack,
"Can we go forward?
"Can we go backward?
"And if we can, then go ahead and go back,
"or go ahead and go forward, respectively."
So we'll do this.
if(MyFrame.CanGoBack).
That's true or false, if it's true,
then we'll do
MyFrame.GoBack().
See how easy it is?
And we'll do something similar here for froward.
if(MyFrame.CanGoForward),
then MyFrame.GoForward().
Great.
All right, so I think that will do it
for the moment for the Main Page.
Let me shut that down,
and now what I want to do
is go to the Page1.xaml,
and here again I'm just going to collapse
and only look at that view there.
Alright, I'm going to replace the Grid with a StackPanel,
and then inside of here I'm going to add a TextBlock,
and I'll make the font size kind of large,
so we can see what we're doing here,
and I'll set the Text equal to whatever
the current page that I am on,
so Page1, like that,
and then I'm going to add a HyperlinkButton.
Now I could add any type of control
where I can handle an event,
and handle it to tell the Frame to navigate
to whatever next page that we want to navigate to.
I use the HyperlinkButton because
it connotes navigation,
just like a web page's hyperlink connotes navigation,
and as we'll learn,
this navigation, this HyperlinkButton,
has a special property
that's different than just a Button
that's been styled up like a hyperlink.
It'll actually have a navigate your eye property
that will allow us to navigate out to a website,
so, actually, on this Page1,
I'll add a second version of the HyperlinkButton
just to demonstrate that.
Alright, so what was I doing?
Oh, yeah.
So let's give it, well, we don't need to give it a name.
Let's give it some Text,
or actualy Content.
Great, and, so, we'll say,
"Go to Page 2,"
and we'll handle the click event like that,
and as I promised let's go ahead
and create a second HyperlinkButton,
and this time we'll say,
"Go to Microsoft.com,"
and we'll set the NavigateURI="http://www.microsoft.com"
NavigateURI="http://www.microsoft.com"
Alright?
Alright, so that should do there.
Now I'm going to copy these first two controls,
the TextBlock and the HyperlinkButton.
I'm going to put that in Page2,
so let's go ahead and collapse that,
get into the XAML view,
let's paste that here,
and I'm going to change out...
This can go to Page2.
This will be Page3.
Oh, and we need a StackPanel for ours, don't we?
Great.
And then, finally, go to Page3,
collapse that,
open up XAML view,
replace the Grid with what we have here,
and we'll just get rid of this
HyperlinkButton at that point.
We won't need it.
We'll call this Page 3.
In fact, what I'm going to do
is actually put something else in there soon,
but let's just stop right there.
Okay, so now let's go ahead and run the application,
see what we have so far,
see if we can get this to work,
if I've missed anything.
Whoops, something failed.
What did we miss?
Oh.
Okay, that's easy enough to fix.
Let's go to Page2,
and I'll just go ahead and hit the F12 key on my keyboard.
That should work,
and, hey, while I'm here,
let's go ahead and navigate, right?
So Frame.Navigate(),
and we'll go Frame.Navigate(typeof(Page3))
Frame.Navigate(typeof(Page3)) like so.
and you might wonder why am I
referencing Frame and not MyFrame?
After all, the Frame's name is MyFrame, right?
True, whenever we call the Navigate method,
and we pass in the type that we want
to create a new instance of,
that Navigate method will create that instance
and will kind of
act as a factory in so much
that it will set up the instantiation of that object
by setting its various properties.
One of the properties that it sets for a given page
is the Frame property,
and sets it to whatever the parent Frame is,
so that's how we get a reference to the current Frame
that we're sitting inside of
in order to call its Navigate method, okay?
All right, so we did that.
Let's see, did we do that in Page1 as well?
Eh, no, we didn't.
So let's just copy this,
and stick it there,
and we'll call Page2.
All right, does that work?
Alright, some success.
Let me pull this down.
Great.
Alright, so the first thing I'm going to do
is I'm actually going to click
the hyperlink button that will go
to Microsoft.com,
that opens up my Edge browser,
navigates to Microsoft.com.
Pretty cool.
So that's what the Navigate Your Eye does.
Next I'm going to click the Go To Page 2,
which goes to Page 2,
and then I'll click Go To Page 3.
Great.
Now I'm going to click the back button,
and the forward button, and then the home button,
so you can see we covered all of those scenarios.
Very cool.
So that's the most basic scenario that we can cover.
Let's add a wrinkle to this.
In page number two, what I'm going to do
is add a TextBox,
and I'm going to call that
ValueTextBox because I'm not
feeling very original at the moment,
and I think that's all I am going to do there.
Well, I will set the width
because I think it'll be small if I don't.
We'll set it to 200 pixels.
You probably want to use a relative size
if this was a real application,
but it's not, it's just a demo,
so let's not worry about it too much,
and I am actually going to add that same
TextBox to Page3 right there.
Now what I want to do
when I navigate from Page 2 to Page 3,
I want to pass along the value
that the user typed in the TextBox
and then display that value
in the TextBox in Page 3.
How do we do that?
Well, it's pretty easy, actually.
If we take a look at Page2.xaml.cs,
there's an overloaded version of the Navigate method
that allows us to pass in anything we want
as a parameter that is then retrieved
by the other page that we're navigating to,
so in this case we'll just take ValueTextbox.Text,
and we'll pass it over to the other side.
Now retrieving it on the other side
is a little bit trickier.
What we got to do there
in the Page3.xaml.cs.
Let's get down to it here.
We're going to have to override
a certain method on this
called the
OnNavigatedTo,
and this event will fire every time
that we navigate to a new...
Or to the page, right,
and so what we can do inside of here, then,
is to retrieve the value
through the NavigationEventArgs,
so we'll go var value = e.Parameter;
var value = e.Parameter;,
and we're going to cast this
because it comes in as object
because it can hold anything.
We'll just have to, in this case,
cast it to string.
You would cast it to a class.
Anything you want,
and then we'll go ValueTexbox.Text = value;
ValueTextBox.Text = value;.
that should work.
Let's run the application again.
All right, and this time let's go to Page 2,
and here we're just going to type in some junk
and go to Page 3,
and we get that same junk there.
Awesome.
So what happens when we go back?
Wait a second.
We've lost our value.
Where did it go?
Let's go forward.
Well, it's still there,
but it's not here.
What happened?
Well, remember what I said,
whenever you're navigating through the BackStack,
through the history of the Frame,
it's going to replay the Navigation event.
In our case, the step of navigating
from Page 2 to Page 3
included some text,
so it gets picked up as we replay that event
and displayed into that TextBox.
However, when we go back to Page 2,
when we navigated from Page 1 to Page 2,
we didn't send anything over.
It replays that event,
and there's nothing there
as a result of it.
Okay, but what if we wanted to kind of
maintain state between these pages?
Well, actually, that's pretty simple,
and there's several different ways
we can go about this.
Some people might say,
"Hey, don't do this.
"This is not quite the right way to go about it."
They're probably right,
but I want to keep this as simple as possible,
and as long as you don't do anything abusive
to your application,
it should be okay for you.
Just keep in mind that there are probably
more elegant solutions to this
than doing what I'm about to do.
So since we said that the application
sits at the very top of the stack.
When you launch an app,
there's an application object
that hosts a Window, that hosts a Frame,
that hosts MainPage, right?
What we can do is kind of treat this app class,
this instance of app,
as a global variable,
and so we can get to it pretty easily.
So inside of the class's definition.
Here, I kind of went to the wrong spot there.
Inside of this class's definition,
what I'm going to do at the very top if this
is actually just paste in this line of code,
and here I'm creating a property
or just a field called SomeImportantValue,
and I'm making it static, of type string,
and then saying this is internal,
which means that anything inside of this app
can access that variable,
but nothing outside of the application, okay?
So SomeImportantValue.
What we'll do here, then,
in Page2.xaml.cs
is we're going to set App.SomeImportantValue = ValueTextBox.Text;
App.SomeImportantValue = ValueTextbox.text;, right?
At this point, we really don't need to pass
this into Page4, or Page3, rather,
if we didn't want to,
but I'm going to go ahead
and leave that code there for now.
So we've set this,
and it's storing it, saving in memory,
and what I'm going to do
is actually go back here to Page3,
I'm going to grab this,
override, and put it back in Page2.
All right, so on Page2 now
we're going to override the OnNavigatedTo,
and if our SomeImportantValue
is not an empty string,
so If...
Is not...
I had to think about that for a second.
If not string is null or empty,
and then I'm going to look at the string,
then I want to preform the following.
I'm going to take whatever
was in here
and set it there.
Just get rid of that.
We don't need that,
and take that,
and put that there.
Great.
So let's go ahead and run it now.
All right, so go Page 2.
Here we're going to type something in.
Go to Page 3,
and now we're going to go back,
and we have the value again,
so it worked.
Very cool.
All right, the next thing that I want to demonstrate
is how to navigate
to a whole different page
at the RootFrame level,
and this shouldn't be too difficult.
Let's go to our MainPage.xaml.cs.
Actually, to the MainPage.xaml.
I'm going to add one more Button,
and I'm going to call this NavigateButton,
and set the Content="NavigateRootFrame"
Content="NavigateRootFrame",
and we'll set the Click equal to a new EventHandler,
and I don't think I need to set a margin.
Think we'll be okay there,
so in this we'll hit, F12, we'll get in here,
and this time what I want to do is use the.
Remember we said that Page has a Frame property,
so I'm just going to use the This keyword
saying, "This instance of
"MainPage.Frame.Navigate,
and then we're going to say type of
Page2 like that.
So let's run the application,
and you can see that now I've navigated to Page 2.
As a result of that, I've lost the Chrome,
the outermost StackPanel,
and I've lost my navigation buttons, okay?
So we'd have to figure out how to get those back,
and it's not as crucial that we do this
for the hamburger-style navigation
that we'll utilize in Windows 10 apps,
but I did want to demonstrate
how to do that nonetheless.
Alright, now the final thing that I want to talk about
is what happens whenever we run this
on a mobile device?
Because the phone has something unique about it
that the other form factors,
the other device families do not have.
You can see that we have this representation
of the back button here on the Chrome of our emulator.
Actually, now it's inside the emulator.
Visible area there,
and let's go to Page 2,
and we can even type in some junk here
and go to Page 3,
and then we can go back, all right,
and we can go forward.
Now what if we were to hit this back arrow?
What we might want to happen
is that we want to go back to Page 2,
then to Page One,
but when I hit the back button,
it completely escapes out of our application
and goes back to the Home Page,
and, unfortunately, how to fix this
will require a little bit more explanation,
so I want to revisit this topic
whenever we talk working with API's,
addressing capabilities that are available
to specific device families
when using extension SDK's,
software development kits,
so these extension SDK's
you'll recall from way back in lesson number three.
They allow you to harness features
that are available only on that particular device family,
so in this case, this device family has,
or potentially has, a back button,
this little back arrow,
and how do we handle it in that case?
We'll, again, we'll come back to this,
and this same example,
and implement that,
and show it running it on the phone correctly,
so when we hit the back button
it navigates back in our application
not just out of our application completely.
We'll show it how to, basically, support
hardware input buttons on the phone, okay?
We'll come back to that later.
Doing great.
Let's continue on.
We'll see you in the next lesson.
Thanks.