Hi, I'm Bob Tabor with
www.LearnVisualStudio.net, and I want you to take a look
on-screen right now because
I wanted to illustrate an idea,
it's easier to show you than explain it.
Here I have a simple application with a Grid,
I set the Grid's Background="Red"
and I have a simple TextBlock and I've got a,
I don't know, 16 point, 18 point font there.
And so watch what happens though whenever I resize this.
I get to a certain point and
it triggers the change of the BackgroundColor
to Yellow, and the FontSize to a larger FontSize,
I think like 24 or something.
Now let's continue to resize,
and the Cackground color changes to blue
and I use an even larger Font for the TextBlock.
And so this is made possible by an object called
the VisualStateManager and it does
exactly what it sounds like, it manages
the visual state of your application,
where things belong, the sizes of things,
the colors of things based on Triggers that you create.
So, essentially you can manipulate any property
of any object, you can resize,
reposition, set the visibility,
you can set the FontSize, set the FontFamily.
Anything that you possibly can imagine
based on the current size of the window,
or the current available screen real estate.
And so think about how that applies to the
Universal Windows Platform.
One of the selling points is that you're able
to write one code base and then use it
across all these different form factors.
And so this allows you to accommodate different
screen resolutions for different form factors
with the same code base.
And so this is a very foundational concept
and what we're going to talk about briefly in this lesson,
we'll talk about how this applies to adaptive layout,
in other words, changing the entire layout
of your application based on the screen size,
the form factor.
We'll talk about that in the very next video.
But again, this is all made possible because of
a object called the VisualStateManager,
You create a VisualState group and inside of that group
you create a series of States.
So a State can be anything, you give it a name
and you give it some Triggers.
So in this case take a look at
the application we were just looking at.
So here I have a VisualState that I called Phone.
I have another VisualState that I called Tablet,
or VisualStateTablet,
And then another VisualState
that I called VisualStateDesktop.
Now you can name these things anything you want to.
And I don't know if there's any standard sizes or
anything that you've got to stick with.
It's whatever makes sense for your application,
and that's why I think, you know, testing your application
continually on different devices, and VisualStudio
obviously makes that very simple.
But testing it as many different form factors as possible,
will help you see the optimal layout
for that given form factor.
So here we go, we have a VisualState.
And a VisualState is comprised of two things.
First of all, a series of Triggers
and then a series of Setters.
So when a Trigger is essentially, in this case,
either the MinWindowWidth,
or the MinWindowHeight,
that once it's achieved will Trigger
this particular VisualState.
So once that State is Triggered,
then it applies these Setters.
And these Setters are very similar to the Setters
that we had in Styles right?
Where we have a Target, property,
so here's the object, the ColorGrid object.
And I'm going to set the Background Value="Red".
Alright, same thing with the TextBlock,
this MessageTextBlock.
And I use the dot notation just like we would to access
members of an object in C#.
So we use the dot notation to access the property FontSize
and we set it's value to 18, whenever we are in that
smallest state where the MinWindowWidth="0".
The next State up has a Trigger
of MinWindowWidth="600".
And at that point then we were applying,
the Setters that we're applying are setting the
background ColorGrid to yellow,
and the FontSize of the MessageTextBlock to 36.
And then finally the desktop, as long as the
MinWindowWidth="800",
once we stretch it out that far,
then we were able to change the Background
to blue and the FontSize to 54.
So conceptually it's easy,
it's very easy.
It allows you to get creative
with how you want to make changes to your application
using this tool.
And that's really all there is to the notion of
what we were calling in the video
an AdaptiveTrigger.
Here's an AdaptiveTrigger object,
we set the Trigger and then once that Trigger is
fired off, we apply the Setters.
Ok great.
Now I wanted to show you
that there's actually a tool that will help you do this.
Now I don't like this tool, honestly,
I'm being completely honest with you,
I would prefer to do it by hand,
I feel like I have more control.
But if you're a more visual type person
and you don't remember the syntax
and you don't want to look up on your cheat sheet,
as we'll add this to our cheat sheet in a little bit,
you can use this trick.
In your project, in the Solution Explorer,
you can see here I have
a New Project called UsingBlendForVisualStates,
and I have the same color Grid and TextBlock,
but I haven't added anything else to it just yet.
Here in the Solution Explorer I'm going to right-click
on the project and select Design in Blend.
And so Blend is a tool that should be installed
along with Visual Studio.
And it really was intended for
more design work, and by design I mean
aesthetic design work.
And you see that it has many of the same
features of VisualStudio.
On the right-hand side we have the properties window.
There is also a Solution Explorer docked by default
over here on the left.
There are two things that Blend does for you
that you can't easily do
in Visual Studio.
And one of them, is it gives you this cool little
way of creating VisualStates and
recording the changes in a given State.
And then secondly, working with animation,
which we're not going to talk about in this series.
But let me show you how this works,
in fact it's just easier if I go straight
to the design view for this.
And let's go down to where we can actually see
our design area.
So there's this Objects and Timeline window,
typically docked on the left-hand side.
And you can see that I can drill down and see
the ColorGrid and whatever's inside the ColorGrid,
in this case, the MessageTextBlock.
And then I'm going to go to the States tab here
that's usually docked up on the upper left-hand corner.
And what I'll do is, I'm going to add a state group,
so I'm going to click this little button here.
And this will create a VisualStateGroup.
I'm going to add a state to that group
and I'm going to call this state Phone,
we can call it anything we want.
I'm going to add another state
that I'm going to call Tablet.
And I'm going to add another state that I call Desktop.
And notice that whenever I select any of these,
that a little red light
is selected on the left-hand side,
and there's a red border all around the designer area.
You might also see that Phone state recording is on.
Now I select Tablet and Tablet state recording is on
So essentially what you're doing here is,
you're recording the changes in the property window
that you want to be made
when you're in that given state.
Now there's something else that we need to do
before we actually continue on with this.
And that is, we need to set the Triggers.
So as you can see here,
there's a little lightning bolt
off to the right-hand side
I'm going to click Edit Adaptive Triggers,
and I'm going to add an AdaptiveTrigger,
and set in this case the MinWindowWidth to zero,
and click OK.
And then for Tablet,
I'm going to set it's MinWindowWidth I think to 600,
again these are arbitrary numbers,
you would want to test this for your own application,
there are no standards that I'm aware of,
at certain break points you should be using
this versus that, I think this is something you get
to determine on your own as the developer.
So the MinWindowWidth 600, that will trigger
the Tablet state, and then finally the Desktop,
we'll set it's minimum to 800.
So here.
800 great.
Now, whenever in Desktop mode,
what we want to do, I'm going to select the MessageTextBlock
here in the Objects and Timeline window.
And then I'm going to change the font
to oh let's say 54, I forget what we chose originally.
And then I'm going to go to the Tablet,
and then I'm going to change the TextBlock
to let's say 36.
And then I'm going to go to the Phone
and change it to like 16.
And so now, let me go ahead
save what I have,
and then I'm going to run the application.
And you can see
that I was able to make those changes
using this tool.
Now again, I would prefer to just type it in myself.
It does create nice clean XAML, but there are some cases
like working with colors, and brushes,
I didn't like the XAML that it outputted.
That's me just being a little snobby here.
But otherwise you can use this tool to help you
generate these sorts of things.
Now when you close down Blend,
you're going to come back into VisualStudio,
it says hey, any windows that you had open,
they changed out from under VisualStudio.
Do you want to reload this?
Yes, I want to reload it and now you can see
All of the visual States
and the Triggers and the Setters
are all updated here in VisualStudio.
So again, a very simple concept, very powerful
in how we can go about using this
to style up our applications based on the
form factor and screen resolution.
And again, foundational concept for building real
Universal Windows Platform applications.
And so we're going to use this now
in the next lesson to actually
create a more realistic app,
and utilize these concepts to change out the layout
based on the available screen resolution.
Alright so stay tuned to exciting part two of this
in the very next lesson, thanks.