So for the most part our application
is feature complete.
We need to address some layout issues
and make it look a little nicer
and then I'll hand it over to you
and you can run with it and add
more functionality to it.
But what I want to do before we get to that point
is add one more cool feature.
And I want to show you how to add Live Tiles
to your application, so tiles that will update
based on content from your application.
And we're going to go through two scenarios.
First of all, we're going to change the content
of the tile on demand, which means
my program is going to actively push
data into that tile.
And then secondly, we're going to
schedule periodic notification and give it
some source online to pull data from
to present to the user.
There's a lot to this and I'm only
going to show you like one easy scenario
through this content, but hopefully
once you have that and once you kind of
know where to look in the documentation,
you can really branch out from there
and add some rich functionality to the start,
to the start menu for the phone
and the start for the desktop.
Okay, so as you can see here in the lower
left hand corner of my screen,
I have a new application I built
called TileUpdateManagerExample,
another, what I call, "scratchpad application".
This was used for me to learn this technique
and these APIs and now that I understand them,
I'm not going to apply them to my main application.
So there's actually two features of this application
as I run it.
The first scenario that I'm going to demonstrate
is how to actively push new content
into a Live Tile programmatically,
but this will be, I will have to force it
programmatically through code
where as the other I'm going to
schedule notification and just say
hey, every half hour go out and
you'll find the data you'll need
way out here on this web service
and we're going to build a web service
that demonstrates that, okay?
So now that I have the application up and running,
what I want to do is actually go to
all programs to find this in the list of apps.
And once I do, I'm going to right click and select
pin to start and now I have the icon,
the Live Tile with the default icon
for this project type on my start screen.
Okay, so now what I'm going to do
is just type in something like
hello world, real simple and click
change tile content.
The next time I go to the start page,
watch that icon, it flips and it has the content there
that I just added, very cool.
How about if I do this again, hello periodic updates,
so we'll just type in hello periodic
because there's not a lot of room on that tile.
And then go here and it's going to flip one more time
and it changes to hello periodic, okay.
So let's talk about how I was able
to programmatically force the message to change.
This is going to uncover a few important concepts
before we move on to the more advanced scenario.
So we have a  TileUpdateManager Class,
it's part of system, or I'm sorry,
windows.ui.notificationsnamespace,
so you'll need to add that in your using statement,
at the top of the file.
And then the first thing we're going to do
is get a template, get the content of a template
and there a number of innumerations
in this tile template type en-um
and you can just see I can just scroll through all of them,
just a bunch of them and you find
a laundry list of them at this URL
that I have on screen right now.
So I'm actually going to open up that page
to, okay here we go, let's get back there,
the tile template catalog and so now
if I look through this page, you can see
that there is innumeration, in this case
tile square 150-by-150 image and
how it's going to look in both
the Windows desktop and the Windows phone
for the start menus for each of those.
And for the most part, they''re going to
seem very similar, there might be
some small layout changes to
accommodate the rest of the, how the menus
typically layout that content, okay.
And again, there's just a bunch of these.
Now once you find one that kind of works
for your scenario, let's say this one right here,
tile square 150-by-150 text 4.
I'm going to click on that and it's
going to take me down deeper into the page
for a more descriptive,
descriptive explanation
of what the tile template does
and how you can modify its content.
Alright, and so you can see that this
particular content will wrap your content.
So you could give a real long line of text
and it's just going to wrap it.
There are others that will give you,
like in this case, four independent fields of information
that you can fill in.
So there are some subtle differences
between each of the templates,
but hopefully you, you can see
where you can find that information.
Here's the XML that we would actually
be working with and let's go ahead
and take a look at what the tile square
150-by-150 text 01, see what it looks like here.
So I'm going to go back up to the top,
I hit control 5 on my keyboard,
paste that in and you can find, okay,
so this is the one that we're working with.
So I click on it and you can see
that here is the, here is the template
that we're working with.
Actually this is the template that we're working with.
Okay, and so just keep that XML in mind
because what we're going to do next
is manipulate that XML in the next two lines of code.
We're going to find an element
with the name text and we're going to
add a child to that first element
with whatever I typed into that TextBlock.
Alright, so we're going to create a text node
in our template and then append it as a child to the text.
So if we take a look at the template again,
we're going to find the first occurrence
of the text element and we're going to
add a child to that element.
And we're going to fill in this text right here
with whatever we typed in.
And then after we've done that,
then we're going to add that new XML
to a new tile notification object
and tell the  TileUpdateMananager
to go update our application's tile
with this new tile that we've basically
borrowed a template and modified its values.
Okay, so that's the basic course of events here
in five lines of code.
Very simple but what we want to do next
is actually another step forward with this idea
and here what I'm doing in the next,
in the next button click event
is to tell the TileUpdateManager
that instead of me giving you explicitly
the data that I want you to force into that tile,
I'm going to say hey, why don't you just update it
every half hour with this URL that I'm going to give you.
So now we need to go out, we need to create
a web service that will return
something like this, some XML like this
every time that its called.
So I have another project, it is an
ASP.NET MVC 5 application.
It has a single Controller, the HomeController
just returns a single View.
So let's open up the index.cshtml
and inside here all that it does
is just takes whatever the current time is
and .ToString()s it and will display to the end user.
So you can see we're using a different template,
the TileSquare150by150Text04.
Basically I went out to this template catalog,
I grabbed the actual XML that is
necessary for text 04, so this one right here.
And I said hey, let's, right here,
I'm going to replace this and just use this
and put, and put the current date time here.
So now that I've created this and
I've deployed it out to Azure, so here's
what we going to do.
I'm going to drag this over and I'm
going to right click and say whoops,
you can't see it, but it's off screen,
but I'm going to choose the Publish option
and I'm actually going to publish this out
to my Azure account.
Okay, and if I click on this, or here,
let me just actually open up another window over here,
so let me open it up.
It will display this, so I'm at periodic.azurewebsites.net,
this may not be available at the time
when you watch this video, it might take this down
because it costs me money every time somebody gets it.
And let's view the source for this,
and could see that I get that template
and inside of the text element
is the date and the time, okay.
So that's a pretty cool tactic.
Let's go ahead and get rid of that.
Now that we've built our notification service,
let's go ahead and pop open TileUpdateManager
and here we're basically saying here's the tile content,
here's the requested interval.
I would prefer if you update every half hour.
You're going to notice that it does not
happen exactly at 30 minutes.
If we were to pause the video and come
back to this in 32 minutes, 35, 37 minutes,
it would probably update in that, roughly,
in that period of time.
So this requested interval,
now we're going to say hey, TileUpdateManager,
why don't we update the tile 4 application
with a periodic update.
Now to learn more about periodic updates,
take a look at this URL and this will explain
a little bit more about how -- whoops, whoops, whoops,
this will explain how periodic updates work.
And the polling sequence and what's going on
behind the scene, so I would recommend
for more information, read that page
bit.do/periodic
And here we're just going to give it the URI
and how often we want it to update.
And it should go off and update itself.
So now let's run the application again
and see this working.
And I go ahead and click "scheduled notification".
And nothing happens, that's good, that's fine.
Now let's open up the Start menu
and with any luck, this will update itself
and it does, and you can see that the current
date and time is listed there, okay, very nice.
Okay, so what we're going to do is take these ideas
and apply them to our application.
So I'm going to shut everything else down
that we don't need and we're going to come back
to UWPWeather, I'll shut that down too.
And what I think we'll do is every time
that we go off and grab the weather,
we'll go off and we'll say hey,
for the current position where the user is at
let's go ahead and schedule an update
using the last known position of the device.
So we're not going to update it wherever you are.
So if you're like on a long road trip
and you only look at your phone or the weather app
once every 10 hours then it may not be accurate.
But if you were to pop open the weather app
then it will change the URL that we're going to point to.
Hopefully that makes sense.
Okay, but there are, there would be ways
to modify this and make it work in that scenario
and I'm just being a little bit lazy here
and I want to show you the simple, a simple case.
Okay, so to get started what we're going to need to do
is actually create a new project.
So let me go over here to Visual Studio,
pop open a new version and I'm going to create
an ASP.NET application and we'll call this
UWPWeatherService
UWPWeatherService, maybe?
And I'm going to grab that name
because I'm going to want that in just a moment,
then you click OK.
Alright, and here I want to use
an empty, and I'm using the old version
by the time you watch this video,
ASP.NET 5 might be out, but I'm going to use,
it doesn't really matter.
That's not really the focal point
of this series of lessons.
But I'm going to use the empty template,
but Add Core References to MVC
and I'm going to make sure that
we're going to host in the cloud as a web app.
And now it's going to want me to log in,
I'm going to use one of my accounts
and it wants me to re-enter my credentials.
Alright, looks like we're ready to go,
I'm going to name this the same thing that I named
the Visual Studio project, so we'll be able
to get to this at http://uwpweatherservice.azurewebsites.net
http://uwpweatherservice.azurewebsites.net
I'm going to select one of my plans
and I'm going to select one of my app service plans.
The resource group region will be
set for my automatically by the service
plan I select and then I'm not going to
select a database and we're going to
go ahead and create it.
This should set up the published credentials
for the project as well as the
project template itself for MVC application.
Now even if you don't know ASP.NET MVC
this is going to be a really simple process here,
so don't feel intimidated, just follow along
and you'll get the idea how to do this.
Right now it's going out too as you're reserving
that name, setting up the account,
so you can see that's where this
overall status bar is, alright great.
So now we're ready out online and locally,
so we're ready to get going.
First thing I want to do is Add a Controller,
so I'm going to right click and select
add a controller and this will be
an Empty MVC5 Controller called HomeController.
And honestly there's, to begin with
we're not going to do anything with this,
we're just going to leave it alone.
We'll come back to it in just a moment,
but I am going to add a view for this controller
at, unfortunately here,
let me see if I can, there we go,
there we go, Add View.
And I'm going to make sure to not make this
a partial view and I do not want a layout page.
I just want it Empty Without Model template
with a view need of index and click Add.
Okay, now what I'm going to do
is rip out everything in the index.cshtml page
and what I want to do is actually
I want to come back over here to my template catalog.
And I want to find
the template 01 right here.
Okay, so this is what I'm going to grab
from the very first, maybe not the first,
but it's the TileSquare150by150Text01 template
and so I've copied that and I'm going to paste it here.
And what I want to do is actually replace
all of this stuff and I'm going to replace it
a couple different ways in MVC to do this. 并且用几种不同的MVC方法来替换
There's the right way and there's 有一种更正统的方法
the cheap and easy way, and I'm going也有更廉价的方法
to use the cheap and easy way, okay.我要用到的就是这个乞丐版了
So I'm going to create a couple of ViewBag 接着我要创建几个ViewBag
values and just pass data from the controller然后利用这几个ViewBag将控件中的数据
into the view using the ViewBag.传送到view中去
If you wanted this to be a real app, 如果你想将这个变成一个实际的程序
I would recommend creating a "view model", 我推荐你创建一个View model
but we're not going to go through 不过现在我们不会详细讲这部分
all that right now.
ViewBag.Name, whoops,
so the first thing we'll display is the temperature,首先第一个需要显示的就是温度
then we'll display the description of what's going on. 然后是对于当前情况的描述
So is it light mist, is it sunny, you know, 比如有轻雾，晴天等等
that sort of thing.就是这类的
And then the name, so that'll be
the area or the town that you're currently in 然后是当前位置的名称
and then finally we'll just show the 最后则是当前日期时间
DateTime.Now.ToShortTimeString
so we can see when it last updated. 这样就能看到最后一次更新的时间了
Great, then inside of the HomeController, 在HomeController的里面
what I need to do is populate those values. 我需要做的是赋值
And so what we're going to do here然后需要做的就是
is, like for example, ViewBag.Name equals, and then whatever, okay, 添加比如ViewBag.Name
and we're going to grab that data 然后我们要将从
as it's passed in through the querystring. querystring里传送过来的数据
So in MVC, I can just add two input 所以在MVC中，我可以只添加两个querystring类别的
parameters with the names of the querystring parameters输入参数
that I expect and then it will 然后接着
parse that out of the querystring,它会将参数进行分析
and pass them into the input parameter然后通过Index action result的方法
for the Index action result method.将它们导入输入参数中
So here we go, string lat, string lon for longitude
and I'm going to need to do some validation
or some trimming of the latitude / longitude,
I know that to be a fact from future
or from previous, previous attempts of doing this.
Sometimes the phone's GPS will pass in
just this really, really long value
after the decimal point and we need to trim that down
in order to get this to work.
But once we have those values, latitude / longitude,
what we need to do is actually then run them
by the openweathermap.org web service
and we're just going to call it from the web app
as opposed to the individual phone,
each individual device or desktop
that it's running on.
So what I want to do is add a new class here
and I'm going to call this OpenWeatherMapProxy
and you can probably guess where
I'm going to go with this.
It'll be identical to what we created
in our example version.
In fact what I'm going to do is come down here
to the OpenWeatherMapProxy,
I'm going to pretty much copy everything here.
Inside of that class or those classes inside
of that file and I'm going to come back
over here and I think I could just
re-use everything like that.
I'm going to have to add a few namespaces,
in fact I know that I'm going to have to add,
here let's go to Tools, Nuget Package Manager,
Manage Nuget Packages for the Solution,
I know I'm going to need HTTPClient.
So let's add that one.
Yes, I accept and I also know that I'm
going to have to add a reference for
the JSON, whatever that was again,
the DataContractJSONSerializer.
So I think I know where that's at,
let's go and right click on references
and click add reference and
then "serialize", "serialize", yes.
And that should be in the System.Runtime.Serialization
namespace, so we're going to add a reference
to that assembly.
And I also know that we're going to need
to add a using statement for System.Threading.Tasks.
So let me add all my using statements here,
just a lot of set up work here
just to get this going in the right direction.
Yes, yes, yes, it's all coming together now.
And I think this is System.IO, let's see,
that should take care of that.
And let Intellisense catch up, here's some coding,
where did that come from?
System.Text okay, that's fine.
And then this comes from yeah,
System.Runtime.Serialization.
Alright, we should be in good shape now.
Awesome, let's, I just want to build this real quick
just to see if we can build it or
if there's any errors so far.
Okay, great, now assuming that this is correct,
yeah, that should work there,
HomeController, here's what I want to do.
Let's set latitude equal to latitude.
I want to trim off or just want to make sure
that this is no larger than yeah,
I use the Substring, the second overload,
I'll say hey, you can have five digits of precision total
and that should suffice, we could up that
to six I think without a problem.
And this will just ensure that
the latitude and the longitude
are just not like these massively long numbers.
Okay, with values after the decimal point.
Alright, so once we have that,
we can call out to our open
I think it's Models.OpenWeatherMapProxy.GetWeather
and then we can pass in the latitude and the longitude.
And I guess I need to take these strings
and make them into doubles as well.
Well we'll do this, Double.Parse,
so I really need to test this a little bit more
and make sure that all this is correct.
We'll call this var
latitude
and var longitude.
Kind of doing this off script and
off the top of my head here,
so hopefully this will work.
Then we'll pass those values in, okay.
Alright, now what does this return to us again?
It's going to be awaitable, it's going to
return to us a rootObject, so var weather equals await
... alright, and remember the formula
if we have something that's awaitable
what we need to do is mark the method
as async and then what it's going to return
will be a promise in the future to return
a task of type ActionResult.
So that should work there.
And we're probably missing a System.Threading.Task
using statement and now we're good to go.
Okay, very good, alright.
All of that to do this, let's
grab off the various parts that we get back from weather.
So weather.name that's easy enough,
ViewBag.Temp should equal
weather.main.temp
and we want to make that,
it's going to give us something that's
going to have values after the decimal,
so we want to cast that to an integer
and then ToString() the whole thing.
And then next one, we go ViewBag.Description
and we go weather, dot, and if you remember
what we had to do here, there are many different weathers
that come back, so we're going to grab the first item
and then grab its description and then finally
let's grab, oh, we already know
that the last one will be the date and the time.
So that's all we should have to do right there.
Let's build this and make sure this actually works.
Okay, great, now I want to run it locally
just to make sure that it's going to work.
And you can see that I get an error,
but the error is because I did not supply
a latitude and longitude, so let's go lat equals 32.
and I'll just type in a bunch of numbers
after the decimal and longitude equals
a -96. and then I'll just type in a bunch of numbers
like that and see what happens.
Alright, some place called "Seven Points",
I have no idea where that is, but the sky
is clear there and it's 71 degrees at 10 AM, okay.
Perfect, perfect.
Okay, so we know that works,
so what I'm going to do, stop it,
and I'm going to deploy it.
So I'm going to right click and select Publish,
which you cannot see off to the
upper right hand corner of the screen.
I want to validate the connection.
It filled in these details when we set up the project
originally a few moments ago and then
we can walk through all this,
but there's really nothing there that demands our attention.
Let's just go ahead and publish this out.
The key is to remember that it's called
uwpweatherservice.azurewebsites.net
So let me grab that real quick.
Copy that, now what we're going to do
is save that, minimize it, and then
let's open up UWPWeather and here what I want to do
in the MainPage.xaml is schedule
the update.
So let's set the var uri equal to
that URL with the latitude
and a longitude
and we'll want to go String.Format that
with whatever we pull back from here.
So actually let me to do this,
what is this, should be Doubles, right?
So, equals,
and we'll grab this.
And then we'll grab that.
Okay then we'll just go lat and long here.
Great.
Next up, I'm going to pull whatever we did
from my TileUpdateManager example
because pretty much the rest of it
is boiler plate honestly it's just going to be
a code I can grab right off
here.
So grab all of that.
Close that down, open this back up, pop that in there,
and then we're going to get this uri
and everything else should work.
Alright, now I'm going to, let's build this,
make sure it does work or build at least.
Okay, great, now let's, let's cross our fingers
and run the app, see what happens.
Now before we get too far,
let's find our weather app.
UWPWeather, should be under U, there we go.
Right click that, pin that to Start.
Okay, so all we get is a little box right now,
that's fine, let's go ahead and click
get weather, I get the notification
"Are you sure you want it to allow
"it to access location?", yes.
And the reason is because uninstalled it.
Okay, so the good news here is that
I get that it's 69 degrees, sky is clear out in Plano.
Now the real key here is
will this update?
And I would've expected it to update by now,
so what I'm going to do is actually debug this real quick.
I want to see the URL that's being created.
Oh you know what, the problem is not in the weather service
as I'm thinking through this, the problem is right there
is that URL ... well that's an easy fix.
Don't have to republish or anything, let's run it now.
Now let's do that.
Here I am going to just go ahead
and step over it and grab the uri
just to make sure that I can test this right.
So copy that, and then let's continue on.
Alright so we get that, now let's go over here to our tile
and with any luck it'll flip, come one flip, yes!
Sweet.
Now the interesting thing is that it says
that we're in Sasche as opposed to Plano,
which are just neighboring towns,
but I must be on the border or something along those lines.
So that's an oddity, but whatever.
I'm happy we got this far, okay.
So probably should have some, wrap some
exception handling around that,
but I'm pretty happy with it,
now we're just going to finish up
with some finishing touches
and then we'll move on to the next,
to the next challenge or the next app
that we'll build together.
So I'm pretty excited about this.
Let's finish it up, thank you.