Hi, I'm Bob Tabor with www.learnvisualstudio.net
www.learnvisualstudio.net
We're not done with Layout quite yet.
Next we're going to talk about new Layout controls
that were introduced with the Universal
Windows Platform API.
Now you might wonder why are there new Layout controls?
What has changed from previous APIs that we used
to build apps for the Windows 8.1 store
and the Windows Phone 8.1 store.
Well there's two reasons why we need
new Layout controls.
First of all, to help us build apps
that look like they belong in Windows 10.
We'll talk about that more in just a moment.
And then secondly to help us build applications
that adapt to different device family and screen sizes
and we'll talk about that in an upcoming lesson.
So as you can see I have loaded up
in my recording area here,
one of the stock applications that come preinstalled
with Windows 10, the Money app.
Now there's also News, Weather, Sports,
and a few others.
But they all kind of share some similar characteristics
that aesthetic and functionality
that really identify themselves
as Windows 10 applications uniquely.
So I wanted to point those out, those features out,
and then I want to show eventually over the course
of the next few lessons how we can duplicate this ourselves
with the built in controls that are now available
in the Universal Windows Platform.
So when I talk about the chrome,
I'm talking about the top area and the leftmost area here
that provides navigation and other services
to your application.
And so this style of navigation, this style of application
is known as "hamburger navigation"
and the hamburger is a term that's used to indicate
that there's an icon with three vertical lines
or horizontal lines stacked vertically
and when you click that button in the upper left-hand corner
it will show a split panel that will display navigation
to the various areas or functionality of your application.
So in this case, we can see that in expanded mode
both an icon and a title for the given area
of our application and we can navigate around
using the expanded view or the compacted view.
When we're in compacted mode, you can only see the icons
on the left, but you can always see the item
that was selected.
It's kind of highlighted in one of the primary accent colors
for the application.
Alright, next up if you look over here
at the very top of the application
you'll see that there's kind of this bar of functionality.
Now this might change over time,
but there are some constants that are in
almost every app like a search bar
in the upper right hand corner.
In this case, we're searching for
the current stock price for a given company.
We can search for it here.
Also then to the left of that, docked over
to the left-hand side is the title of the area
that we're currently in and then to the left of that
a navigation button that allows us to go back
through the navigation history to get back to the homepage.
There's also some other features of these applications
like the card layout, the card-based layout,
where you have all of these little panels of cards
that will dynamically resize themselves
and then depending on the view port,
the size of the window
that has been resized by the user,
they will either shift down, wrap down to the next line
or they will expand and contract, alright.
We'll talk about that later on
and there are controls that will help us achieve
that effect as well.
Alright, so let me shut this down
and the next thing that I want to do
is talk about two Layout controls that'll
help us achieve the effect that we saw there.
The relative panel is the first one
and it's a control, a Layout container
that is useful for creating user interfaces
that don't have a clear linear pattern.
When I say linear pattern what I mean
is that it's for layouts that are not fundamentally
stacked or wrapped like that card layout
or even tabular like in a grid.
So these are layouts that you may not find
as easy to reproduce using a stack panel or a grid.
Now certainly, what we saw in the Windows 10 application
we probably could achieve that using a StackPanel
and grid combination, however, I think you're going to find
that these two new controls will help you achieve
this a little bit more elegantly.
So the relative panel basically defines an area
where you position and align child objects,
so other controls either in relation to each other
or in relation to the parent panel itself.
And there's three basic categories of attach properties
that allow you to position the controls inside of the panel.
There are panel alignment relationships
so these are attached properties like align top
of my control with the panel.
So align top with panel, align the left with panel
and so on.
Then there are sibling alignment relationships.
So align top with and then you give the name of the control
that you want to be aligned top with.
There's another control here and you say
I want my top to be aligned with the same top
as this sibling.
And then there's sibling positional relationships,
the third type of attached property
and so this is, I want to be above my sibling,
I want to be below my sibling,
I want to be to the right and the left of my sibling, okay.
So what you see here, I've got the beginnings
of an application and you can pause the video
and catch up with me.
It's just called relative panel example
and what I'm going to do is add in some code here
to really exercise the relative panel.
So the first thing I'm going to do
is get some row definitions here so we can do
some interesting things.
And what I want to do is put a RelativePanel
in the first row, or actually the second row,
Grid.Row="1", alright.
And also I'm going to set a minimum height,
so no matter what I never want the height
of this RelativePanel to be less than 300 pixels.
I'm going to start adding a number of rectangles.
In fact, I'm going to add this first rectangle.
So it's going to be a red rectangle,
but notice I've set the relative panel dot
aligned right with panel equal true.
Let me bring this down a little bit
so you can kind of see this in effect.
So here again, we've got three rows.
One row, two rows, three rows in our grid
and in the middle row I have my RelativePanel
and I said for this rectangle I wanted the right side
to be aligned with the panel so I set that
attached property equal to true and you can see now
that red box aligns itself to the right hand side.
We can then do something in relation to that sibling
adding another rectangle, a blue rectangle
that says, "Hey I want to be to the left of that red rectangle"
and you can see that no matter what,
even as we resize this application,
let's run the app.
Alright, even as we resize the application,
the blue rectangle will always be to the left
of the red rectangle.
See that?
And the red rectangle will always be aligned
to the right-hand side.
Very neat.
Alright, next up what I want to do
is show that we can also set multiple
attached properties.
Here I'm going to paste in a green rectangle
and I've set the AlignVerticalCenterWith
AlignVerticalCenterWith="RedRectangle".
So now the center of the red rectangle
and the center of the green rectangle will be the same.
Furthermore, I want to align the horizontal center
with the panel.
So show me where the center is of the
horizontal size of the app and I want to be right there
in the middle.
So now let's see what effect that achieves.
We'll see how running the app with different
screen sizes or by resizing the app
we're always going to have that green rectangle
with its center aligned vertically to the red rectangle
and its horizontal alignment centered to the center
of the application, cool.
And just to kind of speed up this process
I'm going to paste in two more here at the same time
a yellow and a purple rectangle to look
at the properties there.
So let's view
the yellow rectangle.
You can see that we set
the minimum width to 50
and the minimum height to 50.
And why this is important is because
we want to align the bottom of our rectangle
with the bottom of the panel
and we want to align the top with the purple rectangle.
And so the purple rectangle is above it
and it's defined here where we wanted
to be positioned below the red rectangle,
we wanted the right of it aligned with the
right of the red rectangle, and we want the left
aligned with the green rectangle.
So now we're going to, as we reposition
the actual size of the control will change.
So let's go ahead and run it.
In both these cases you'll see
that by resizing, we will get
a larger width or height,
a larger rectangle.
Okay, you see that how the yellow rectangle grows
and how the purple rectangle grows?
So this is why you can do some interesting positional things
with the relative panel because you can set things relative
to other controls or relative to the panel itself
and things can automatically resize themselves.
Alright, so what to all this?
Why is this important?
Well, the reason is because, and let me just save this,
and let's take a look at another project
that I currently have open and this will be
the search bar.
So RelativePanelSearchBar.
You can load it up.
It's available wherever you downloaded the code
or the video for this lesson.
And we see the beginnings
of a Windows 10 application
where we have a search bar over here on the right-hand side
and we've got to clean it up some.
It doesn't look finished yet, but you can see how
no matter what, over on the left-hand side,
or on the right-hand side rather,
we have it always docked to the right
and we have the title to the left.
Furthermore, I wanted to show that
we can create a little status bar
that's always docked to the bottom here.
Furthermore, depending on the information,
it's either aligned to the left, aligned to the right,
or aligned center.
So let's see how we achieve this effect in our XAML.
Let's open up our MainPage.xaml
and then get rid of this output window.
Alright, so we have three rows.
The top and the bottom rows are Auto
so just take up enough room, just what you need,
and then the middle area will be star sizing
and so we didn't do anything in there.
So the first item that we created was a RelativePanel
that sat in that top row and you can see that we have
that Button and that TextBox, the SearchButton
will be aligned right with the panel,
so it's on the rightmost side and then
we say to the SearchTextBox,
align yourself with the left of that SearchButton
so that you'll always be to the left of that SearchButton
no matter what.
And we do the same thing with the text itself
that's next to it that has the word search.
It's just a TextBlock and it has it's left
positioned to the left of the SearchTextBox.
Then you can see that the other TextBlock
is just aligned to the left-hand side
because we didn't tell it relative of anything,
it just defaults to the upper left-hand corner.
Alright next up, you can see that we have
at the very bottom here that status bar
and I used an object called a Border
and a Border just creates a little layout control
that provides us the ability to style the background color
and the stroke around the background color.
So we're just putting our RelativePanel
inside of this Border and the Border, all it does
is going to give us some color
and then we're going to do our work
inside of the StackPanel itself.
And so there's three sections to that RelativePanel.
The RelativePanel on the left-hand side
will just contain the number of items
like maybe items that need to be addressed
and so it uses all the positional attached properties
that you would expect AlignLeftWithPanel
and then the next item, the next TextBlock
align yourself to the right of that first TextBlock.
So that's the left hand side.
The right-hand side works the same way
except to the opposite.
And then the third case, I actually create a StackPanel
because if you were to set one of the
AlignedHorizontalCenterWithPanel,
if you were to set one of the TextBlocks
equal with that setting, then it will be
in the absolute center and anything else
that you need to the left of it or to the right of it
would then be off center and it wouldn't look quite right
so you put them all in a StackPanel and you can make sure
that the StackPanel is centered no matter what
it's width is and then you can put whatever you want
inside of there and know that it's gonna always be centered.
Alright, so the last thing that I would say about
the RelativePanel is that you could potentially
get yourself in a little trouble by creating, you know,
a circular reference.
I want number one to the left of number two,
number three to the left of number two,
number four to the left of number three,
number one to the left of number four, okay.
So obviously, you can set multiple relationships
that target the same edge of the element
and when you do that, you might have
conflicting relationships in your layout as a result.
So whenever this happens, there's actually
an order of events just like whenever you are
working in a math problem or even in code
that parentheses can dictate the order of operation.
There is an order of operation with how
these relationships are deciphered in this order.
So first priority will be panel alignment,
so align me to the left or the right of the panel.
Then the second one will be Sibling Alignment relationship,
so align me with the top of this control,
align me with the left of that control,
and then the third and the lowest priority
would be Sibling Positional relationships.
Set me above this control, below this control,
to the left of this control, okay.
So any rate, we're going to utilize the RelativePanel
several times in the remainder of the series.
It's a valuable tool to elegantly, simply align items
relative of either the panel or other controls on our form
and we'll need that when building Windows 10 apps.
Alright, let's continue on and talk about
the other layout control that's new
to the Universal Windows Platform API.
We'll see you there, thanks.