Okay, so the first thing we're going to do in this
video is actually get that....
the images working for the plan that I came up with
in the previous lesson.
And then we're going to turn our attention to getting
the actual GPS coordinates
for our device.
Whether we're running on desktop, or more likely
scenario running on a phone or a smaller device.
Okay, so to begin with, what I'm going to do is actually
just copy this folder of weather assets, you can see that
I have essentially a copy.
I've used the names, the exact names that they used
on their icon list
and I just have a graphic designer I know create some
cute weather icons,
so that again, they're royalty free.
And now I can use these in my app.
So I'm just going to drag the weather folder up.
Had that same issue we had last time, that pesky issue.
So let's go ahead and select everything,
drag and drop, it's going to say "Hey, it's already there."
Yes, copy it, okay great.
So now all I need to do...
is I need to...
instead of pulling these icons from OpenWeatherMap,
instead what I'll do is just change this URL.
Just get rid of that, and whenever you're going to
access local resources and you need a URI,
you use the prefix "ms-appx:" and then three forward
slashes like so, okay?
So that will say "Hey, look in the Assets folder, look in
"the Weather sub-folder, and look for that...
"three alpha numeric character
"name for the file."
And if I named everything correctly, and I think I did,
then we should see different icons used.
So let's go and run the application again.
And let's go ahead and...
hey, hey, how cool is that?
Alright, so that was the easy part.
Let's move on, and now let's talk about utilizing
the location capability of the device
that we're working with.
So in order to utilize some sensor or some hardware
feature of the platform you're running on,
you have to declare a capability, and you do that in the
Package.appxmanifest.
So let's open it up and let's go to "Capabilities" and say
"I want the location capability."
And you'll notice how this manifests itself the very first
time that we run the application here locally
on my desktop, and then also the first time that we actually
try to run it in a phone emulator, the message
that we'll get.
It will have to be approved by the end user
before we can actually use it.
Now there's a lot to using the features that I'm going to
show you right now.
However, what I recommend...
is that you actually search for this article.
I didn't create a shortcut, but just search for
"Windows 10, Get Current Location."
Alright, you should come to this page in the Windows
Dev Center.
And this will give you code that you can use to check
the current status and whether you're going to be allowed to
actually utilize that capability, and if not it'll report
back that you cannot use it.
So there's a lot of extra code in here that is really
a safety net for your application.
You can also respond on updates, so while the phone,
while you currently have it and you're running,
and you're on the move, you're driving,
you may want the location to be updated
in real time, and in which case you can implement
all this additional code to make that happen.
We're going to take the simplest possible scenario,
and so some of what I'm going to write here in a moment
is just taking from kind of this right here, and ignoring
a lot of the complexity that would be needed
for a more full featured application.
So to make this work, what I'm going to do is actually
add another class called the LocationManager.
And it's going to abstract the way a lot of the complexity
of working with the GPS or the location features
of Windows 10.
So I'm going to call this LocationManager.
And we can set public class, and we're going to go ahead
and create a public static.
Let's call it "void" for the moment, but I know I'm going to
return something in a moment called GetPosition().
Great.
And what I'm going to do is...
Okay, so what we're going to do, let me get rid of the webcam
here so you can see the whole screen, let me move this over,
beause were going to use some heavy duty coding here.
Okay, what we need to work with is something called
the Geolocator, it's going to give us everything we need.
Now unfortunately as you can see, Geolocator's not found.
I'm going to hit Control+"." in order to add a using
statement to Windows.Devices.Geolocation.
Great, and there's a method called RequestAccessAsync.
And what this will just do is say "Hey, can I get access to
"the Geolocator? Will it give me a latitude, a longitude
"if I actually ask for it?"
So it's going to return back to me a status.
So we're going to call this accessStatus.
And we see the async keyword and so I know I'm going to have
to wait the "await" there and I know that I'm going to have to
add the async keyword here.
And I know that I'm going to have to return something here,
currently it's void, we'll come back to that
in just a moment.
Alright, so the only status that I'm really concerned about
is there's a Geolocation status,
GeolocationAccessStatus.Allowed.
If it's denied or unspecified, then that means
we're not going to have any luck.
So, if...
if the accessStatus is not equal to allow,
then I'm going to
throw new Exception. I probably should take more
care here and create a custom Exception
and be able to pass back what the issue is,
but I'm just going to go ahead and croak, just have the
application die.
Again, that's something I need to come back and make
a little more elegant and test that in the future.
But assuming that everything is okay, then we're going to
continue on here.
And I'm going to get
an access to an instance of the Geolocator, so let's just go
var geolocator= new Geolocator.
And I'm going to use
the object initializer syntax to set
the desired accuracy meters.
Just going to set it to zero, meaning "Hey, give me
"what you can."
I could specify and say "Hey, I prefer if it was 1 meter
"accuracy, 10 meters, 100 meters."
But this will just set it to the default value which is
"give me whatever you can give me."
Now that I have all that work done, I'm going to get a position
and I'm going to say geolocator.GetGeopositionAsync().
And then I'm going to return that position.
Now the position object will be of type...
Geoposition.
So there's a Geoposition object, let's go ahead and get
rid of void.
And what I need to do is to return
a Task which is a promise
that in the future, I promise to give you a Geoposition.
It doesn't seem to like that, but I think...
Let's see.
Oh, right.
Doesn't like it because I forgot the await keyword.
There we go, great.
So that should be all we need to do
to get the correct position.
Once we have that position...
So let's go...
Let's go "var position = " and we'll call the
LocationManager.GetPosition().
And I know that this too is await-able.
So we'll hit "await."
And now that we have that we should be able to do
something like this, and the get weather, let's go...
position.Coordinate.Latitude.
And then position.Coordinate.Longitude.
Now it's giving me some green squigglies, let's see
what we got going on here.
Oh it's obsolete, yeah, I ran into this before.
The issue here is that they thought that it might be
unavailable after Windows 8.1, but I was unavailable to find
what they're replacing it with in 10.
I didn't see anything, in fact I found this code,
this very code, in the Windows 10 documentation.
So it might be something they just haven't
gotten to quite yet.
You might have a completely different experience,
just be aware that the direction I'm leading you here,
this could be obsoleted in the future, and you may have to
change that line of code, okay?
But for now, this is what we got.
Alright, so now let's just set a break point here
because I want to see it actually get to the spot.
Now notice when I click the "Get Weather" button, I asked
for access to the location feature of
my local computer,
and it says "do you want it to access your location?"
And I can go to the Settings app if I want to modify it
later, but for now I'm going to say "Yes."
So now that I've given it access, it's going to go ahead
and try to figure out what the position is.
I'm going to hover my mouse over, looks like I'm
32.98, and longitude negative 96, so that looks good.
Now let's go ahead and run it.
Dallas County - 78 - light rain. Very good.
Okay so, we're in good shape there, what I want to do is
stop the video right here, and I want to come back to this
because I want to test this on the phone, and the phone
emulator and change my position around the country, and see
what it would look like if I was running this from Seattle,
or from New York, or from Chicago,
and so I can really test that functionality out and the
phone emulator has a great feature that will allow us
to do that.
We'll look at that in the very next video, okay?
See you there, thanks.