Alright, this is the last of the solution videos
for the Stupendous Styles Challenge.
And now we're going to work on the CompletePage.
I'm going to show you a little something
I failed to talk about during the regular videos,
and you're going to see this at work.
It's a pretty cool feature of Styles.
I kept saying that they're like Cascading Style Sheets.
But I never really demonstrated that notion,
we'll do that now.
Okay, so what I'm going to do is borrow actually from
the DonutPage again.
Let me just grab all of this here.
That's all I need for now.
Paste that in there.
And, what I'll do...now notice here, you know,
if we take a look at what do we got?
Yeah, we're going to use the color logo here, right?
But you'll notice that I copied in the Style
that points to the WhiteLogoStyle.
That's true.
But what if I just override that one attribute
of the Style that was created on the WhiteLogoStyle
that sets the Source equal to the
color logo instead.
Will that work?
Let's see.
Got to make sure I spelled it right first.
Or else it'll be anticlimactic.
Okay, here we go.
Whoa, same size, same spacing, everything's the same
except its color.
So you see I was able to borrow from the Style
but override the things that I needed
to be different about the Style.
And that is how Styles in XAML
are like Cascading Style Sheets, so cool.
Alright, but that's not all we need to do here.
We also need to work with this ticket
and with this Order 96, and all that business, right?
And so, let's go ahead and first of all,
I'm going to add that Image.
Grid.Row="1", in fact, I think I only need
two Rows here.
So, let me get rid of that.
Okay, alright.
Yeah, the first Row is going to be for our logo.
But the second Row, Row 1,
that's where all the magic's going to happen
for the CompletePage.
So, let's set the Source="Assets/ticket.jpg"
Source="Assets/ticket.jpg".
And I'm going to set the Vertical and HorizontalAlignments
equal to "Center".
And we'll see where that takes us.
Now I'm pretty sure this image is going to get
just ginormous, so we're going to have to come back
and address that.
The other thing I want to do, though is add a StackPanel.
And inside that StackPanel we're going
to put two TextBlocks.
And the Text in the first one will be the "Order",
and then the Text in the second one will be that "96".
Again, this is just a mock up, no real functionality here.
I'm going to set the FontSize on the second one
equal to "64".
Pretty big.
And then the FontSize on the first one to "36".
HorizontalAlignment="Center".
And I don't think I'm going to need
to touch the VerticalAlignment
because I'm actually going to do that
here in the StackPanel.
So a Grid, we're also putting this in Grid.Row="1".
Now remember one of the qualities of working
with the Grid Rows is that you can put as many things
as you want in them and they'll be stacked
on top of each other.
And I'm actually counting on that to happen.
So, VerticalAlignment="Center".
HorizontalAlignment="Center".
Alright, so we should be good to go now.
Let's see what we have.
Now I know that the Image is going to be
ridiculously large.
So, I'm going to have to come back and resize that, yeah.
That's ridiculous.
And I don't see my TextBlocks.
What happened?
Alright, so clearly we got some issues here
we got to address.
Let's set, let's put the,
the Width of this thing to "300",
that should help.
Oh, you know what?
I'm a knuclehead, we don't need these Columns.
That's the danger of cut and paste, right?
You get stuff and you forget that you have it in there.
That should fix that issue.
And complete, yeah, it looks,
well, it looks pretty close.
Something not quite right about the centering on this.
But, I think it's good enough for now.
All right, so we're going to go with that.
And that is basically the solution to
the Stupendous Styles Challenge.
I hope you were able to use Styles as much as possible.
If you were able to use them more than I was,
then you get bonus points for that, that's aweome.
And hopefully you saw the value
of the Styles here and there.
And you got to play around with some logic.
You got to work with Layout.
Some of the things we did previously,
you get to strengthen those muscles
like working with a Frame and navigating around, okay?
So, let's move on.
Now we're going to get to the more complicated,
interesting stuff.
This is when things start to get fun.
So wake up, and let's get going.
See you in the next lesson.
Thanks.