Ok, so the next task is to create
User Control and use that as the DataTemplate
so we'll rip out
everything that we did here and actually,
in the process we'll fix it and make it look better.
So to get started here,
let's go ahead and select the Project
and then go over to the Project Menu
and select Add New Item and we wanna choose
a User Control and we're going to call this
the news item control, you can call it anything you want.
NewsItemControl.
Good, good.
All right and inside of the NewsItemControl,
for the most part, I'm just going to grab everything out
that I did here.
So the Grid, Control+"X" and
paste it over the Grid in the NewsItemControl.xaml.
So that's one of the first steps that we'll need to take.
The next thing that we'll need to do is
to reference that Control so let's go ahead
and I think what we do here is just
local NewsItemControl, right?
Then I think what we're going to have to do
in order to continue to use the x:Bind
is we have to make some changes to this.
So first of all, let me go to the Code Behind
for the NewsItemControl.
You remember, there were two things
that we needed to do here.
First of all, we need to
do something like this, public Model.NewsItem
Model.NewsItem NewsItem.
And let's do a getter on this, right?
So, get
and we'll return this.DataContext
as Model.NewsItem.
And that was all very templated, you could
pull that directly from the cheat sheet.
Then, we just needed to handle the
DataContextChanged Event.
And we'll do this little lambda here.
And tell the bindings
that we have inside of our XAML to update themselves
whenever the DataContext changes.
So then back here in NewsItemControl,
what we'll need to do is to
set the x:Bind to NewsItem.Image
and NewsItem.Headline
NewsItem.Headline and ".Subhead" and ".DateLine".
Great.
And also while we're here, I'm going to go ahead
and fix the alignment issues.
So in this Headline TextBlock, I'm going to go
RelativePanel.AlignTopWithPanel.
There we go, equals "True".
And I'm going to make the FontSize a little bit larger.
At least initially.
And we'll turn on TextWrapping.
I don't think I told you to do this but
we're going to need that.
Let me go ahead and put all this on separate lines
so you can easily see it here inside the viewable area.
So the next item, the Subhead, we'll set it
as the RelativePanel.Below
the Headline TextBox.
Oh, I didn't give this a name.
So let's give that the name
HeadlineTextBox.
So, we should be able to do this now.
Great
I'm going to set its TextWrapping
as well to "Wrap".
And then finally, this bottom DateLine,
I'm going to put that Aligned with the bottom
so RelativePanelAlignBottomWithPanel
RelativePanelAlignBottomWithPanel="True".
Let's set the FontSize, something kind of small here,
to like 10.
And that should be all we need to do there.
So at least that should space things out nicely.
Let's see if this works.
If I've forgotten a step in this process.
I forgot something.
Oh, yeah.
So I forgot a end of line statement.
This is kind of an odd line of code to write.
It's all on one line, we're used to
seeing things on different lines.
I'll forgive myself if you do. (laughs very softly)
Hey hey, it works.
And just out of curiosity, I'm going to do something here.
Let me resize this window, it's a little ungainly.
Alright and we get the scroll bar so that's good.
Awesome.
You know what, I think we need is the
BackgroundColor for this to be the light gray.
So let me go to this...
To the MainPage.xaml and here in the GridView,
and let's set the Background="LightGray".
And let's see what that looks like.
It definitely has some padding issues in this guy,
inside of each of these items so let's go ahead
and add some padding.
We're on that RelativePanel in particular.
So in NewsItemControl, find the RelativePanel.
Here, I'm going to set the Margin
and I'll set a "10" on all sides.
That should work.
That's a little bit better.
I like where we're going with this.
So I think that's all we really needed to do
for this lesson.
We created the User Control, used it as DataTemplate,
styled it up a little bit better and it's looking great.
There's, I think, only one step left and that is to
add in the StateManagement
for the different State Triggers, Adapative Triggers.
So let's tackle that in the last of the solution videos
and see you in the next video, thanks.