In this lesson, we're going to learn a little bit more
about how to use some of the features of the
phone emulator in order to uncover a
issue with our short-term memory. (laughs)
The programmer's short-term memory, not the device.
And so, let's go ahead and if you haven't already done this,
change from running it on the local machine to one of
the mobile emulators and I'm going to go ahead and hit run.
And then I'll show you one of the
cool features of the emulator that I briefly touched on
at the very outset of this series of lessons,
but didn't really elaborate on at the time.
So what we want to do is test our app to see if it's grabbing
coordinates correctly, geo coordinates,
from different places in the world,
and so one of the things that we can do is actually
click the double chevron to open up the Tools pane
for the emulator and go to the location tab.
And here what I can do is search on a map,
you know, either search for cities or places
or I can zoom in, zoom out, and find somewhere on the map
and say, I am physically located here.
Now I'm sitting in Dallas, but I'm putting my little marker
there in Redmond, and now that will tell the emulator
whenever it uses the location services for the emulator,
or for the phone, serve up Redmond,
the location that I have pinned right there.
So let's go ahead and click the get weather button,
and it gives us that familiar little
little message, "Are you sure you want to allow
"this application to access location?"
I'm going to go ahead and click yes.
Now, when I do this, we're going to,
you know, be a little confused here.
I have my position set to Redmond, however,
this is still delivering back Dallas County.
Now I could say to myself, "Hmm, there must be a problem
"with what I've done here in the location
"window of the emulator or maybe I did
"something incorrectly in code."
And in this case, the latter would be true,
but this would help us to uncover issues.
And the issue is this, if we take a look at this,
the OpenWeatherMapProxy.cs, you can see that we hardcoded
the latitude and longitude and
we never ever swapped that out.
So what we should do here is actually
var url equals and then I'll do
a String.Format around that
and then pass in the lat and longitude that we grabbed from
from input parameters for the GetWeather method.
Let me grab all of this out right here
and paste that in there and we will substitute in
latitude and longitude.
So, it frequently, I see people go online and say,
"Hey, Microsoft's stuff is broken. It doesn't work."
And many times I've done that
and when I was just getting started,
I thought that they were the problem,
but the longer I do this, the more I realize
it's me that's the problem, that I've forgotten something.
And so, that humility has led to,
has prevented me from a lot
of embarrassing situations. (laughs)
Alright, so be humble when you're a software developer
because it's probably going to come back
and bite you at some point.
Okay, here we go.
Now that I've fixed that,
and let's open up the tools pane and location
and looks like it forgot my, where I was at previously here
so let's go ahead and make sure we put
our pin right on Redmond and then click get weather.
Allow permissions and here we go.
We get Redmond, it's 56 degrees and there's a light mist.
Very nice.
Alright, so that's how we could use the emulator's tools
to further test our application
to uncover bugs that we may not find,
especially whenever there's a sensor
on the device that we're utilizing.
And there are other sensors that
we can mimic in a similar sort of way.
We're just not utilizing those in this series of lessons.
Alright, so let's continue on in the next lesson
as we continue to build this app.
See you there, thanks.