Hi, I'm Bob Tabor with www.learnvisualstudio.net.
In this lesson we're going to talk about a couple of things.
Start with data binding, but then we'll talk about
two Controls that'll allow us to bind data
in a grid-like fashion or in a list-like fashion.
Let's start with data binding.
It's been around ever since I started building software
on the Windows platform way back in '93.
Data binding a process of taking some data
and associating it to visual elements on a user interface.
In our case, we would take something like
just a plain old CLR object.
A car object. A book object. Those would have properties.
A Book object would have maybe the book image,
the author, the title, things of that nature.
We would want to present each instance of Book in a
in a collection of books on-screen to the user
in a grid-like fashion.
We may want to have the Book image on the top.
We might have the title overlaying that image.
We might have a short description below it,
the author's name below that.
We get to create a little template,
how each individual instance of Book
will be represented in the user interface.
That's what the GridView would allow us to do.
The ListView is exactly the same,
except it works more in a single-column fashion.
We'll show an example of that a little bit later.
As you can see, I've got project called xBindDataExample.
For reasons that will become obvious in just a moment here.
I've already started working on this a little bit.
You can see that...
Let me call your attention to a Book class
here in the Models folder.
This is a simple class.
When I say plain old CLR object,
I just mean a simple class with properties.
This doesn't even have methods but it could.
This simple Book class just has a BookID, Title, Author,
and then CoverImage which would be
a reference to Assets that I have here; image Assets.
1.png, 10.png.
You can see as I hover over we've got
some fake book covers here that I created.
Below that, I have another class in the same file.
Ideally, I would have separated that out,
but I delegate the responsibility to this class
called BookManager.
I'll create a new instances of Book,
adding them to a new collection, a List of Book,
then returning that List back to the caller.
Inside of there you could see that I have
this object initializer syntax actually set
each of the book's properties to something unique.
Again, just some lorem ipsum text
for Title, Author, and the CoverImage.
We'll use this method here in just a moment
to get the information that will bind our Grid to.
Let's work on the Grid itself.
First of all, you can see here in the MainPage.xaml,
I've already started laying out the layout grid.
This Page will have two Rows.
The top Row will be where we do all of our work.
The bottom Row will just contain a TextBlock.
Later on whenever we select one Book,
I want to show you the process of selection.
Selecting one will grab the details
and print them to that ResultTextBlock there.
What we'll do for the majority of the time here
is actually work on adding a GridView
and binding it to data.
Data that we're going to grab from that
Book.cs file that we created; the BookManager Class.
Let's start by creating a GridView.
One of the things you need to do with a GridView
is we want to create a template,
how each individual instances of Book will appear on-screen.
To do that, I'm going to go
GridView.ItemTemplate.
The ItemTemplate contains a DataTemplate.
We'll come back and flush some things out
about this DataTemplate in just a moment.
Inside of that DataTemplate we can basically lay out
how we want each instances of Book
to be represented on-screen.
We can use Grid, StackPanels, any of the controls
that we've leaned about up to this point.
In this case, I'm going to keep it pretty simple.
I want to display an Image of the Book,
then the tile and the author.
Maybe the title will be slightly larger font,
author will be slightly smaller font.
Okay?
We'll start out with an Image,
then have two TextBlocks beneath that.
The TextBlock will be...
The FontSize for the one that will contain
the title of the Book, we'll make that like 16 FontSize,
then the one below it FontSize
equal to maybe 10, real small.
The Image itself I'm going to make sure that the Image
is no larger than 150 pixels wide.
Let's set the Width="150".
A lot of setup work here just to kind of get things rolling.
The next thing that I need to do is to tell the GridView
what I'm going to bind to ultimately.
In order to do this,
I'm going to populate the ItemSource property.
I'm going to set it to a new type of binding, x:Bind,
and we'll set it to a public property
that we're going to create on our code behind called Books.
I'm going to create a public property called Books
in my MainPage.xaml.
Books will be of type: List of Book.
Just like what we'll return from the BookManager.
Now, I need to tell the DataTemplate what
the data type is that is should expect to be working with.
To do that, I'm going to set a property
on the DataTemplate called x:DataType.
I want to set it to type Book.
In order to reference this class in my XAML,
I need to add a XML namespace here up at the page level.
What I'm going to do is type xmlns:data=
then I'm going to give it the name
of the application, so xBindDataExample.
Then the namespace where my Book class is located.
In this case, in the Models namespace
because I put it in the Models folder.
Right?
Now that I have that I should be able to do this.
data:Book
Next up, I'm going to set a property of each of these controls
equal to a property of the Book class.
In this case I'm going to set the Source=""
Source="".
(typing)
Here I'll set the Text property
and bind it to the Title.
Finally, I'll set the Text property of the second TextBlock
and bind it to the author's name.
I'm getting a little blue squiggly here
that the property VisualTree can only be set once.
See the mistake I made?
Need to put this in the StackPanel.
Forgot that. Got a little ahead of myself there.
That should fix that situation. Great.
Alright, the only thing left to do at this point
is to make sure that I create a public property
on my MainPage.xaml.cs
and populate that property with Books.
How do we do that?
Well, first of all,
inside of our MainPage class...
It can be public or private, it doesn't matter.
Here I'll go private.
List, we'll call it Books.
Remember if you don't see it...
I already had a "using" statement to the Models namespace.
If you don't get that you can hit the Control+"."
on your keyboard and select it from the drop-drown ListBox.
Inside here I want to initialize Books.
I'm going to set Books = BookManager.GetBooks();.
That will return me a list of Books.
At this point, I think we're ready to go.
Let's run the application.
Okay.
You can see that I get a number of Books.
Thirteen Books.
Now there's some formatting I could do here.
I think I should center up the text
right underneath the book itself
and may add some padding, and margins,
and things of that nature.
But, for the most part, it looks pretty good.
Notice that one of the qualities of the GridView
is that as you make it smaller in Width,
you have fewer Columns
and the Rows are commensurate to that as well.
Let's make a couple of quick changes
to the template.
Let's set the whole thing
HorizontalAlignment="Center"
then definitely want to do that
on each of the individual TextBlocks.
(typing)
Alright, that should look better.
We'll look at that in just a moment.
The next thing I want to be able to do is make a selection
on one of these items and
then retrieve information about that item.
What we're going to do is set two attributes of the GridView.
First of all, I want to make it clickable.
We're going to set an attribute called IsItemClickEnabled.
We'll set that equal to True.
Now we can click on an item
and receive an EventHandler as a result of that.
Then to set the actual EventHandler we want to...
(typing)
Set the ItemClick event to a new EventHandler.
GridView_ItemClick is just fine.
We'll get into that in just a moment.
I'm going to go ahead and move some things around here
so we can continue to see things on screen well.
Alright, now back to in the MainPage.xaml.cs.
You can see that we're going to get
an ItemClickEventArgs e.
"e" will give us the ClickedItem so we want to grab that
and we're going to convert that into an item of type Book.
Var book equals...
Now we have the instance of Book
that was clicked on in our GridView
in our ResultTextBlock that was already added
before we started working here.
Let's put "You selected"
and we'll concatenate the book's title, like so.
Great.
Let's run the application again.
Alright.
Things look a little bit better with centering and such.
You can see when I click on any of these items,
see what was selected.
Very cool.
There's a lot of permutations on this idea that we can take.
For example, this DataTemplate.
What if we need to use it in multiple spots?
Well, we can actually treat this just like we would
a Style and we can extract it from here,
and put it in a Page resource
or even the application resource.
All we need to do,
if we're going to reuse this in multiple places,
is to give it a Key.
BookDataTemplate.
Something like that.
Then I would remove that and set the
ItemTemplate equal to a StaticResource.
just like we were using Styles.
What did I call that BookDataTemplate?
It should work exactly the same as before.
Let's make sure.
Again, if there are multiple Pages in our app
that needed the same DataTemplate,
we could reuse it.
Great.
This is actually going to come in handy for us,
this little technique of extracting it out
then referencing it.
In an upcoming lesson when we take a more
advanced approach to how we style this up.
Before we conclude this I want to show you the exact,
same example except using the ListView control.
Look, it's almost identical in every way.
The only difference is that I changed up
how the DataTemplate is oriented.
I have one StackPanel that's horizontal.
I have the Image first on the left-hand side.
Then I have another StackPanel to the right of it
with the Title and Author kind of above each other.
You'll see how it's changed
but everything else about this example is identical.
Just wanted to show you
that it's essentially the same thing.
Okay? One single c=Column.
Now, inside of that column we can do as much styling
as we want to but it's just a different look.
Okay?
Alright, in this lesson we talked about data binding.
We talked about the GridView.
We talked about how to create a DataTemplate,
how to use the binding statement to bind to the data.
We looked at the difference between the
GridView and the ListView.
We're going to need these skills for
pretty much every project we do from here on out.
I hope you were paying attention.
Let's continue building on this in the very next lesson.
We'll see you there. Thanks.