Hi, I'm Bob Tabor with www.learnvisualstudio.net
and in this lesson we'll talk about
the second new layout control in the
universal Windows Platform API, the SplitView.
And the SplitView allows us
to create a panel that can be displayed
or hidden, and there's a little animation
associated with it so it looks like
it slides out and slides back,
into view and out of view.
So we would use the SplitView
to implement that hamburger navigation style
that is used in Windows 10,
like we saw in the previous lesson.
There are two parts to a SplitView.
One might be optional.
The other is required.
The part that's hidden by default that you display,
that's called the pane.
The part that's already displayed and can either
be overlapped, or it can be pushed over,
that's called the content.
Not sure that you have to have a content.
It'll work, I believe, without it.
But we're going to go ahead
and demonstrate it with it.
What you do is, you then implement
or define other controls
inside of the SplitView pane
and the SplitView content areas
that make up your application.
In the SplitView pane, what you want to do is to,
if we were to create a real application
that used the hamburger navigation style,
we'd have an icon and then text next to it.
And we'll get to that.
We'll build that in a couple lessons from now.
But we're just going to start with the basics
of just this component itself,
although it is a large piece of the overall puzzle
to make that happen.
Alright, so let's start by building a SplitView.
Here in my new application called "SplitViewExample."
So we're going to create a SplitView,
and inside the SplitView
we're going to create a pane,
and then a content area.
So inside the content area we can do
anything we want to do.
I'm going to actually just put a bunch
of TextBlocks for all of these.
Set the text equal to ...
So I'm going to create
just simple TextBlocks
in both the pane and the content area.
I'll just fill in some text
so we can distinguish it.
The first, second and third TextBlock will be in the pane.
The fourth,
fifth and sixth TextBlock
will be in the content area.
Now as you can see, we get the little error
that the property content can only be set once.
Why?
Because it has content property,
not a child property.
We're going to use a StackPanel or something else then
to enclose all of our items inside of each
the pane and this content area.
Alright.
Great.
Allright, and you can barely see,
let's go ahead and blow this up a little bit more,
to like 75%.
You can see that we will by default
be able to view the StackPanel's pane.
Now, if we were to run the application,
however, you see that the pane is nowhere to be found.
We only see the content area.
How do we actually display the pane?
Well we're going to have to first of all
give our SplitView a name.
So let's do that, MySplitView.
And then here let's go ahead and add
a Button outside of the SplitView
and call this...
And set the Click property...
the Click event rather, to Button.Click
And inside of here, what we're going to do
is work with MySplitView.IsPaneOpen,
and we're going to set the IsPaneOpen property
and we're going to set it to whatever
the MySplitView pane property is not.
So you can see that we're setting it equal
to the opposite of whatever it is right now
by using the not operator,
the exclamation mark.
So now let's do one more thing.
I'm going to change this outermost item
from a Grid to a StackPanel,
and then I'm going to delete that.
And then I'm going to save it,
and let's run the application.
Alright, so you can see that I can display
and hide that panel, very cool.
Now we can control more about that panel.
First of all, let me change this StackPanel
to the Orientation="Horizontal", great.
And what we're going to do
is set the SplitView's DisplayMode.
The DisplayMode is one of the most important
properties that we can set on the SplitView,
because it will
dictate how it actually operates.
So there's four options here.
Let's take a look at Inline,
and let's go ahead and run the application.
You can see whenever we click Inline
it actually pushes, the pane as it comes out,
pushes the content over.
Whereas, if we were to change this to Overlay,
just going to run the application again,
it would completely cover it up.
And then there's one other variation on this,
but we're going to have to set another property.
We're going to set the CompactPaneLength,
and you typically set this to a small value, like 50.
Just enough to display an icon.
So this is 50 pixels,
and so we'll do overlay...
CompactOverlay
This is a variation on overlay
that will display just a little crack
of what's underneath in the pane.
You can see First, Second and Third.
Let's change that even to just 10 pixels,
just so we can barely see it creeping out.
Right now it doesn't look particularly interesting.
You can just barely see First Second and Third
creeping through there on the very most left side.
Then when we click "Click Me," the pane covers up
whatever we see in the content area.
So that's CompactOverlay.
CompactInline is exactly like inline
except it shows that little compact area as well,
that will only be 10 pixels wide.
Here again, we see just a little bit
of First Second and Third text block,
and when we click it, it pushes everything over,
because it's Inline.
We can also adjust things like the OpenPaneLength,
and we can set that to, let's say, 50 pixels for example.
Now let's see how that affects our application.
So you can see that it really restricts
the size of that pane as it opens up, in this case.
We can also set the background and things of that nature.
Now, here's the thing about the SplitView,
is that by itself it really doesn't do much.
You're given a lot of latitude to build out
how you want to implement your pane.
In this case I just used TextBlocks.
They don't really make a whole lot of sense.
We would want to either use a Button
or something that's clickable so that
when we click it, we navigate to something
in the main area of our application,
some feature or some different information.
Again, like I said earlier, we're going to learn
how to do that a couple of lessons from now.
First, I think we need to learn a couple more
input controls that we can use,
and once we learn about those, I can show you
a very simple way to implement the hamburger navigation.
We're going to come back to this idea
in another lesson or two.
So we'll see you there, thank you.