All right, so in this video, we're going talk about
adding an option so that a user can purchase
the ability to remove ads from the application.
And we're going talk about that in just a moment
but if you recall at the very end of the previous video,
I was a little flustered because
we lost some functionality in our application.
We added the ad control and then our application
no longer showed album art
and you can't play without the album art.
So, what I discovered apparently is unique to my machine.
When I dragged and dropped
the Ad Mediator Control onto the designer surface,
somehow, someway, it removed all of the binding expressions
in the DataTemplate, here in the source,
here in the item source for the GridView.
Everything else was there, just anything
that had to do with data binding was stripped out.
So I merely just pasted that in from a previous
older version of the example and it works again.
So I talked to Microsoft about this.
Apparently this is something specific to my machine,
but just be forewarned, if you hit the same thing
then at least now you know what's going on.
That took a few hours out of my life I'll never get back.
All right, but what we want to talk about
is actually how do we add the ability
to allow the user to make purchases inside of our apps?
And there's a great starting point
for learning about this at the following URL.
Let me navigate there, actually.
All right and the instructions are pretty good here.
You should be forewarned that there are
a few things that you're going to have to do
during development time that you're going to have to change
right before you submit your application
to the Microsoft Store.
So one of the things that we're going do is
work with something called a Current App Simulator.
Once we have finished debugging
our application and our application
is feature complete, then we're going
to change all references to the Current App Simulator
to simply Current App.
Further more, whenever we're in the store
and we're ready to publish our application,
there will be an opportunity there
to list out each of the options
that can be purchased from with
inside of our application.
So we create what's called an in-app offer token.
We just have to make sure that
we remember what these are
and enter them as well as the price,
how much we're going to charge
for each of these options and so on.
We'll see a little bit of this in just a bit.
Here I have an extremely simple application
that will demonstrate just the bare bones
functionality for enabling or disabling a feature
based on whether the user has made
a purchase or not.
So let's go and run the application.
And you can see, at this point
I've determined that the feature
in question, a rectangle.
The user has not purchased the rectangle yet.
So they see the Purchase Rectangle button.
Now you don't have to use a button,
you can use a link, you can use anything
that you want that can just trigger
the process of displaying the purchase option
to the end user.
So I'm going to go ahead and say,
let's go ahead and purchase the rectangle.
Now we see this simulation of
the purchase process pop-up.
This is the current app's simulator's user interface.
We'll show you the code where we actually
call in to pop this up.
You can see the in-app offer token
is called, MyInappOfferToken.
The return code, we can say whether
this succeeds, whether it fails,
whether there's invalid arguments
that have been sent in.
So we can test a lot of different conditions
that we would expect to receive back
from the store whenever our app
is live and available for purchase online.
But this time I'm going to go ahead and say
the code to return is okay.
So I hit continue and you'll notice
that the Purchase button went away
and I displayed...
the red rectangle that the user purchased.
Now let me show you how this works.
First of all, what you need to do is...
understand that there is a local file
that keeps track of all of the in-app purchases
and whether an app is in trial mode or not
and it's called the WindowsStoreProxy.xml file
and if you take a look back on that web page,
it talks about the location for this
on the local user's hard drive.
So you can actually go to your own
local hard drive and if you've purchased
applications or you've added in-app
purchases to specific applications,
you can go look for this file.
I'm not sure if it will show it to you or not.
I haven't actually taken the time to look
for these files for other applications
but if you look at your
userprofile/appdata/local/packages
then whatever the package name is
and it's going to be a big, long GUID
/localstate/microsoft/windowsstore/apidata
/windowsstoreproxy.xml.
Then you're going to see a file
that looks something like this.
Let me go ahead and open it up here in notepad.
And again, this is just the sample
that was created for a sample application
that I created and what I did was,
I took this, edited it and then
added a version of this
to the Assets directory of my project
and we'll come back to that in just a moment.
Essentially, this is going to contain
listing information, the name of the app,
the description of the app, the price of the app
and for the various markets where
the app is sold.
Then there are individual products
that can be purchased within the application itself.
So you can see there's two different product types.
There's a durable product type,
this obviously would last for the duration
of your ownership and then there are
consumable product types, so this might be
credits or tokens towards something
in the game or I'm sorry, in the app.
Like in a game situation, you might purchase
gold and you might use that gold
and use it up essentially.
That's a consumable in-app purchase
but if I were to turn on a feature
by paying an extra $2, $5, that would be
a durable product type.
I have to use the name of that in-app
purchase token, the feature token
and then the price and obviously
it's in dollars USD in this particular market data.
You can see that this is for the English US.
So I can define multiple of these
for different regions and languages around the world.
And then, each of these have a product ID,
as you can see and those are referenced
down here in the license information.
So you have the listing information on top
which lists the app itself as well as
any in-app purchases and then the licensing
information is really what we're most
concerned about especially in our case
since we're worried about a durable product
that we're going to enable.
So first of all, the app itself is the app active?
Has the user purchased the app?
If IsActive is True then they can use the app.
If it's False then they won't be able to.
You can also have a trial mode
for a certain period of time as defined
up here but we don't have a trial mode.
We can turn that off and set it to False.
Here's the key for the purpose of this video
is the product ID and whether this particular
in-app purchase is active or not.
Let's take a look now, I took this general
template and I created a template
or I'm sorry, a file called test.xml
that's specific to this application.
I left some of the things like the market data off.
I really don't care about that so much.
What I really focused on was this
MyInappOfferToken product ID.
For the English US market, I also used the name.
I could give this a more friendly name I suppose.
Then finally here at the bottom
for that given in-app offer, the license information.
I've got the IsActive set to False.
Now, when I run the application,
it's going to read in that file,
it's going to know the different products
that are available in-app and it will
then determine that I do not currently have
that feature so show the Purchase button
for that feature, then after I make
the purchase, then it will change the value
to IsActive is True.
It's important to know that in debug time
with these files that we're loading here
locally into the current app simulator,
it will not write to these files.
So if I want to test the condition
where the purchase was all ready made
prior to running the application,
a second or subsequent time,
then I can change that value from False to True
and re-run the application.
You can see now, it just defaults to,
hey you've all ready purchased
the red rectangle, here it is.
So some important things to consider
when you're going to use this.
Let's take a look at the code itself
and what we did.
I kept everything in the MainPage.xaml.cs
but obviously if you're working with something
that is a little bit more global in nature
then you're going to want to put this
in the App.xaml.cs file instead
and then reference it from the rest of the application.
In the page load, you can see that I've got
some important little bits here where I put
a flower box comment around it and some explanation.
Here is where I load up that test.xml file
that we looked at just a moment ago
and then I give it to the current app simulator
and say, hey reload the simulator
and use that test file that I created.
Once I am about to submit this application
to the store, I would want to comment
all of this out or delete it completely.
Probably just comment it out because
I want to continue to test this even after
I release the application.
Furthermore, I would want to change
all of these references to current app simulator
to just CurrentApp.LicenseInformation and so on.
At any rate, first of all I want to get
a reference to the app license information
and then I can look at the various product
licenses and say hey, I have a product
with this token name, MyInappOfferToken,
is it active or not?
If it is active then we'll change the visibility
both of the rectangle and the purchase button accordingly.
So that's what I do in these lines of code here.
Then, whenever the Purchase button is clicked,
here again we're going to insure
that that particular In-app offer token is not active.
If it is active, then there's a problem
with the logic in my application because
it shouldn't be right?
So we would just bail out of this.
However, assuming that we have not
all ready purchased this once,
then we want to and this is the key,
make a call into RequestProductPurchaseAsync()
and pass in that token for the product
that we're going to allow the user to purchase, so we call,
CurrentAppSimulator.RequestProductPurchaseAsync()
and that's what pops up that little dialog
and what would pop up,
a common dialogue in the phone
or on the desktop to allow the user
to decide whether their going to pay
$2, $5, for the in-app purchase.
Once it's complete, we're going
to get back a purchase results.
This is what's going to give us that
the purchase succeeded or the order
wasn't fulfilled, it wasn't purchased,
it's all ready been purchased.
If it succeeds, then what we want to do
is adjust the state of the application
accordingly and then, in this case,
just change the visibility of the rectangle
on the button and then move on.
That's all there is to it.
I know it sounds like a lot but it's really
not that hard to add this in into your app.
Obviously in-app purchases are the best way
to monetize an application because you give
people a reason to download the app
in the first place and then you only
monetize it for those hyper responders
who want the extra features that you're
willing to sell them.
Now what we want to do is apply
everything we learned here into our app.
I'm going to move this out of the way, off screen
and I'm going to pop back over
to the AlbumCoverMatchGame.
What I'm going to do is set the visibility
of the Ad Mediator Control.
So visibility equals collapsed to begin with.
And then what I'm also going to do here
is add, no I'll keep it simple.
It's not going to be pretty but I'm going
to add a button instead and just
put it here and let's call this,
the Name equals PurchaseButton.
And the click event will be,
PurchaseButton_Click.
And the Content equals "Remove Ads"
We'll worry about how it looks
and where it's positioned in just a moment.
I'm not going to worry about that just yet.
But I probably should put it in the same
grid cell for now.
Let's separate this out on the separate lines, like so.
Now let's go into the PurchaseButton click event.
Next up what I want to do is go ahead
and I'm going to add a new item.
Sorry that's off to the right hand side.
I'm going to create a New XML File.
I can call this anything.
I'm just going to call it "Test" for now.
This is where I'm going to go
to the test.xml file that I created
a moment ago that we looked at
in that in-app purchase example
and I'm just going to copy and paste it here,
the body of it, into this Test.xml.
I'm going to probably need
to change things like the app name.
So, AlbumCoverMatchGame.
The description, Have fun guessing songs
and album art from your music collection.
The price of this is going to be free right?
So, probably just leave that at zero.
Here we come to the MyInappOfferToken.
I'm actually going to call this something different.
The "RemoveAdsOffer", maybe that's something
we can call it and we'll say,
"Remove Ads from the App".
And the price will be $1 and then we'll
make sure to paste in that product ID here
and set the IsActive to False.
That should be all we need to do in that file.
I'm going to close it for now
and I literally am just going to copy
code that we've all ready written
in that in-app purchase example
that we looked at a little bit earlier.
What I'll do to begin with here,
is in the Page_Loaded event.
I'm really just going to copy all this stuff
and paste it in there.
Because there's not much that needs to change
except I'm going to need to paste in, oops.
I'm going to need to get that, whatever I called that
Remove ads offer.
I'll need to re-paste it in here and I think
that's it for now.
You can see that we got some red squiglies.
Let me get my face off here so you can
see the whole screen.
Now we're going to hit control period
to start adding using statements.
For an app simulator, let's hit control period.
It's in Windows.ApplicationModel.Store with that.
That should resolve a bunch of stuff for us.
Oh yeah and this app license information,
I actually created that as a public property
of the MainPage.XAML.
So up here at the top, above private,
I'm going to paste in that, I just did
prop, tab, tab, license information object, it's of type,
Windows.ApplicationModel.Store.LicenseInformation
and I named it AppLicenseInformation
and just let the default getters and setters,
leave them where they are.
Now you can see that I'm getting
red squiggy's because of the fact
that this should have an async keyword
there in the method signature.
Then, obviously, this isn't what we want here.
We're going to have to rethink that as well.
And that actually should be pretty easy right?
What we'll do is, we got the name
of the Ad Mediator Control so let's
set the Visibility equals Visibility.Collapsed
if they've purchased the feature
and if they can't, then we'll set
the Visibility equals Visable and then the same
is true for the button.
What did I name that button?
We named it PurchaseButton, great.
So the reverse will be true on
the visibility of the purchase button.
So PurchaseButton.Visability equals Visibility.Visible
and then the reverse is true here.
All right, so far so good.
The last thing that we need to do
is just find the purchase button click event
and here what we want to do is actually pop-up...
the purchase dialog, so I'm going to past that in.
Here again, this is going to be async
and I need the name of my offer.
I probably should make this a constant frankly
instead of using these magic strings
all over the place.
And then we'll obviously want to change this,
If succeeded so then that means
we want to get rid of the ad mediator.
So let me copy those two lines of code
and replace them with this.
You see how easy that was?
I am concerned about the placement
of this button, where it's actually going to show up.
The way it stands right now,
the button will actually sit on top of the control.
Let's see how it looks and then we can
make some hard decisions about that.
I don't see my button.
All right button, where'd you go?
I just noticed something here.
When we dragged and dropped that control,
we put a huge negative margin there.
I'm not sure that I needed to do that.
Maybe we'll try this.
VerticalAlignment equals "Top".
and HorizontalAlignment equals "Right".
Let's see what that gives us.
Still not seeing my button. Where are you?
What am I missing here?
Oh you know what?
I'm a complete and utter knucklehead.
Here's the problem.
It's not exactly like the previous scenario.
You're probably sitting there and saying,
"Bob, you're missing the point of this."
If you purchase this, it should go away.
So unlike our example where we show something
when you purchase it, now we want
to hide something when you purchase it.
We want to hide both the button
and the ad mediator control.
I'm a little embarrassed. Sorry about that.
That's what you get whenever you code
in front of a live audience.
Probably would want to add a little bit of margin there,
clean things up, make it look a little better
but let's go ahead and click the Remove Ads
and I'm going to go ahead and say,
"Hey, let's remove them." And it works, awesome.
We'll just pick one, got to learn those songs.
We're pretty much done with the app.
Like I said, I would really, really, like
to get a graphic designer involved in this
and add some better aesthetic,
maybe some better placement of things and so on.
One thing I am going to do here is just
add a little margin around the mediator control
and around the button itself.
Let me think about this for a moment
What I want to do is just set a margin here...
of 10 on the left, 10 on the top
and I think I may need to make
some more room here actually.
This is, I think this is a 100, yeah,
row definition I want to make 110
because 90 plus 10 plus 10.
In fact, let's just be brief about this.
I'm going to do the same thing here as well.
So margin 10 and let's see what that gives us.
I might move that to the lower right hand corner
but at this point, it's kind of academic.
Probably need a good logo.
Obviously need better art work.
Really the focus here on this particular project
was being able to access all of the files
from a library, being able to iterate through
and grab them all.
We were working with the KnownFolders.Library
collection of files to get all of the music files
on your local computer.
I think the other thing that we wanted
to demonstrate in this was adding ads
to monetize the application
and then adding the in-app purchase
like we did in this video.
I can't seem to think of what else
we wanted to demonstrate.
Oh, playing media, retrieving a file
and playing it and just a ton of logic here
to decide what to play and how to play it
and to keep score and all those sorts of things.
Hopefully it was a helpful project in that regard.
The great news is that we have
one more project left and it's going
to be a fun project because we're
going to get with the Marvel API
and I'm really excited about this.
So we'll see you in that lesson, thanks.