Alright, so to get started, we're going to do
some basic Project setup, and then we're going to
talk immediately about our approach
working with the Weather API.
So let's go ahead and get started by just
creating a new Project and getting that part
of it out of the way.
We'll find our correct
Blank App template here.
I'm going to call this UWPWeather.
Okay, and first thing I'm going to do here
is get rid of the frame counter,
like always, and I'll open up the MainPage.xaml
MainPage.xaml
So what I have envisioned here is a
pretty simple application.
It's just going to have the current weather
for the current location you're at.
You can extend this, and I'll show you how
you can make this as complicated
and as feature-rich as you want.
It's just pretty much more of the same
of what I'm going to show you here
in this lesson, in these lessons.
Now that we have that in place,
I'm going to go ahead and minimize this.
We're going to pull our data from
a website called openweathermap.org.
By all rights, if you're going to use this
in a commercial product, you need to sign up
for an API, and then if your requests
are in excess of a certain number per month,
you'll need to get a
paid license.
For example, for $180 a month, as I record this,
you can have 30,000 API calls per minute.
Now, for just our own purposes
in learning and development, we're not
going to get any more than 1,200 APIs per minute,
API calls per minute, but here again,
you probably need to consult their website.
I'm not lawyer, I don't understand all
of the ramifications of this.
This is purely for us learning how to make
a call to a web service.
So I'm going to leave that part of it
between you and OpenWeatherMap,
but I'm going to look at the API.
There's several different weather APIs
that we can call.
API will be
basically a web-callable API.
That means we use a URL to make a call,
and it will deliver back to us either JSON
or XML or some file format that then
we can parse through and use as data
for our application.
There's current weather data, which is
the one we're going to use.
There's also 5 day/3 hour forecasts,
16 day/daily forecast,
a bunch of other APIs.
We're going to focus on this first one,
the current weather data.
You can see in the openweathermap.org/current
that there are different ways to make calls
into this weather API.
For example, if all we have is the
city name, then we can give it
something like that,
where we replace this curly brace
city name with, for example, Dallas
or Dallas, USA.
We would get back the weather, the current weather
for that location.
So there's a number of different ways
that we can acquire this.
We can use a city ID.
There's a list of IDs that we can download
and utilize.
We can get to the weather by geographic coordinates.
This is the one that we're going to use
because we're going to use our
device's built-in GPS functionality
or location functionality to bring us back
the latitude/longitude for
the current position of our device,
and then we'll deliver that as latitude
and longitude to this API call,
and retrieve back the current weather conditions for it.
We could also use ZIP code.
There's some advanced scenarios, as well,
that we're not going to really worry about
all that much.
But if you like, you could scroll down,
you could learn a lot about
what's delivered back to you
when you make one of these calls
into this API.
So let's do this.
What we'll do, first of all, I'm going to start
by saying Dallas
latitude longitude
This will give me back the coordinates.
32.77 North.
I think this is a,
it might be negative 96.79 West,
so West would be a negative.
But any rate, let me copy those coordinates
and put them just in a little notepad file
that I have here offscreen so that
I can remember those.
Then what we'll do is we'll come back over here,
and I'm going to
find this.
In fact, let me just go ahead and click on it
to start off with.
Then I'm going to change the latitude
and longitude here
to 32.77.
Then I'll change the latitude to a negative
96.79.
I'm going to see what we get back.
You can see what we get back
is a series of JSON,
JSON, JavaScript Object Notation, a very
lightweight way of exposing data
over the Internet, very common way of exposing data.
While this might look a little convoluted,
it actually follows a very simple pattern.
But let's do this, I'm going to actually
use my mouse to select that entire
JSON string that even runs off to the
right-hand side of the screen.
I'm going to hit Control+C to copy this
to my clipboard.
Then I'm going to go to another website
called json2csharp.
What this is going to allow me to do
is to paste in the JSON, right like this,
and now when I hit Generate, what'll happen
is it'll create a series of classes
that represent that JSON.
So now I have C# classes that I
can then deserialize the JSON
into these strongly typed classes in C#.
So you can see at the very highest level here,
I'll have a RootObject.
This RootObject will have a List of Weather items.
Then there's just a series of
other classes that were created, a main class,
a wind class, a rain class, a clouds class
and other information as well.
For example, this Sys class will give us
the county, a message, the sunrise, sunset times.
Just a ton of information.
In the main class, there's pressure, humidity.
In the weather class, we can get an icon
and a description for the current weather.
What we're going to do is actually I'm going to copy
all of this
to my clipboard.
I'm going to create something called,
here in Visual Studio.
I'm going to go over here and right-click.
Actually, let me go ahead and select
Project, Add Class.
I'm going to call this
OpenWeatherMapProxy.
A proxy is a go-between.
That might not be the best name for this,
but it's what came off the top of my head.
Inside of this, I'm actually going to paste
all these other classes as well.
So my thought process here is that I'm going to
have a static method on this
OpenWeatherMapProxy.
What it will do is it will, when you give it
the latitude and longitude, it's going to feed it
to this web service URL
that we have here, replacing the latitude
and the longitude that we're going to get
from our device's GPS,
and it will convert the data that comes back
in JSON format into a series of classes
that we can then navigate through, pull out
the bits we want to display to the user
on the screen.
Hopefully that all made sense.
You'll see it as we move forward here.
So what I want to do, just as we start
playing with this idea, is,
actually, let me go ahead and get rid of that.
I'm going to start just with a StackPanel.
I'm not going to get too fancy with this
just to begin with.
But I'm going to set the Background="HotPink"
because I saw a cool demo with
a hot pink background and it looked pretty cool,
and it's very different from anything else
that you'll see
out there right now.
I am going to add a Button with
Content="Get Weather".
I'll say set a Click Event.
I think that's all I'll need to do there.
Then I'm going to add a TextBlock.
We're going to call this, name this
"ResultTextBlock"
"ResultTextBlock".
I want you to know that this is not, ultimately,
what I'm going to have for my layout.
This is just for me to be able to test
the process of going out and grabbing
the data, and then displaying something to the user.
Once I can get that hardest, here's my thought process.
Whenever I go sit down to build an application,
I always like to tackle the most difficult aspects
of the application first because
then I get some degree of confidence
that I know what it will do.
I don't make any assumptions beforehand
what it's going to do, how it's going to operate.
That might adjust the way that I lay things out,
the way that I approach the rest of the application.
So I always attack the most difficult part
of the application first.
Typically, that's going to be any of the internals
of the application.
It's going to be business logic,
it's going to be any data access, it's going to be making
calls out to web APIs like we're doing here.
Once I can get those question marks
in my mind resolved, then it makes
building the rest of the application fairly easy.
That's what I'm doing here.
I'm just going to create some initial code
that I'm ultimately going to probably throw
all this stuff away.
So at any rate, let's go ahead and hit F12 there.
So now we have a Button_Click Event,
and we're going to make a call into this
OpenWeatherMapProxy class.
What I want to do is create a
public static RootObject GetWeather
public static RootObject GetWeather.
Eventually, I'll pass in the latitude and longitude.
Should I do that now?
Yeah, sure, why not?
I can always ignore it.
Whoops, double latitude,
double longitude.
Alright, great.
So what I need to do is make a call
out to this web service.
The way that I'll do that is through a class
called the HttpClient.
To add this, I'm actually going to go
to Tools, NuGet Package Manager.
I'm going to Manage NuGet Packages
for the Solution.
I'm going to search for the HttpClient.
I'm going to install this.
It asked me, "Do you want to add all these?"
Yes, yes,
and I accept.
Alright, very good.
So now what I want to do is
go here.
Should be able to find it.
I'm going to add that using statement.
We'll go var http = new HttpClient()
var http = new HttpClient(), like so.
Now what I want to do is
get a response object.
This a type HTTP response message.
I'm going to get to it by calling the GetAsync method.
So what we'll do is give it a URI,
a string URI that we're going to request.
Any time we see the word async,
what do we need to do?
Remember the formula.
We need to say, "I will wait for the results,"
and that means I need to tell my method
that this is an async method, right?
Then I need to give it the URL.
If you recall what we did here,
I should be able to just copy this in
for testing purposes, and just go ahead
and pop that in there like so.
We should be able to get back
whatever data comes from that,
comes back from that method.
Next up, I need to grab a result,
and the result will be
what comes back in the
response.Content.ReadAsStringAsync()
response.Content.ReadAsStringAsync().
Again, we see the async keyword.
That means we need to await that as well.
Now I have this in a string format.
Now what I need to do is I need to serialize.
I need to take all that string
that we see when we looked here,
and we need to convert that into an Object Graph.
All of these, the RootObject and all of the
objects that it has references to.
To do that, what I need to do is
use an object called the DataContractJsonSerializer.
I'm going to create something called a serializer.
It's an object that knows how to serialize
and deserialize from JSON.
We'll go DataContractJsonSerializer
DataContractJsonSerializer.
As you can see, it's not really part of my
Project just yet.
However, I can just hit Control+".".
and I can add that System.Runtime.Serialization.Json
System.Runtime.Serialization.Json namespace, and we should
be good to go there.
I need to give it the typeof
class that I want to work with.
In this case, we'll start with the RootObject,
and it'll have references to everything else
that it needs.
Oh, we need to create a new instance of that.
There we go.
Now, in order for this to work, we have to do something,
we have to adorn each of these classes
and their properties with special
attributes.
To get this to work right, every class is going to
have to be adorned with something called
a DataContract.
This attribute is in a namespace that we
need to add, System.Runtime.Serialization
This will just tell the serializer that, "Hey,
"treat this like a class, and treat this like
"a property."
We'll go DataMember for each property.
Now we have to go through
and add that attribute on top of every class
and every member of the class.
I'm just going to go ahead and do this.
It's going to take me a minute or two
of just copying and pasting a lot.
This is a common thing that you'll do whenever
you're calling out
to web APIs.
I don't think that you could be a professional developer
nowadays without knowing these techniques,
being able to serialize and deserialize from XML
and JSON format, and maybe other custom formats,
too, like some binary format.
It's a pretty crucial skill to have in your toolbelt.
This is just one
possible way to go about this.
I see something that caught my eye
just a moment ago.
It spurred a memory
of frustrations past.
Let me get back to it here in a just a second.
There'll be some things that I want to change
the names of that I don't like how they're
automatically named by that
tool that we used,
that free website that converts
your JSON into C#
POCO classes.
Yeah, for example, this item here
has an invalid name.
In fact, what I'm going to do is just
comment this out completely.
I'm not going to even use this at all.
Hopefully, the deserializer,
the DataContractJsonSerializer
will just say, "Oh, okay, they don't have a class for that.
"We'll just ignore that," as it tries to pair up
all of the data
that it has with all the class
and property names.
So that's the only thing that I think
I was concerned about.
Let's go ahead and continue on here.
Now what we're going to need to do is get
a MemoryStream.
New MemoryStream.
Let me go ahead and hit Control+"."
on my keyboard
and add the System.IO namespace.
I want to tell it that we're working
with a certain type of Encoding,
specifically, the UTF-8 Encoding.
We're going to call GetBytes.
The reason why we're doing this
is kind of a long story.
I don't really want to talk about it
at the moment.
Most of the time, whenever you're grabbing JSON
and you're working with it, you're going to need
to work with the,
the way that the text is encoded is just UTF-8,
so you'll often use this similar line of code to this.
Just keep that in mind.
Finally, now that we're ready to accept
a MemoryStream, and a Stream
is just a
straw.
It allows us to just have data come in and go out.
Whenever you have things that are happening
at two different speeds, you have something
sending data at a different rate of speed
than something accepting data, you use a Stream.
Here we're going to use a MemoryStream.
We're just going to keep everything in memory
until it all gets sorted out.
Data will go in one end, and then it'll be taken out
as it's needed on the other end.
Finally, we're going to go ahead and do,
get the actual data out of the serializer.
ReadObject
and
let's also then cast that
to a RootObject.
Then we're going to return the data.
So I realize this is pretty meaty stuff here.
It looks like there's one last thing that I need to do.
If I hover my mouse cursor over this,
we've created an async method,
but we've not adorned
the return object as a Task.
So we need to say, actually, what we're going to
be returning is not a RootObject,
but a promise that when this is completed,
it will give us the type RootObject.
That's what a Task object is.
That should work, hopefully.
We'll test that out in just a moment here.
So let's go over here to our MainPage.xaml
and make a call into
that.
So let's go
var weather equals
new, well, actually, let's not do it that way.
Let's go RootObject myWeather
RootObject myWeather = OpenWeatherMapProxy.GetWeather()
RootObject myWeather = OpenWeatherMapProxy.GetWeather().
We'll give it just
a fake
latitude and longitude because I know
we're going to be hard coding that.
This has to be awaited, right?
That means this has to be async, right?
So that looks like that works, great.
Let's move that over a little bit.
Now that we have the weather, we should
be able to, for example, in the ResultTextBlock.Text,
we should be able to go
myWeather.name,
and then let's concatenate that to
myWeather.
What else can we get here?
I think if we do, if we want to get to the temperature,
we go to myWeather.main.temp
myWeather.main.temp.
There we go.
Then I think, also,
we can do this,
my... plus
myWeather dot...
What we'll get back with this weather
is it'll be a list of weather items.
We want the first weather item.
I think the other weather items are for
different hours or different days.
Then we'll say, "Give me a description
"of what the weather is."
So let's go ahead and run it.
I'm sure we'll hit some bugs
in just a moment.
Yeah.
Oh, here we go.
That's easy to fix.
I got rid of the class, so I have
to get rid of that as well.
Let's try it now.
Alright, well, we got our hot pink.
At least that's going for us.
I'll click Get Weather, and awesome.
Look, we got Dallas County.
We get the temperature is 299,
so that's Kelvin degrees.
We need to use, we can use Celsius
for those who live in the Metric System,
or Fahrenheit for those who live
in the Imperial System.
But at any rate, I was able to grab out
where I'm at currently.
So I'm in Dallas County.
This is on my local desktop.
I don't have a GPS, but it's able to triangulate
based on where my IP Address is to determine
where I'm coming from,
and it can determine that.
Then you can see here, it's light raining,
which is true.
I think it's in the mid 70s, high 70s.
We'll have to change that.
In fact, I think what I can do here,
let's go ahead and play around with this
a little bit.
We make our call out,
I think I can hit,
do this: units=imperial
units=imperial.
See if that's correct.
Yeah, so 78 degrees.
In fact, let me do one thing here with that,
with the temperature.
I'm just going to go ahead and go
convert that to an integer, and then take
the whole thing and convert it ToString,
like that.
That will get rid of the decimal.
Great.
One other thing that I want to talk about here
before we go any further, and that is
if you look at
this, you can also get to icons.
If we scroll down, there are some icons
that are associated
with.
Let me see if I search this, icon.
Yeah, you can see that it will return back
an icon as well.
So let's just,
let's have a little fun with this, actually.
Let's add an Image control.
Let's set its Name="ResultsImage"
Name="ResultsImage".
I'll just do Width="200"
Height="200".
Then what we'll do inside of here is set the
ResultImage.Source = myWeather
I think in order to get this work,
I'm going to have to act on this a little bit.
I don't think it's going to give me back,
the data that it gives us back, if we take a look
at this, like an example,
it gives us just '04n'
as the icon.
If we take a look at
this URL,
weather conditions.
Openweathermap.org/weather-conditions.
You can see that there are a bunch
of weather icons with specific names.
'01d' for daytime, '01n' for nighttime,
'02d' for daytime, so this is sunny,
partly sunny, cloudy, overcast.
It looks like they have the descriptions, too, here,
clear sky, rain, mist.
There's nine or ten of these things
with specific names.
So what my thought process is, is we can
access these
by going to
this URL, for example,
openweathermap.org/image/w/10d.png
openweathermap.org/image/w/10d.png.
Let's open that up in a new tab,
and you can see that we get that new image there.
So let's do this.
Let's grab that URL.
I copied it to my clipboard.
Let's go string icon = String.Format
string icon = String.Format
Then we'll use that for the most part,
but I know we're only going to get that little bit
right there from the
myWeather object.
So let's go myWeather dot...
There should be an icon here.
How do I get to the icon?
Oh, yeah, it's part of weather.
So weather.icon, great.
Now that we have it, we're going to set
the Source = new BitmapImage.
Yeah, and I don't have that correct,
so I'll have to add the using statement for
Windows.UI.Xaml.Media.Imaging.
So we've added that, and now I'm going to create
a new URI.
The URI will be
the string that we just formatted.
I have to tell it what kind of URI I want there.
So URIKind.Absolute.
So let's see if that works now, and let's
run the app.
Awesome.
So here's my thought.
I don't like their icons.
It makes the app look too generic.
What if supplied my own version of the icons,
and I just change wherever
we're actually accessing them?
I won't go out to
opwenweathermap.org/image/w.
I'll just go to my Assets folder here.
We'll do that, I think, in the next video.
I think that's the next thing that we'll talk about.
If not, it'll be the video after that.
We'll add that in.
At least we'll have our own icons,
and it'll look very distinctive
for the style that we're trying to achieve.
We covered a lot of ground in this video,
but we talked about a little bit of setup,
but mostly about how to get at the data.
So we've made huge strides just in this
very first video.
We'll pick it up in the next one.
Thanks.