Okay, so this is the coffee page step of the
Stupendous Styles Challenge Solution.
If you take a look at the screenshot I gave you,
brown background, three buttons that have
a background style, looks like,
we'll need to work on that somehow.
Looks like we have one, two, three rows,
and then I know we're going to have another row here,
that'll just push everything up.
With star sizing.
Actually you could do this a number of ways.
I think I just centered these three together.
I think I put them in a StackPanel,
and then centered the StackPanel,
so any way you want it, just move them over,
that's fine with me.
Looks like we're going to use the same spacing,
the same graphic and everything,
so for the logo, so that might be a perfect
opportunity to create another style,
a style at the application level.
And looks like we have some text here as well,
we might be able to borrow that from the previous,
from the previous video, and put that in the
application level style as well.
So let's go ahead and get started here.
You can see in the instructions we get
quite a bit of instruction around this.
In number six, the flyout menu contents.
What I want to do right now is work with this right here.
Grab that color, and we'll,
in the coffeepage.xaml,
I'm going change that first of all.
So I know I'm going to need
just rows for my implementation,
you might use columns, that's fine.
Let's do grid.rowdefinitions.
Or definition height
equals auto.
And then do one, two, three of those,
then on the fourth one we'll do star sizing, okay?
Very good.
So I know I'm going to need my image.
Now at this point, I have a decision to make.
Do I basically copy and paste from the donut page?
Or do I take the step of grabbing out
all this stuff, 'cause I'm going to reuse it all,
and putting that into a style, so let's do that.
I'm going to go to the app.xaml.
I know I'm going to use it on multiple pages,
so this is the right place for it.
And we'll create a resource section and create a new style,
and this will be, the target type will be image.
And then the key equals
white logo style.
Probably could come up with a
slightly better name than that.
I'm actually going to paste in what I have in my clipboard.
Setter, property,
and value.
All right, source.
With.
It's going to be what, 150?
And then the margin.
20, 20, 20, zero, and then finally...
That, and...
Let's try it here.
This should give us what we want there,
I'll come back to that in a minute.
I know also that I'm going to grab this,
start from the TextBlock,
and create a style out of that as well.
So I'm going to grab...
The font size, foreground, and margin.
And I'll go to the app.xaml.
And I'll just call this style...
TextBlock.
We're going to call that...
LabelTextBlockStyle.
Again, naming things is so hard.
So if you want to name it something
a little more descriptive, please,
please, be my guest.
Font size.
18.
and foreground.
White and then margin.
And that'll be
20, 20, 20, 0
All right, that should be good, let's correct that.
And I want to start using these all replace.
So here on the donut place,
let's get rid of
a lot of this stuff.
And I'm going to set the style equal to
static resource.
Great.
We'll just grab that out here.
And then use it here as well.
Okay.
And then...
Style here.
Static resource.
Nice.
All right.
So before we go any further, let me...
Just make sure that it compiles.
That nothing changed with our donut page,
and that our coffee page is off to a good start.
It looks like I need to create another setter
to set the horizontal alignment left so...
Let's go here.
And...
Horizontal alignment value left.
And that should take care of that issue.
And we'll look at that next time we run it.
Okay, back to the coffee page.
Yeah.
So in this case, I know I'm going to need buttons.
I need three of them.
Oh, and these buttons are special buttons, right?
So I can't just do the self-enclosing there, I need that.
And...
These buttons are going to have flyouts, right?
So flyout.
And then we want a menu flyout.
And then we want
MenuFlyoutItems
And here's where we use those lists.
Now I just happen to have them offscreen,
so I can see them here.
But I'm going to basically do that.
And...
We'll set the content equal to "Roast" on this one.
I'm going to set the...
I'm going to set margin to 10 all the way around.
So I'm just going to set it once,
I don't know if I should do that technique,
but when you set it once, it'll set 10
on all four sides, just FYI.
And then the foreground of this button is
going to need to be white.
And that reminds me what I wanted to put them inside,
it was a StackPanel, so let's go ahead and
set that up as well.
And the StackPanel's going to be in row two.
So grid.row equals one.
And I recall telling you that I set the horizontal alignment
center on that, so let's go ahead and set that as well.
Oh yeah, and,
we need to set the orientation to horizontal as well.
Great, okay, we're off to a good start here.
Now, since one of the requirements was
to use styles as often as possible,
I'm going to use a gratuitous style here.
Don't really need a style here, honestly.
But I'm going to use one anyway.
So...
Page.resources.
And we're going to have the style.
Type, whoops.
Target type button.
And the key will be...
Flyout button style?
Again I could probably come up with
a much better name than that.
So then we need some setters.
Just going to paste that right there.
Property and value.
Set the margin, 10.
And then the foreground.
It's going to be white.
And now we can use the flyout button style, nice.
So style equals static resource.
Button style.
Okay, great.
So I need three of these.
And you know what, I think,
oh, I've got the margin already, I'm good.
So let's grab one, two, and three.
The second one will be, what, sweetener?
And then the third one will be for...
Cream.
All right, so now what we're going to do is
change the text on each of these,
so this is going to be dark,
and this is going to be medium.
All right, then next up we want to go sweeteners none,
and sugar, and we'll get rid of the third menu flyout item.
And then the last one will be 2% milk,
and whole milk.
All right, and then what I want to do is add
click event handlers, but I'm going to kind of group them
together so each of the three, or two menu items,
flyout items will have the same click event handlers.
So click equals, and I want to create this myself,
I want to call this Roast_Click.
And I'll just copy this for all three.
And then we'll do the same thing with the sweetener.
Except we're going to rename this to sweetener.
And...
And then finally, Cream_Click.
All right, let's put our mouse cursor in
the new name of the new event, and hit F12,
to create that stub.
In our code behind.
Great, we'll come back to this in just a moment.
We've got a little bit of unfinished business here,
in the XAML, oh, in the coffee page xaml.
And that is that below all of this, I want to add
the, you know the coffee,
little label there, so StackPanel.
And I'm going to put these
in an orientation equal to horizontal,
and this will be in Grid.Row equal two.
And so I'm going to have two TextBlocks.
And the first one will be just static.
Coffee.
And I'm going to reuse one of the styles, since again,
that is really the point of all of this.
Static resource label
TextBlockStyle, perfect.
And then the second TextBlock will be,
we'll give it a name because we're going to want to
access it programmatically.
And then style equals,
and we'll do the same static resource
label TextBlockStyle.
And I think that's all I need to do there.
So we should be in good shape on that side of things.
All right, so in the coffee page, here's what we want to do.
My thought is that...
In each of these cases we're going to
retrieve off what was selected,
and then we want to rebuild that result
that we'll put in the ResultTextBlock.
So when I, I think all three of these methods need to call
a common helper method to do the assembly
of that resultMessage.
So I'll just do a private void
displayResult.
Like so.
We'll get to that in a moment, but here's kind of
how each of these will work.
We're going to use the routedEventArgs
for the click event, to determine which menu item
was the one that was selected, so here we go.
var selected equals sender.
I'm sorry, we're not going to use event args,
we're going to use the sender,
that will tell us which one was clicked.
Okay, sorry about that.
And then we'll say, we'll cast it to
of type MenuFlyoutItem.
Now we should have what we need.
But I'm going to need to pass some data
to this display result.
So since I need to kind of keep state
across all three of these button clicks,
I'm going to add some private variables,
so we'll do something like this.
Roast, and you'll see how I use this in just a minute here,
so you might be like, "What?
"What are you doing here?"
Trust me.
Okay.
So here's what we do now.
We set the roast equal to the selected.Text
of the MenuFlyoutItem, right?
And then we'll call that displayResult.
So now we just follow this pattern two more times.
So I'm copying and pasting, but what we grab off,
is different each time, right?
This time we want sweetener.
Is that how I spelled it?
Sweet, sweeter (laughs).
En-er, yeah, looks weird, but that is correct I guess.
And then the cream.
Great.
Now in displayResult, what we want to do is,
ultimately, kind of add
all of that stuff together, ResultTextBlock.Text
equals you know, coffee.
Or I'm sorry, _roast.
Plus...
_sweetener
Plus _cream, but it's really not that easy,
we've gotta take a few extra steps here.
All right, first up.
If the _roast is either none or if
that _roast string is empty, it hasn't been populated yet,
then we want to set the ResultTextBlock
to the word "None", because you can't just have
sweetener and cream without some coffee selected.
And then we're just going to exit out of this displayResult.
So if _roast
is equal to the string "None"
or (and this is one of my favorite
little methods, I don't know why, I just love it.
It's gotten me out of-- it just is an elegant way
of handling this situation.)
_roast
Then we're going to set the ResultTextBlockText,
equal to "None".
And then we'll just return out of this method, great.
All right, so then assuming that we were able to
make sure that
there's at least something in _roast,
we'll go ahead and set the ResultTextBlock.Text
equals _roast, all right, so we're in good shape there.
The next thing we need to do now,
is to check both the _cream and the _sweetener.
If the...
If the _cream, for example,
is not equal to "None" ...
and ...
It's not String.IsNullOrEmpty
_cream, so we have something in _cream.
Then we'll add it into the ResultTextBlock.Text.
We'll use plus equal, because we want to make sure to
add on whatever the _roast was.
We're going to add a plus symbol and some spacing.
And then we're also going to add _cream.
Whatever's in that _cream variable, okay.
And then I need to do the same thing.
With _sweetener, so let me just replace all those.
All right, and I'm going to go ahead and build it.
All right, so let's just test some weird scenarios here.
All right, that makes sense.
All right, none.
None.
Dark.
Whole milk.
None.
Dark, okay, I feel good about this.
I think we've completed that step.
So let's continue in the next video.
See you there, thanks.