Hi, I'm Bob Tabor with www.learnvisualstudio.net
and this is the solution, or at least part of the solution
for the challenge I called the Stupendous Styles Challenge.
In this first video there's going to be a lot of setup work,
we're going to create the Project, add the Pages,
copy over the Assets from that .zip file,
that folder that I have on my desktop there.
We'll work on navigation,
styling up the Buttons, creating Styles.
So I'm going to go ahead and turn off the webcam
so I can make facial expressions and not
distract you with my ugly mug.
And let's go ahead and create a New Project
and we'll call this GoNuts,
click OK.
And just so we can get it out of the way,
the very first thing I'm going to do is
take all the image assets from that folder
and I'm going to go to View, and go to Detail view.
It'll be easier that way.
And I'll take everything here
and I'll drag and drop it into the Assets folder.
Alright, very good.
So now I can get rid of that and I can
give myself some more space here.
Next thing I'm going to do is I'm going to add
all of those Pages, Blank Pages, to my Project.
So let's go.
We already have a MainPage.xaml so we need
a DonutPage.xaml.
I wonder how many projects in the history of Visual Studio
have had a DonutPage in them.
CoffeePage.xaml,
SchedulePage.xaml,
and this was CompletePage.xaml.
So we're good to go there.
And while I'm here I'm going to go ahead and remove
this DEBUG statement, get rid of the Frame counter,
and we're good to go there, I'll just close that up.
So the first thing I'm going to do is set up
the structure on that MainPage.
I do want to change the view to this 13.3" Desktop.
I just prefer working in that landscape mode.
And so we said that we're going to create
two Grid rows, so let's go ahead
and create some Grid.RowDefinitions here.
Grid.RowDefinitions and
we'll set the height
and copy it.
I do a lot of that, where I know that I need something
so I create the structure,
copy it a bunch of times and then fill in the details.
It just saves keystrokes that way.
So that top Row will be, actually I don't want it Auto,
I want it 100 like we specified in the instructions.
So in that top row we're going to have a Grid
and in the bottom row we're going to have a Grid as well.
Now I know in the bottom row
that Grid's going to have two Columns, so I'm going to
go ahead and just kind of lay that out right now.
So column, whoops, ColumnDefinitions.
And ColumnDefinition, I want the Width,
remember it was going to be 66% on the left,
33% on the right.
So how do we do that?
Width="2*",
Width="1*", great.
And on the left we're going to use a Frame,
so let's go ahead and just add a Frame,
and we'll fill in the details to that later.
Well actually I'll just call this MyFrame,
cause that's all I need to really do.
Equals MyFrame.
And then on the right we're going to put an Image.
And we'll set the Source="Assets/background.jpg"
Source="Assets/background.jpg".
And I'm going to set that Grid.Column="1"
Grid.Column="1", and I know I'm going to have to do
something else there but I'll see where we're at after that.
Next up I'm going to create,
this topmost Grid is going to have four Columns.
So let's just do this, actually.
That'll give me a good start.
And then each of these will just be, have an
equal share of the width, so they're all have "*" sizing.
And then I need buttons.
And what I'm going to do is actually just create one Button,
get it right, extract the Style,
and then create the other Buttons.
So I know inside the button I'm going to have a StackPanel,
because I want an icon, so I'm going to have an Image
on the left and then the TextBlock on the right.
Okay, so far so good.
The TextBlock, let's go ahead and set its
Text="Donut", in this case.
And the Image Asset, whoops, the Image Source
will equal "Assets/donut-icon.png".
And I'll have to play around with the sizes of those things.
I do know that I want the Background for this thing
to be black and I want the Foreground="White".
So that's good there
and like I give you the hint in the instructions,
I want these Buttons to take up the entire size
of the cell that they're sitting in.
First of all let me go ahead and do Grid.Column="0".
I know I don't have to do that on this one
but it'll remind me to do it on the others.
The next thing that I wanna do is
oh yeah, that HorizontalAlignment="Stretch"
and the VerticalAlignment="Stretch".
And that will make it the entire size of the cell.
If not it'll just be really small,
just large enough for the text inside of it
to actually display, or whatever the content is.
See what the preview looks like.
Alright. Clearly things are not looking great just yet.
Oh, I see what we need to do here.
So this Grid.Row="1".
That should fix that issue.
And we'll get back to that in a minute.
Up here it looks like this Image is
way too large in the preview.
I think all I really need is like 20x20.
So let's go Width="20" and Height="20"
Height="20", and I think the TextBlock's icon,
so the Foreground would equal White,
and I don't think we need that there, actually.
And then the, so the TextBlock, the Donut, Foreground,
oh, StackPanel, yeah we need that.
I can barely see it, and it didn't look quite right.
The Orientation needs to be "Horizontal".
Alright, that looks a little bit better.
Let's run it and see what we've got so far.
And you'll notice in these solutions that
I do a lot of coding and then afterwards
I test it but honestly
what I typically do is do a lot of testing.
I just don't want it to take forever long
recording these videos, okay?
So let's go ahead and shut that down.
I need to add one more thing in here,
and what I need to do is to set that BorderBrush,
remember we talked about that,
and let's set that to Gray, and then we're going to set the
BorderThickness to, and this works just like margins do,
so on the left I want a "0", on the top
I want a "0", on the right I want a "2",
and on the bottom I want "0" BorderThickness.
So now let's take a look at that.
And it might be hard to see against the white background
but there's a little tiny gray border there on the right.
Now you can also see while I'm in here
that this doesn't look quite right.
I think I need to set the Stretch property of that Image.
Let's go Stretch="UniformToFill",
and I think that will fix the issue.
So let's run it again.
Okay that's more like it. Great.
Now what I want to do is extract a Style
from this Button so we can apply it.
So Page.Resources,
and here I'm going to create a Style,
TargetType, sorry about that,
Style, TargetType="Button",
and then let's get a Key.
And I try to be as descriptive as possible with the Keys.
So NavigationButtonStyle, there's no mistaking what that is.
Here we're going to create a bunch of Setters,
and we'll set the Property and then
the Value and just like I've done before I'm going to copy
and paste a bunch of these cause I know I need them.
Don't know exactly how many.
Now here's what I'd like to do.
Because I need to look down here
and then make changes up here,
I use a feature Visual Studio, let's get rid of that,
this little icon in the upper right-hand corner
allows me to see two Panes with the same file.
So I'm still on the MainPage.xaml but I'm looking at
these two independent Panes.
So I can look at the bottom down here like that,
and then here at the top
I can do things like set the Background, and I love
that I get IntelliSense when I do this by the way.
That's nice.
Background Black.
HorizontalAlignment="Stretch".
And VerticalAlignment, and we'll set that to "Stretch".
And let's see, we'll do the BorderBrush,
and we'll set that equal to "Gray",
and then the BorderThickness
equal to that,
and I think that's all that I need to do right now.
Now what I'll do is grab all this, remove it,
and I'm going to set the Style equal to
that StaticResource, right?
And we're calling this NavigationButtonStyle
NavigationButtonStyle.
Now if I did this right, and I'm going to remove that,
nothing will change whenever I run the app.
Great. Looks right.
Now I do notice I still have some things I need to do here
with the innards of the Button on the Image itself.
And this might be an area where we can create another Style
because we're going to use this four times.
So let me
let me first get the margin right, correct, rather,
and let's go
Margin="0,0,10,0", maybe?
That should work, right? So let's try it.
Okay, that's better. Very good.
Now let's make a Style out of that.
So here we go, Style,
TargetType="Image"
and let's create the Key
to IconStyle?
Think that's good enough? ImageIconStyle?
IconImageStyle?
Naming things is hard. It's always hard.
The Setter and Property and the Value
and I think we'll need three things here.
So we're going to set the Height and Width,
set that to 20,
width, 20,
and then we're going to do that Margin thing
that we did a minute ago where we go
Margin="0,0,10,0".
I'm going to copy that, because I'll forget that name.
And we'll go Style="StaticResource"
and then the IconImageStyle.
I'm not going to do one for the TextBlock
with the text Donut in it.
There's just no reason for it, I mean,
we only have one property that we're setting there.
Let's make sure everything looks good before we now
copy and paste those Buttons three more times.
Okay. I like what it looks like.
One last thing that I need to do is I'm going to need,
well, let me just hold off on that.
Sorry, I'm getting ahead of myself here.
Okay. So I've got these Buttons looking pretty sharp.
I'm going to copy and paste
so I have one, two, three, four, this will be in Column 1,
Column 2, and Column 3.
Alright and so now we'll just change out each of these.
So instead of that, we'll go coffee-icon,
and the Text="Coffee".
Then I'm going to go schedule-icon
and the TextBlock will be Schedule, and then finally,
what was this, complete-icon,
and Complete.
Alright, I feel good about that.
Let's see what it looks like real quick.
Nice! Look at that!
See how efficient it can be whenever you
kind of get your act together and you
you create your Styles, and then you copy and paste things.
Alright, I tell you what, I'm going to stop right here
and I'm going to work on the navigation
part of this in the next video.
So we'll catch you there.