Hi, I'm Bob Tabor with www.LearnVisualStudio.NET.
In this lesson, we'll begin learning about the XAML syntax.
Honestly, it's pretty easy to figure out
the absolute basics of XAML, just by looking at it.
I mean, I can imagine that whatever you saw
in the previous lesson, you were at least able
to figure out the correlation between the tags,
the properties, and what you saw
in the visual designer, right?
Well, what I want to accomplish is to talk about
some of its features and functions
that may not be so obvious at first glance.
So we're going to take a couple of passes at this
in short videos that, when combined together,
will give us a pretty thorough understanding of XAML
and how it all works.
In this first lesson, we're going to talk about the purpose
and the nature of XAML, especially in comparison to C#.
Then in the next few lessons, we're going to talk about
the special features of XAML.
Little hidden features of the language that,
again, may not be obvious
when you first start looking at it.
So my aim is that, by the end of these first set of lessons,
you're going to have enough knowledge
that you can look at the XAML that we write together
in the remainder of this series,
and you're going to be able to take a pretty good guess
at what it's trying to do before I even explain
what it does.
All right, so first of all, let's talk about what XAML is.
In the previous lesson, I made a passing remark
about how XAML looks similar to HTML
and that's no accident.
XAML is really just XML, the EXtensible Markup Language.
I'm going to explain that relationship in just a moment,
but at a higher level, XML looks a lot like HTML
insomuch that they share a common ancestry.
Whereas HTML is specific to structuring a web page document,
XML is a little bit more generic in nature.
And by generic I mean that you can use it for any purpose
that you devise, and you can define the names
and the elements and the attributes to suit your needs.
Now in the past, developers have used XML
for things like storing application settings
or using it as a means of transferring data
between two systems that were never intended
to work together.
And to use XML, you start out by defining
what's called a schema, which declares the proper names
of the elements and their attributes.
And so a schema is kinda like a contract
that two parties agree to.
Everybody agrees, both the producer of the XML
and the consumer of the XML, to write and read
the XML, to conform to those rules set forth
in the contract, I mean, the schema.
And now that they both agree
that they're working in the same rules
and the same contract, they can communicate
with each other.
So a schema is a really important part of XML.
And just keep that in mind,
because we're going to come back to that in just a moment.
Now XAML is a special usage of XML.
Obviously we see, at least in this case,
XAML has something to do with defining a user interface
for our application.
So in that regard, it feels a lot like HTML,
but there's a big difference.
XAML is actually used to create instances of classes
and set values of their properties.
So, for example, in the previous lesson,
we created a little Hello World application.
I kind of expanded on that here,
just to give it a little more design.
I added a button.
And notice that I put all the attributes on separate lines
so now we can see, hopefully, the definition
a little bit better.
Let me actually make a little more room here.
We're going to rely less and less on the visual designer.
In fact, we may even start getting rid of it completely.
But you can see here that I've create a red button
called Click Me, and there's also a MessageTextBlock
that will appear below it.
So it's very much like what we did before,
I just started over from scratch.
And what I want to do is,
well, first of all, let's go ahead
and take a look at the code behind,
and we'll
set the TextBlock equal to
"What is XAML?", the topic of this lesson.
Whenever you click the button.
So let's run the application briefly.
Just to show that there's nothing up my sleeve.
And click it, and we get the result, great.
Okay, so now what I want to do,
just to demonstrate how XAML works
is to actually comment out this button control.
And I'll use the syntax that you would use
if you're familiar with HTML and how to comment out things.
It's just this open bracket, exclamation mark dash dash
to start the commented section.
And then to end the commented section,
you just do dash dash, closing angle bracket, like so.
And you can see that in Visual Studio's code editor
that it appears green by default.
Okay, so now that we've got rid of it,
what I'm going to do is actually come back over here.
Well, actually, a couple of things.
I already gave this a name,
but by default, whenever you create a new project,
the grid does not have a name.
I gave it the name LayoutGrid because that is
indicative of what it's actually doing for us.
And then the other thing that I want to do
is that whenever the page loads,
so I'm going to go find
the load, loaded event.
I'm going to create a new event handler called PageLoaded.
I'm going to use the F12 key on my keyboard,
pop that open in the code behind.
And so now I'm going to write code that will execute
whenever the page has loaded into memory.
And this is going to take me a little bit
and hopefully you'll see why and it will prove
what I'm trying to explain here.
So I might even just start this out
and then fast forward near the end of this typing exercise.
I don't recommend that you do this.
Okay, so it took me about two minutes to type all this out.
I'm not the slowest typist in the world,
but this is pretty thick typing and Intellisense helped a lot.
I made a few mistakes along the way.
But the point of this is,
if we actually run the application,
I want to show you what it does.
Hey, it created a red button almost identical,
in fact it is identical to the one that we defined in XAML.
And if we click it, it gives me the same result.
So the point that I'm making here is that it took
all of this C# code
to do what I was able to do
in basically just one line of code.
Now I spaced it out over several lines,
but you can see that the C# version of this
is much more verbose.
And then secondly, what we're really doing
when we're defining elements and attributes in XAML
is that we're creating new instances of classes
in the Universal Windows Platform API
and defining and setting their attributes,
their properties, just like we're doing here in this code.
Alright?
By the way, before I forget, if you want to follow along
and do this exercise yourself, I will add the,
I already have the before where we started out,
and I'll add this code that I just typed in as the after.
So you'll be able to get at this project.
"What is XAML?"
So the important takeaway is this;
that XAML is simply a way to create instances of classes
and set those objects' properties in a much more simplified,
succinct syntax.
What took us, what, 12 lines of code,
13 lines of code in C# only took one line of XAML,
even if I did separate it out.
It's still much shorter than it would have been
had I used C# to create all of my objects.
Furthermore, whenever I do use XAML,
I get this automatic feedback here
in the visual designer.
In the preview pane.
So I can see the impact of my changes instantly
if I choose to work like that.
So in the case of the procedural C# that I wrote,
I have to run the application each time that I wanted to see
how my tweaks to the code actually worked.
So, okay, that's it, that's the point of this lesson.
Twofold.
One that XAML's just a specific flavor of XML.
It follows all the rules of XML.
Somebody defines a schema, a contract,
and then both the producer and consumer of XML agree
to the contract, and then they can begin to work together
knowing that they're pretty much on the same page.
Now in this case, the contract is XAML
and it was defined by Microsoft.
The producer of the XML is you, me, in Visual Studio,
and then the consumer of the XML
is the compiler, which will turn our code in an executable
that will run in Windows 10.
And so that's the first point.
And the second point of this lesson
was that XAML is an easy way to create instances of classes
and set their properties.
And sure, you could do it all in C#,
but it's much more verbose and you would lose
the design-time tooling that we've become accustomed to
in here in two or three short videos.
Okay, so actually, this example that we just created
has a few other little interesting features of XAML
that I want to explain a little further.
So I'll start that process in the very next lesson.
Thank you.