Hi, I am Bob Tabor with www.learnvisualstudio.net.
In this lesson we will begin learning about the XAML syntax.
Honestly it's pretty easy to figure out the absolute basis of XAML just by looking at it.
I mean I can imagine that whatever you saw in the previous lesson
you were able to at least figure out the correlation between the tags,
the properties and what you saw in the visual designer, right?
Well what I want to accomplish is to talk about
some of the features and functions that may not be so obvious at the first glance.
So we will take a couple of parts at this short videos
that when combined together will give a pretty throughout understanding of XAML
and how it all works .
In this first lesson we are gonna talk about the purpose and the nature of XAML,
especially in comparison to C#.
Then the next few lessons
we are going to talk about the special features in XAML.
Little hidden features of the language that,
again, may not be obvious when you first start looking at it
So my aim is that by the end of the first several lessons
you're going to have enough knowledge that you can look at the XAML that we write together
and in the remainder of this series you are going to be able to take a pretty good guess of what it's trying to do
before I even explain what it does.
Alright, so first of all let's talk about what XAML is.
In the previous lesson I made a passing remark about
how XAML looks similar to HTML and that's no accidents.
XAML is really just XML, the eXtensible Markup Language.
I will explained that relationship in just a moment,
but at a higher level
XML looks a lot like HTML and so much that they share a common ancestry.
Whereas HTML is specific to structuring a web page document
XML a little bit more generic in nature
and by generic I mean that you can use it for any purpose that you decide
and you can define the names and the elements of the attributes to suit your needs
Now the past developers have used XML for things like storing application settings
or using it as a means of transferring data between two systems that were never intend to work together
And to use XML you start off by defining what's called the schema
which declares the proper names of the elements and their attributes
and so schema is kind of like a contract that two parties agreed to,everybody agrees
Both the producer of XML and the consumer of XML
to write and read the XML to conform to those rules set forth in the contract,I mean, the schema.
And now that they both agree
that they're working in the same rule of the same contract and communicate with each other
So, a schema is a really important part of XML
and just keep in mind 'cuz we will come back to that in just a moment
XAML is a special usage of XML
Obviously we see, at least in this case
XAML has something to do with defining a user interface for our for application
so now we got it feels a lot like HTML but there's a big difference
XAML is actually used to create instances of classes and set values of their properties.
So for example in the previous lesson we created a little hello world application
I can expand on that here just give it a little more design
I added a button and notice that I put all the attributes on separate lines and now we can see
hopefully the definition will look a bit better
I'm actually getting more room here
We are going to rely less and less on the visual designer
In fact we may start to get rid of it completely
but you can see here that I created a red button called "click me"
and there's also a MessageTextBlock that will appear below
So it's very much like what we did before,I am just starting over from scratch
what I want to do is well first of all let's...
let's go let's go ahead and take a look at the code behind
and we'll set the TextBlock equal to "What is XAML?"
the topic of this lesson, whenever you click the button
So let's run the application briefly
just to show that there is nothing up my sleeve
And click it and we get the result
Great, okay now what I want to do
just to demonstrate how XMAL works
is actually comment out this button control
and I'll use the syntax that you would use if you're familiar with HTML at how to comment out things
It's just this open bracket
*** mark, dash, dash
to start the comment section
And then to end the comment section you just do dash, dash,
closing angle bracket like so
and you can see that in Visual Studio code editor that it appears green by default
Okay, so now that we've got rid of it
what I'm gonna do is actually, come back over here
well actually a couple of things
I already gave this a name
but by default whenever you create a new project
the grid does not have a name
I gave it the name LayoutGrid Because that is *** what it is actually doing for us.
And then the other thing I want to do is whenever the page loads
so I'm going to find the Loaded event
I'm gonna create a new event handler call Page_Loaded
and use the F12 key on my keyboard to pop that open and the code behind
And so now I'm gonna write code
that will execute whenever the page has loaded in the memory
And this's going to take me a little bit
and hopefully you'll see why and it'll prove what I'm trying to explain here
So I might even just kind of start this out
and fast forward near the end of this typing exercise
I don't recommend that you do this
Okay so it took me about two mins to type all this out
I am not the slowest typist in the world
but this is pretty fit typing
and tell us how to not make a few mistakes along the way
but the point of this is if we actually run the application
I wanna show you what it does
Hey it created a red button
almost identical in fact is identical to the one that we defined in XAML
and if we click it it gives me the same results
So the point I'm making here is that
it took all of this C# code
to do what I was able to do in basically just one line of code
Now I spaced it out over several lines
but you can see that the C# version of this is much more verbose
And then secondly what we are really doing when we are defining elements and attribute in XAML
is that we're creating new instances of classes in the Universal Windows Platform API
and defining and setting their attributes and properties just like we're doing here in this code, alright
By the way, before I forget
if you want to follow along and do this exercise yourself
I will add the I already have the Before where we started out
and I'll add this code that I just typed in the After
so you'll be able to get in this project "WhatIsXAML"
So the important take away is this
that XAML is simply a way to create instances of classes
and set those objects properties in a much more simplified succinct syntax
(It) took us 12 lines of code, 13 lines of code C#
only took one line of XAML
Even if I did separated it out, it's still until much shorter than would have been had I use C# to create all of my object
Furthermore whenever I do use XAML
I get this automatic feedback here in the visual designer in the preview pane
So I can see the impact of my changes instantly if I choose to work like that
So in the case of the procedure C# that I wrote
I have to run the application each time that I wanted to see how my tweets to the code actually work
So okay that's it, that's the point of this lesson
Two fold, one that XAML is just a specific flavor of XML
It follows all the rules of XML
Somebody defines the schema
a contract, and then both the producer and consumer of the XML agree to the contract
and then they can begin to work together, konwing that they are pretty much on the same page
Now in this case, the contract is XAML and it was defined by Microsoft
the producer of the XML is you, me and visual studio
and then the consumer of the XML
is the compiler which will turn our code into an executable that will run in Windows 10
And so that's the first point
The second point of this lesson was that XAML is an easy way to create instances of classes and set the properties
and sure you can do this all in C#, but it's much more verbose
and you would lose the design time tooling that we've become accustom to in here, two or three short videos
Okay so actually this example that we just created
has a few other little interesting features of XAML that I want to explain a little bit further
and so I'll start that process in the very next lesson.
Thank you