All right, just a handful of finishing touches
and then we're going to move on.
Let me run the app real quick.
There's two things I want to do.
First of all, going to get rid of the button,
going to make sure that everything is nice and centered,
which it's not so we'll fix that.
And I guess three things,
I'm going to add some exception handling as well.
So let's go to the MainPage.xaml.
This will all be really just quick and easy honestly.
There's a little TextBlock,
I'm going to put that there.
And let's quick change the font.
FontSize equals,
oh, I don't know, 36.
That should be sufficient.
Foreground="white".
That should look good.
I might even break that up into multiple lines
so let me see how that looks before I get too far here.
We're going to get rid of the button
and I think what
we're going to do also is
VerticalAlignment="Center".
Let's see how that works.
And then HorizontalAlignment="Center"
on the image and the text.
Then, on the MainPage.xaml,
actually let's go back to MainPage.
I'm going to go Page, add a load--
Loaded event handler.
And inside there, I'm going to take everything
inside that click button and move it
like so.
And we'll have to add async keyword,
And we'll get rid of the Button_Click event.
So this will just load up as soon as we load the app.
All right, so let's take a look at the changes now
and just make sure everything looks good.
There are one or two more things I want to do though.
Whoa, that's not what I had in mind whatsoever.
Okay, all right, so clearly got one thing
I need to do there.
Let's wrap another StackPanel
inside of that StackPanel.
Okay, we got that going for us.
And we're going to make the background
of the outermost StackPanel pink.
All right, why aren't you happy?
Oh, that's why.
Okay, all right, that's good.
That should fix that problem.
Let's see where we have ourselves now.
Okay, ideally I'd put these on separate lines.
Let's go ahead and do that.
So there is the location, the temp, and the description.
So let's do this.
Location, actually let's go Temp,
Description, and then Location.
I like that better.
Temp will be the largest.
We'll put this at like, I don't know, 52.
The Description, yeah, 36 is good there.
And then the Location.
We'll make that smaller, 24.
All right, and so Temp, Description, Location.
Where are we here? Yeah.
TempTextBlock.Text =,
Description, Text
and LocationTextBlock.
Great, okay, so let's grab the Location off,
stick that there,
grab the Temp off
and we'll stick that here.
And finally, we'll take this
and, whoops, put that there
and this, the Temp, here.
Great and get rid of that.
Okay, one other thing that I want to do.
So structure exception handling,
you always want to wrap any call with a
try-catch statement any time you're calling out to something
you don't control.
So if it's something you control in your own source code,
that is up to you.
But if you're going to make a call to a network,
to a database, to a web service,
to something you do not control,
to the file system, you want to wrap it with a try-catch.
Typically you only want to wrap try-catch around
those things not just entire blocks of code.
So you want to be very deliberate and specific
with what you're wrapping try-catches around.
Typically.
In this case, if we get an error in one spot,
the whole thing is going to fall down like a house of cards.
So in that case, what I'm going to do
is just wrap the entire code passage
with a try.
Now I could be a little bit more
careful with what gets wrapped and what gets reported
but honestly I'm just going to do this.
I'm going to take this and in that Location
I'm just going to say,
"Unable to get weather at this time."
something like that.
And so here's what I'm going to do.
I'm going to set up a break point on the try statement
and then when I hit that I'm going to force it go
to that line just so I can see what it looks like by itself.
All right, so let's right click and say
Set as the Next Statement.
All right, well, pooh, on me.
All right, we'll force this issue.
We'll go and do it like this instead.
I just want to see what it looks like when we can't get...
All right, let's do this.
Let's get rid of that.
I'm just going to comment everything out.
I just want to see what this will look like
with just that text in it.
I probably need to add the wrapping.
No, that should do it.
Let's see what it looks like here
whenever we see it in our phone.
Yeah, I need to wrap a little bit there.
All right, no problem.
So we'll turn on wrapping,
equals Wrap
Do it again.
Okay, it's not pretty.
I could work a little bit more on this
and make it look better but for my purposes right now,
it's just fine.
Now let me go ahead and take the gloves off
and let me run it,
the whole code on the phone emulator.
Yes.
All right, I'm surprised that this is not lower.
Well, let me think about this one second here.
Did we not set VerticalAlignment="Center"? Hmm.
That surprises me a little bit.
But honestly it's just fine the way that it is.
Okay, I'm going to go ahead and stop right now.
And again, if you wanted to go and improve this,
let me give you one little assignment.
I'm not going to show you how to solve this,
but what would be great if, in addition to right now,
the current weather conditions,
you were able to see for the next seven days.
You can get that through the open OpenWeatherMap API.
And you've already got the icons, just make them smaller,
just put them up for the next seven days.
Figure out how to do that.
That would be a nice little addition to this.
You can improve some of the exception handling,
maybe add some options to change the background color
from hot pink to whatever you want it to be.
So those were all things I'm just going to
let you do on your own.
Take this, run with it, it's yours.
And now we're going to move on to the next one.
All right, so great, we're doing awesome.
We'll see you in the next lesson.
Thanks.