Hi, I'm Bob Tabor with www.LearnVisualStudio.NET.
In this lesson, I want to begin talking about layout,
or rather, the process of positioning visual controls
and other elements on your application's user interface.
And there are several different XAML controls
that exist for the purpose of layout,
and we'll cover most of the popular ones
in this series of lessons.
Now in the past, layout was relatively simple.
After all, you were typically only laying out
an application for a single form factor,
a single device like a phone or a desktop application.
However, there are a few new wrinkles
introduced as we begin to build applications
that can adaptively resize based on the device
that we run our app on.
And this is one of the new key features in app development
on the Windows platform.
We'll start with the easy stuff in this lesson,
then we'll build up to the more challenging stuff
in the following lessons.
Now before we begin, I want to point out one thing
regarding all XAML controls that are intended
for the purpose of layout.
Most controls have a content property,
so your button control has a content property, for example.
And the content property can only be set
to an instance of another object.
So in other words, I can put a TextBlock,
and let me just copy and paste some code here
into what I've got.
I can create here a Button
with a Content property set to a TextBlock,
but then I also have added an Image inside
of that Button control as well.
So whenever I attempt to put more than one control
inside of the Content property,
I get this error, and if I hover over it,
it says: The property "Content" can only be set once.
However, layout controls are intended to host
more than one control.
And so as a result, they do not have a Content property.
Instead, they usually have a Children property
that is of a special data type, a collection data type
that can hold XAML controls called UIElementCollection.
In XAML, as we add new instances of controls
inside of the definition of our layout control,
we're actually calling the Add method
of our layout control's UIElementCollection,
or rather, just the collection property.
So here again, XAML hides a lot of the complexity for us
and makes our code very concise
by inferring our intent by how we write our XAML.
Alright, so we're going to begin in this lesson
looking at the Grid control.
Like any grid, it allows you to define both rows and columns
to create cells.
And then each of the controls that are used
by your application can request which row and which column
that they want to be placed inside of.
So whenever you create a new app
using the blank app template,
you're provided very little guidance,
as you saw here a moment ago,
let me just get rid of that,
that's pretty much all you are given to get started.
You get a single empty Grid
with no rows or no columns defined.
However by default, there is always one row definition
and one column definition,
even if it is not explicitly defined in your XAML.
And these take up the full vertical and horizontal space
available to represent one large cell in the grid.
Now any items that are placed between
that opening and closing Grid element
are understood to be inside of that single,
implicitly defined cell.
So I'm going to create a quick example of a grid
that defines two rows, just to illustrate two primary ways
of creating rows and setting their heights.
And so actually, I have already taken the opportunity
to create this.
I'm going to go to a project called Row Definition.
You should be able to open this up and follow along.
Or you can just pause the video and type this in as well.
So here you can see that I want you to notice
that I have two rectangles.
There is an upper rectangle and a lower rectangle.
And those are defined through a series
of RowDefinition objects here.
So you can see that I have, inside of the grid,
I have this property element syntax to define
a collection of RowDefinitions with instances
of RowDefinition created with their height property set.
And here, the first one has its Height property set to Auto
and its second row definition object has its height
set to star (*).
And then we have two rectangle objects,
and notice that here, we're setting the row
that this rectangle object wants to put itself inside of.
It wants to put itself inside of the row zero,
so we can see that this is the first row, row zero,
so it's zero based,
and then the second rectangle wants to put itself
inside of the Grid.Row="1"
so it puts itself here in this row.
So the first thing to notice is how the rectangles
are putting themselves into the various grid rows,
and then also how you reference both rows and columns
using a zero-based numbering scheme like we saw here.
Now the second thing that I want you to notice
is this weird syntax: Grid.Row
Grid.Row, and we'll also be setting Grid.Column
in another example here.
And these are called "Attached Properties".
Attach properties enable an object,
in this case, a rectangle, to assign a value for a property
in this case, the row property,
(but it could apply to the column property as well),
to assign a value for a property
that its own class structure does not define.
So nowhere in the Rectangle definition is there a
Grid.Row property, or even a Row property.
These are all defined inside of the Grid object.
Now the reason why Attached Properties exist
is really an advanced XAML topic that is not actionable
at this point in your introduction to XAML.
So I'm going to skip that topic.
If you want to get deeper into the internals of XAML,
then you should search MSDN for articles
about both Attached Properties, as well as
the loosely related topic of Dependency Properties.
But in a nutshell, Attached Properties
keep your XAML simple.
Let's just leave it at that, and then you can go off
and explore that topic a little bit on your own later on.
So the third thing that I want you to notice
about this example are the two different row heights.
The first height, we set to Auto; and the second row height,
we set to star (*).
There are three syntaxes that you can use
to help persuade the sizing for each row and each column.
I use the term "persuade" intentionally.
With XAML layout, heights and widths are relative
and can be influenced by a number of different factors.
All these factors are considered by the layout engine
at run time to determine the actual placement
of items on your given page, or your screen.
So for example, this term, Auto,
means that the height for the row
should be tall enough to accommodate all of the controls
that are placed inside of that row.
If the tallest control, in this case,
you can see this rectangle, has its height
explicitly set to 100 pixels,
if the tallest item is 100 pixels tall,
then that's the actual height of the row, 100 pixels.
If we were to change this to 50 pixels,
you can see that the height of the row changes
now to be half the height to 50 instead.
Let's change it back to 100.
So therefore, auto means that the height is relative
to the controls that are inside of that given row or column,
or whatever the case might be.
Secondly, you see this asterisk,
it's also known as "star sizing", and it means
that the height of the row should take up
all of the rest of the available height available.
So here is a quick example of another way
to use star sizing.
I created a project that has three rows
in the content panel.
Here, let me get to star sizing. Great.
Bring it down here.
So again, you can see that we have three rows
that are defined.
Let me just get down here like so.
Notice the heights of each one of them.
Putting a number before the asterisk,
I am saying of all the available space,
give me one share of all the available space,
or two shares of all the available space.
Or in this case, three shares of all of the available space.
So the sum of all of those rows adds up to six.
So each one star is equivalent to 1/6th
of the height that is currently available.
So therefore, three star would get half of the height
that is available as depicted in the output of this example.
As you can see, it gets half of the available height.
I also want you to notice, off to the left-hand side,
that there are some visual tools that we can use
to change the sizing.
So for example, I can change from star sizing to auto,
or to pixel.
I can also just type in the given value here,
and that would set the height property
in this particular case.
Besides auto and star sizing, you can also specify
widths and heights, as well as margins in terms of pixels.
So in fact, when only numbers are present,
it represents that number of pixels
for the width or the height.
Now generally, it is not a good idea to use exact pixels
in layouts for widths and heights
because of the likelihood that various screens
will be larger or smaller, so there are
several different types of phones
or several different form factors for tablets and desktops,
things of that nature, and so you do not want
to specify exact numbers or else
it is not going to look correct on a different form factor.
Instead, it is preferable to use relative layouts
like auto and star sizing for layout.
Now the one other thing that I want you to notice
from this example is that the XAML control,
widths and heights, are assumed to be 100%
unless otherwise specified, especially for rectangles.
And that's pretty much true for many different controls,
not all controls, like the button control is not
treated this way, but a rectangle, an image control,
these are all assumed to be 100% of whatever space
that is available, width and height.
I also want to point out that a grid can have a collection
of column definitions.
And what I want to do is show you another example here.
And so here you can see that we have a 3 x 3 grid,
three row definitions and then we see that we're also,
with property elements syntax,
defining a ColumnDefinitions collection that contains
three columns.
Furthermore, you can see that I put a TextBlock
inside of each one of the cells.
Now unfortunately, you cannot see the numbers here
on the designer.
It is not representing them correctly,
but if we were to run the application,
you would be able to see that we get a different number
in each cell.
We'll make that smaller, you can see one through nine, okay?
And one of the things I want you to notice, for example,
in this very first cell in the upper left-hand corner
is that I am not setting a row,
nor am I setting a column.
And so by default, if you do not supply that information,
it is assumed to be zero.
So we're assuming that we're putting this particular
TextBlock in row zero, column zero.
Furthermore, if you take a look at this next TextBlock,
I am setting the grid column equal to one,
but I'm not setting the row,
meaning that I am assuming that to be zero.
And I do that here several times throughout this example.
So relying on defaults keeps your code, again,
more concise, but you have to understand
that there is a convention being used here.
All right, I have another example that I want to show you
called AlignmentAndMargins.
Here, let's bring this down.
Most of these examples should be pretty obvious
if you stare at it for a few moments,
but there are several finer distinctions
that I want to make about alignments and margins.
First of all, this example illustrates
how VerticalAlignment and HorizontalAlignment work
even in a given grid cell.
And this will hold true in a stack panel as well,
when we talk about it in the next lesson.
The Vertical or HorizontalAlignment property attributes
pull controls towards their boundaries.
So by contrast, the margin attributes push controls
away from their boundaries.
So in this case here, you can see that,
the HorizontalAlignment, we're pulling this blue rectangle
towards the left hand side,
and we're pulling it towards the top hand side, okay?
However, if we take a look at an example
that has some margins defined, here at the very bottom,
this white one.
So here again, we are pulling the HorizontalAlignment
towards the left, and we're pulling the VerticalAlignment
towards the bottom.
And then we're setting the margins equal to 50, 0, 0 and 50.
So you can see that the margin will now push
the rectangle away from the left-hand boundary by 50.
So you can see here that we get that
little spacing on the left-hand side,
and the margin is pushing the white rectangle
away from the bottom boundary by 50 pixels as well.
Now the second observation that I want to make
is the odd way in which margins are defined.
And we already talked about this,
so I'm not going to harp on this in this lesson.
Margins are represented as a series of numeric values
that are separated by commas.
And this convention was borrowed
from Cascading Style Sheets.
So the numbers represent the margin pixel values
in a clockwise fashion, starting at the left-hand side.
So in this case, left, top, right to bottom, alright?
A bit earlier, I said that it is generally a better idea
to use relative sizes like auto or star sizing
whenever you want to define heights and widths.
So why is it then that margins are defined in exact pixels?
Well, usually, margins are just small values
to provide spacing or padding between two relative values
and so they can be fixed without negatively impacting
the overall layout of the page.
I mean, if you want a small amount of spacing
between two rectangles, 50 pixels will be enough
whether you have a large or a smaller size.
And if it is not, then you can change it
through other techniques that we'll demonstrate later on
in this series.
So let us recap what we have talked about so far.
In this lesson, we've talked about layout controls
and how they allow you to define areas of your application
where other visual XAML controls will be hosted.
In this lesson, we specifically learned about the grid
and how to define columns and rows,
how to define their relative sizes using star and auto,
and then how to specify which row and column
a given control would request to be inside of
by setting Attached Properties, Grid.Row, Grid.Column,
on that given item like a Rectangle in this particular case
or whatever it might be.
We also talked about how to set the alignment
and the margins of those controls inside of a given cell
and more.
So grids are great, but they're really just one tool.
You're going to likely use them
along with other layout controls like the StackPanel,
which we're going to learn about in the very next lesson.
So we'll see you there.
Thank you.