So the next feature that I would
like to add is to drag and drop
a sound from the desktop onto our
design surface, our app's GridView
and have it play that sound.
What I set out to do was to create
a little scratch pad application,
I frequently do this, to help me
understand how to get drag and drop working
and once I understood that then
my plan was to apply it,
add it to the larger application.
This helps me to isolate just the feature
or the idea that I don't quite understand,
wrap my brain around it,
try variants, understand what my options are
and then once I'm done experimenting
and I have it pretty full-fledged,
then I can apply that to the larger project.
What I set out to do was create
a little app, you'll have access
to this drag and drop example.
You can see it's very, very, simple
but it does illustrate some important ideas.
As we launch the app here,
the idea is that we have a StackPanel,
this red area here and I can
drag and drop an item off of my desktop
on to this red area and that it will either
display and image or play the sound
and it will also allow me to copy
that file from the desktop to a working
folder that is available to my application
on the user's device or computer
and that's called the working folder or local folder.
For example, if I drag and drop
this image control on to that red area,
you can see that I'm displaying it now
in an ImageControl in my application.
Also notice that here is this location
where I copy that file to the local
storage container for this application
and I'm just going to Control+A,
Control+C, to copy the location and then
open up File Explorer and paste it in.
You can see that as I, you navigate
through all the various folders
and everything to get to it.
It's copied this image and actually
since I've done this several times
it copied the image several times.
Let me actually just delete all of this out
and then do this again.
I'll just redo that same image.
Drag and drop and you can see
by dragging it into my app,
it copied it over to the local storage area
and then used that local copy
to display it in my image.
Same thing would be true with the song file.
Here I'm going to drag and drop the sound,
the MP3 file (music plays) and it will start playing.
Here I'm playing nine seconds
and I fade out the sound after a few seconds.
And I'll show you how I do that as well
here in this little example app.
There's a couple of things to notice first of all.
Let's look at the XAML to begin with.
Here I have a StackPanel then I have
that image where I display
the dragged image and in the media element
where I play music.
Then there's that TextBox at the bottom
where I actually display the full URI
for that private local...
local storage area.
Now inside of the StackPanel,
this inner StackPanel, I've actually added
two properties, actually three.
The first one is important: AllowDrop.
If you don't set this property,
drag and drop won't work.
Doesn't matter if you have everything else working.
We have to set that equal to "True"
and then we have the Drop EventHandler
set to StackPanel_Drop and the DragOver
set to StackPanel_DragOver.
These two are crucial, one for what happens
as we're dragging the file over
and you saw as we were dragging,
we showed a little bit of a hint
at the bottom which said, "Drop here
"in order to play that sound."
Then the Drop will actually perform,
it will grab the file, copy it into local storage,
use that storage area to either
display or play it.
Let's look at the code behind where
this actually all happens.
In the MainPage.xaml.cs
Let's first of all take a look at
the DragOver and the DragOver,
all I'm doing here is saying,
treat this like a copy operation
and so it's as if I were going to copy this file.
That's the accepted operation
and then I start setting attributes
of the DragUIOverrideObject
on our DragEventArgs e.
Here I'm able to set the caption,
I'm also saying, make the caption visible,
make the content of the file
itself visible so in the case of an image
you'd be able to see the image file
and then is a Glyph visible and I think
the Glyph is for the little icons.
In the case of a copy operation,
it would just have two little files
sitting on top of each other.
Let's notice that behavior as we
drag the image on top of that red StackPanel.
You can still see the image
and you see that little helper message,
Drop to create a custom sound.
And then also, the little Glyph
off to the left-hand side and I drop it
and you can see that part working.
That's the DragOver part of it.
Let's look at the Drop part.
The first thing we want to do is make sure
that what's being dragged over and dropped
is actually a file.
These are storage items, not just fragments
of text or something else from another
application that's being dragged over.
If that DataView of what's been dragged
into our StackPanel is something
that is a StorageItem, a file based
drag operation, then we can proceed on.
Then go ahead and get a reference
to all of those items.
If more than one has been selected
then let's get a reference to all of them.
Now we're only going to work with one item
so you can see here that making sure
that there are items actually in that...
drag operation that are StorageItems,
then we're going to be able to say hey,
give me the first item at index zero
and we'll make sure to pull off
the ContentType so is it an image file,
a sound file, a document,
whatever the case might be.
Here we get a reference to that local folder
so that local storage area that our application
will be allocated whenever it's installed on our device.
We just then display that in that PathTextBox.
Now we're going to check the contentType.
It's either going to be an image/png,
image/jpeg in which case we're
dealing with an image and we want
to display that in the ImageControl
or it's going to be audio/wav or audio/mpeg
in which case we want to tell our
media player to go ahead and play that file.
What we do first of all is actually copy that file
into our local storage area.
That's what this line of code does
on line number 50.
Here's the folder, here's the file name.
If there's all ready a file with that file name
then generate a unique name.
Now we have a reference to that file.
We're going to create a bitmapImage
and say the Source of that bitmapImage
is that new file and then we set that
as the Source to the ImageControl in our XAML.
Now with the audio we do things slightly different.
Still almost an identical line of code,
line 57 and line 50.
Here we are taking that file that was
dropped into the StackPanel
and we're going to save that in
a local storage, that's what line 57 does.
Then we want to, on the MediaPlayer,
set the Source to that file that we copied
into our local storage and at this point then,
you'll notice the different sort of line of code.
We're going to do something a little bit different
in our actual app.
I was trying something to see how it would work.
Here I'm calling the MediaPlayerStoryboard.Begin().
If you take a look here in our MainPage.xaml,
I've created a Storyboard.
A Storyboard allows you to define an Animation.
Before you think you know what
an Animation is, let me say that in XAML
it's a little bit different.
An Animation is anything that we want
to be able to change the value of over time.
If you have an attribute of an object
and you say I want to at 1/2 a second
or five seconds in I want the attributes
to be changed to this value,
three more seconds I want it to be
changed to this value and then
10 more seconds I want it to be
changed to that value.
So in our case, we're not going to animate
the position on an X-Y axis like
you would do in a traditional Animation
but instead we're going to control the volume
and we do that here in the StoryBoard
that I created called MediaPlayerStoryboard.
And I'm saying, the TargetProperty
that we're going to change is
the MediaElement.Volume.
The object that we're going to change
is the MediaPlayer.
That MediaPlayer defined right here.
What we'll do is at key moments in time,
so these key frames, this KeyTime
of zero seconds, two seconds, nine seconds,
we're going to modify the volume to different values.
In fact, what I'm going to do here
is actually bring this all the way up to 1.0
and I'll let it go for six seconds and then,
on the seventh second, I'm sorry,
that should be...
let's see, at two seconds
we'll get it up to volume 1.0.
At six seconds, then we'll...
still have it at 1.0 and then it will
from six to nine, go to value 0.
Sorry, I confused myself there a little bit.
Let's go ahead and see if this actually works.
It will be difficult to ascertain through
audio on my computer but if you rerun
this application and you listen closely
to a sound that you drag in that's
at least nine seconds long,
you'll hear how this works.
And again, this is not a feature that
we're going to use in this lesson
but when we get to a future lesson
where we want to nicely,
instead of abruptly end a sound
we want to, over a second period of time,
phase it off, have it trail off.
It's a nice little touch that it sounds
better to the ear than just an abrupt stop.
Here I'm going to drag in the song.
It's going to start out at 1/2 volume
and build to full volume within
the first two seconds.
(music plays)
And then it's going to go along for six seconds
and then it starts to fade out
from seconds six through nine.
That's how that works.
Now that I have this working
and I kind of understand what it does,
I'm going to apply that to my larger project.
I'm going to get this actually up out of the way
but I'm going to use it as a reference here
in just a moment.
Here we are back at our MainPage.xaml
and what I would like to do is go
to my GridView control so whenever
I drag and drop a song on to my GridView,
it will just play it.
I'm not going to give it an icon.
I'm not going to store it persistent long term.
That would be a great project
for you to work on yourself to be able
to just drag items, have it save
to that local storage area and then
represent that data from that point on
every time the user opens the application
from that point on subsequently.
But that's not something I'm going
to demonstrate how to do here.
That would probably be a better
full featured app though.
One thing I want to do is set
the AllowDrop="True".
Without that we're not going to get
satisfaction of this working.
I'm going to handle the Drop event
and I'm going to handle the DragOver event as well.
With that in place, now I'm going
to hit F12 on the keyboard with my mouse
selecting SoundGridView_Drop
and here what I going to do is...
I'm going to go and copy verbatim
everything that I had in that previous project
and I'll strip out the things that don't
really apply and add things that do.
I think we're good to go there.
I know I'm not going to use
the MediaPlayerStoryboard so I'm just
going to go ahead and get rid of this.
Another thing I didn't talk about
was creating a marker and you can see,
I have that all commented out.
I'm going to go ahead and remove it from this.
A marker just allows you to say "Hey,
"in this position in this audio file I want
"to set a marker and you can label the marker
"and you can have an event fire whenever
"playback happens and that marker is reached."
So the idea is that I can do an annotation of a video.
Three seconds in I might want to pop-up
a TextBlock that has some messaging
and then it'll continue to play on
and then I'll pop-up something different.
It allows us to do a closed-captioning style system.
There's a lot of options there, really cool.
But we're not going to work with markers
but you can see how I used that application
as a scratch pad to learn more about
how the MediaElement actually works.
I'm actually going to change this
to MyMediaElement, the name of
the MediaElement.
I got lots of unresolved references
so I'm going to hit Control+"." on my keyboard.
It looks like the issue here however,
is that we don't have the async keyword.
So again, this is not a topic that I want
to talk about in this series.
I do talk about it in the 8.1 series.
I believe the 8.0 series as well.
Whenever you see the await keyword
or the async keyword like I just used here
in the method signature,
you're essentially saying that I have
a method that could be long-running in nature.
Instead of allowing that long-running method
to block the ongoing operation
of all the other code beneath
the current line that I'm on,
that I'm calling out to that method,
I'm going to say, go off and do your thing
and I'm going to continue running
until I can't go any further and when
you are finished, let me know that you're done
and I'll make everything work together magically.
There are two different ways to introduce
asynchrony into your applications
based on the two different types
of blocking that there are.
There's blocking because an operation
is mathematically intensive and then
there's blocking because the operation
is not mathematically or computationally intensive
but instead because there's just lag time.
For example, I make a request over the internet,
without any async or await keywords
introduced into my application,
my app would wait right there
for two seconds, five seconds, ten seconds
and could perform nothing else,
it would be completely unresponsive
to any additional user input,
any changes in the user interface until
a response came back from a remote web server.
There's not a lot of computational time
being spent there it's just waiting lag time.
Async and await allow you to just
handle those situations where we're not
computationally intensive, we're just
waiting on something to finish.
Beyond explaining it like that,
I don't want to go into it any deeper
but you'll see this frequently.
Any time in the Universal Windows Platform API,
there's an operation that could potentially
take a long time.
To a computer 1/2 a second, one second,
that's a long time.
Any time that you see any operations
that might take a while because
there's latency in access to a disk,
to a network, whatever, you'll see
the need to apply and adorn that method
with the await and async keywords.
Hopefully that's helpful enough.
The only thing you need to know
is that if you see an await keyword
in your code, you know that you're
going to need an async method in the call.
Furthermore, if you get any methods
that have the keyword async,
like we're calling in to this UWP/API methods
called GetStorageItemsAsync.
Async is going to require you to adorn
that call with an await keyword
to add an async keyword to the method.
You learn a lot more about async and await
and asynchrony in other channel nine videos,
even on my own web site
but that's all I'm going to say about it for now.
Let's continue on here.
We're resolving references in the code
that we copied in.
For example, the BitmapImage I need
to hit Control+"." on my keyboard,
add the using statement Windows.UI.Xaml.Media.Imaging
and that should resolve that reference.
Well and that's funny because I don't even
need that whole section,
we're only dealing with the audio.
We'll just get rid of that like that.
Here we don't need the PathTextBox,
we can get rid of that.
I actually need one more of these.
StorageFolder, ApplicationData,
these area all items that you'd probably
need to add using statements for if you're
trying to follow along with me as
I'm going through this.
I think that will pretty much do
what we need it to do here with one exception.
We're not going to use the storyboard
so I'm just going to call my MediaElement.Play()
instead and that will just play
the song straight out.
Now we need the DragOver code
and once again, I'm going to come over here
and I'm going to copy all of the code...
that I had and you can see that
I actually added some comments here
about an article where you can learn more
about how to do this
drag and drop operation and add...
a Drag Adorner which would allow you
to put a custom image as your dragging.
I'm not going to obviously going
to do any of that so I'm just going
to rip all that out like so.
I have here that it's using
Windows.ApplicationModel.DataTransfer
for that keyword.
I'm just going to rip that out as well.
Now with any luck this will actually work.
Let's make sure the cow works (cow moos).
Now I'm going to drag and drop that song.
(music plays) It works.
What happens if we were to drag a different
sound like one of these that we all ready have?
(crash sound)
(laughs) An abrupt ending to the song (laughs)
Let's see what happens when we drag an image.
Nothing, it just ignores it okay? Very good.
Now the real question is what would
happen if we attempted to run this in mobile
because we can't drag and drop with mobile right?
We haven't really tested this at all anyway.
Let's just do something real quick here.
(gun shot)
We can hear it but there's nothing
really to drag and drop into here.
It just ignores that functionality
in this particular case.
That's pretty cool.
A neat little addition to our app
to make it a true soundboard
to drag and drop and have it play automatically.
I know we could probably just double click
on a given item and have it pop open
and groove music unless Windows 10
disagrees with that idea.
However, again, this is just really for the purpose
of showing how this functionality,
how we can add it to our app.
It's pretty cool. Let's continue on.
We've got some finishing touches.
I'd like to implement the AutoSearchBox
in the next lesson and just a little bit
of general cleanup and then we'll be
looking to start getting this ready
for submission into the Windows Store.
Doing great, we'll see you in the next lesson. Thanks.