Alright, so next step, we're going to think about ways
that we can monetize our app,
and there's two obvious ways to do this,
very low-friction ways to get our app into people's hands
and make money every time that they use it
even if they don't pay for it,
but then also for those people
that really hate advertisements,
we're going to allow them to upgrade to a "pro" version,
(chuckles) I guess you could say, and remove the ads.
In order to get started with this, take a look
at this URL that you see on screen right now.
That'll take you to the,
let's see here, to this page,
where you can learn more about how to add
ads in your apps, and you can get the SDK
for Windows 10, it also works for the other versions, too,
but we're basically just going to click Install the SDK,
that'll take us to the Visual Studio Gallery
where we can download the Windows Ad Mediation Extension.
Now I've already downloaded this onto my desktop,
and you can see it right here.
And the first thing you should do before running this
is actually close down all of your Visual Studio instances,
then run this, and then you can open up Visual Studio again.
Because it is an extension to Visual Studio.
So I've already gone through that.
It's a very simple, just a normal Windows installer,
nothing really all that fancy there.
I'm not going to walk through it.
It's pretty simple, not a lot of options.
And then I'm going to create, just to demonstrate
how it works, I'm going to create
a new project called AdExample.
I've done absolutely nothing to this.
So I'm going to go ahead and remove the frame counter,
cause I like to get rid of that, as you know,
and the first thing that I'm going to do, and let me
pull this way over to the side here so you can see this.
I'm going to right-click on the project,
and, unfortunately, it pops up off the top of the screen.
But I'm going to select Add, Connected Service.
Here, let me see if I can get this.
Let me try to pull this off
right around here, and right-click.
Pull it down here.
Right-click, select Add, Connected Service, like so.
And you should see the Ad Mediator
in this list of Connected Services.
If you don't, then try shutting down Visual Studio,
re-opening, try re-booting, try re-installing
that MSI that you just downloaded.
I'm going to go ahead and click Configure, and
it says "this extension enables plug and play
"of third-party ad network solutions."
We can Select ad networks.
We only have one set up for ourselves.
We'll talk about ad networks in just a little bit.
If you click OK you're going to get this little message
that you couldn't add all the required references,
that's just fine, let's not worry about that.
But I am going to hit the Add
and there won't be a lot that happens
that you can see in the project,
but I'll show you what really does happen here
in just a moment as we move this back.
What we really accomplished with that was
whenever we open up the MainPage.xaml,
and then we go, once the designer loads,
we go to the Toolbox, you'll see
that there are two new sections in the Toolbox,
one called AdMediator, and then AdMediator Universal.
This is the one that you want, just forget the first one.
You want the one with the Universal name.
And there's an AdMediatorControl
in that section called AdMediator Universal.
You're going to drag and drop that onto your designer surface.
You have to drag and drop onto the designer surface,
not directly into your XAML like I've done in the past.
You'll get this message that this reference
has been added to the project.
"In order to use types from this new reference,
"press OK to restart the XAML Designer,"
then "re-create the control on the artboard."
So we'll do that, and then I'm going to
go ahead and click Build Solution,
make sure it still builds.
Alright, and it does.
And now I'm going to go back to the Toolbox
and I'm going to re-add that same AdMediatorControl
by dragging and dropping it from the AdMediator Universal
section of the Toolbox onto my designer surface.
And this time you'll see that it adds
a couple of things here, let me go ahead and go up here.
It adds a new namespace, and it adds a control
that accesses that namespace.
And let me go ahead and just separate these
on individual lines here.
Alright, there we go.
So what we have is a control with a special name,
undoubtedly the name of your control
will be different than mine.
You're going to have an ID and undoubtedly
this ID will be different than mine, as well.
These are just randomly generated,
and these are going to be just for development purposes anyway.
When you go and register your app with the store,
as we'll show in just a moment,
you're going to get a permanent one and it will
actually replace all of this for you,
you won't have to worry about that process.
Now that we've done that, let's go ahead and
go back to what we did before by right-clicking
and selecting Add, Connected Service,
you could see it barely off in the
upper right-hand corner when I did that.
So we're back to the screen, and we're going to click
Configure this time, and you'll see this message that
"your project changed and AdMediator.config will be updated.
"For more information, see the ad mediation documentation."
And it shows what will be added to that
AdMediator.config file, that's great.
Now you should see references are fetched,
and you can click Add to that,
and, again, I'm going to go ahead and build a solution.
You have to take those exact steps
or you're not going to get it to work,
I have found painfully as I have spent
more than a day working with this.
When I run the app, it takes a moment here,
but if I wait for a few seconds here, you'll see a little
placeholder ad for MSN pop up on my screen.
So I know that I did this right.
Very cool.
At this point, what I would need to do is to go into
go into my dashboard area and
if I haven't already done this, I'm going to need to create
a new entry for my new app.
And if you take a look at
the App overview for this new app,
you want to make sure to
go to Submissions, and you can see that
I'm currently in progress in a submission,
and one of the first things I'm going to need to do
is make a change to the App properties,
and I need to, at a minimum, give it the category
and the subcategory, which I just selected
as Education, Instructional Tools.
It doesn't matter what you've chosen there.
But then save that, and now go back
to App overview, and if you scroll down,
you'll see something for Ad mediation,
and you should be able to start
configuring ad mediation now.
And you can choose what ad networks
that you're going to serve up,
and you can even create Microsoft Advertising Ad Units,
which is something that you're going to need to do
at some point, whenever you go to submit your application.
As you can see, I've already created
one ad unit name and gotten an application ID.
It'll be a banner ad for the PC/Tablet.
And so this will be utilized
inside of the settings for my app.
Now let's talk about
the different types of ads that
we can create for our application.
If you take a look at that URL,
that'll take you to a document in the Windows Dev Center
called "select and manage your ad networks."
And there's a bunch of ad networks
that are partially supported
by this ad SDK.
As you can see, the Windows Universal Platform,
they're still, the ad networks are still coming online.
It's mostly supported in some of the
oldest versions of the Windows Phone
and Windows 8.1,
but at any rate, you can decide to have multiple ad networks
and just iterate through
each of the ad networks that you want to use.
Now again, only Microsoft Advertising
is supported currently for the
Universal Windows Platform version that we're using.
But if you scroll down you can see that,
here are some more details about including
Microsoft Advertising network into your application,
and what's required, and how you get
the Application ID and the Ad Unit ID
and what they're used for, and how you can then use them
inside of the Ad Mediation Control.
Then if you take a look at the navigation
on the left-hand side, it will give you another
article about adding and using the Ad Mediation Control,
what we dragged and dropped onto our designer surface,
and the different default settings that are added
and how you can configure them for
each of the different ad networks,
and how you declare the capabilities
for a given network inside of the ad mediator,
or rather, the, yeah, the ad mediator that we saw
a little bit ago when we clicked on Add, Connected Services.
But I think, ultimately one of the most important things
from this page that is a takeaway is that
these are the different ad sizes that are supported
for the Universal Windows Platform.
And so most of these are going to be square
or like a three by four sized orientation,
I guess you can say, or four by three, rather,
but this one, this long, skinny one, would be the one
that I would probably use for our project,
because it's 728 pixels wide but 90 tall.
So it'd fit really nice along the bottom of our application.
So we're going to remember that.
In fact, I'm going to open up Notepad here
and type in 728 and 90, cause I'm going to remember that.
Alright, but ultimately, whenever you submit your app
to the app store, it will replace several of the
settings that were created here by default,
like in this AdMediator.config file.
So generally you shouldn't have to mess with this
if you were to configure
everything correctly in the dashboard.
So, any rate, now that we know how to create a ad,
let's go ahead and get back into our project
and make sure that we add that in.
So here we are, back in the AlbumCoverMatchGame.
And what I want to do is go to the MainPage.xaml,
specifically I want to go and I'm going to add
one more row definition at the bottom,
and it's only going to be 90 tall,
and that's where we're going to put the ad.
We'll put it, then, here, we'll drag and drop it
onto the design surface in just a moment.
I'm going to right-click my project name and select,
and you unfortunately can't see this
off to the top of the screen, Add, Connected Service,
and the Ad Mediatior, I'm going to select Configure,
I'm going to select the ad networks,
Microsoft Advertising is my only choice,
I'm going to click Add.
Now what I want to do is go to MainPage.xaml
and I want to view the design view for this,
and I'm going to try and find that bottom area,
hopefully I can drag into it.
I'm going to go to the Toolbox, go to the AdMediator Universal
section of the Toolbox and drag the AdMediatorControl
into what I hope to be that third row,
but I can fix that if it doesn't go there perfectly.
I'm going to get that message box that
the reference has been to the project,
I'm going to click OK, I'm going to click Build the Solution,
great, and now I'm going to go back and attempt to
go to the Toolbox and re-drag and drop
the AdMediatorControl into that bottom area there.
Now, admittedly, you can see that
it's kind of fighting me, but that's fine.
At this point I have everything in there that I need
and I go back to the XAML view
and actually make the changes to it that I need to make.
Here we go, Grid.Row equals 2 is what we needed,
perfect, it put that in there.
I'm going to go ahead and get rid of the margins here.
I'm also going to change the height of this
to 90 and the width to 728,
remember that was one of the ad sizes.
Let's get rid of everything there
and let's get rid of everything here.
Let's build it one more time just to be on the safe side.
And I'm going to run the app
and with any luck, after a moment we'll see
at least a sliver of that little MSN
advertisement popup.
(guitar music)It's not popping up for me.
That could be a size issue, so let me
back out of this change,
I'm just going to hit "ctrl + z" and "ctrl + z".
Oh, you know what, I did forget a step.
I forgot a step.
After I added everything, I need to go back now,
and go back to Add, Connected Service,
go back to the ad mediator, Configure,
click OK, and click Add.
Now I should be able to build,
I knew I was forgetting something.
And now I'm going to change the height to 90
and then the width to 728.
That should fix that.
And let's go ahead and build the solution
one more time, cause I'm paranoid about this.
(laughs) Clearly.
And let's run the app.
And hopefully we'll see the little sliver of blue down here.
And we do. Great.
So it's there.
And if I click on it, it opens up to MSN.
Perfect.
(guitar music)So that's how we can add
Microsoft Advertising (chuckles)
Microsoft Advertising to our app.
Now hold on a second, I just noticed
something that did not look very cool.
Let me make sure this is all running correctly.
I seem to have lost my(guitar music)
lost something here in the process.
I've introduced a bug somehow,
hoping it's a small fix, but let me look into that as well
by adding the Mediator Control,
seems like I lost all my album art.
So let me look into that
and we'll start back up in the next video.