Hi, I'm Bob Tabor with www.LearnVisualStudio.net,
and I just wanted to take this lesson and cover some
of the most basic input controls that
we haven't already covered up to this point.
We're going to need some of these input controls
for future projects.
Also I just want to do a review of all the controls
eventually and so we'll get to that.
We're going to cover seven in rapid fire
in this lesson.
You see that I've created a new project: ControlsExamplePart1
and I've really done nothing to it just yet.
I'm going to drag and drop an image that should be included
with the download associated with this lesson.
I'm just going to drag and drop if from my desktop
into my Assets folder
so you can see it now appear here.
All right, and we're going to need that
in just a little bit.
So I'm going to copy and paste most of the code
for this lesson just because there's so much of it.
And there's really three things that I want to learn
about each control.
First of all, how do I display it on screen?
Secondly, how do I handle the major events
that it will emit whether it be a tapped
or a selection changed, whatever the case might be?
And then third, how do I retrieve the value
out of that control,
the current selection, whatever has been typed in,
whatever has been checked or unchecked,
things of that nature, okay?
So the first input control that we want to look at
is the CheckBox,
a very simple yes/no control.
As you can see, we create a new CheckBox
and I set the content to
a label that will be displayed
by default to the right of that square, that CheckBox.
The user will tap it to check it or tap it to uncheck it.
So we have a Tapped event that we can handle.
And inside of this, what I want to do is just
display in the label below it or the TextBox below it,
whether the CheckBox is currently checked or not.
Now there's also a Checked event, however, it only
fires once and then it never fires again
and that's not what we want.
We want to handle every time that particular control
has been touched.
So you can see, when I check it or uncheck it,
I get the IsCheck property equals true or false, great.
All right, we're off to a great start.
All right, the next thing that I want to look at
is a RadioButton which is similar to a CheckBox
however it will allow you to add
multiple potential values
each grouped together by a GroupName.
So all the radio buttons that belong together
you have to give it the same GroupName.
You can have two groups of radio buttons,
and the selections will be unique within
each of those groups.
So here again, I'm setting the Content property.
It'll be a label off to the right-hand side
of the actual RadioButton itself.
RadioButtons are not really buttons,
they're more like CheckBoxes, so that's an odd name,
but I guess because it's a button like a button on a shirt
it's circular.
So let's see, the other thing that we want to do,
we can handle the Checked event again.
I'm not sure we're going to get the results we want.
Here, I'm going to go ahead and go along with that,
so I'll hit F12 on my keyboard.
And here we will set the
RadioButtonTextBlock below it
to the Text and we'll just use this ternary operator.
We'll either say yes or no.
So let's go ahead and run the application now.
And so we'll select yes or no, or yes or no, okay.
And we could add as many RadioButtons as we want
but it typically only works well
with four or five selections at most.
If you have more than that, then you'll probably
want to move onto a different type of control for input.
All right, so we've covered those two.
Let's move on to the next one and look at a ComboBox.
And a ComboBox will allow you to create a number
of ComboBoxItems, each with their own value.
Let's go ahead and format this a little bit.
If I stuff in the paste.
All right, so here we have a ComboBox,
and we're handling a SelectionChanged event
so whenever somebody makes a different selection
in the ComboBox, we want to handle that and then
take whatever the new selection was and display that
in the label below or in the TextBlock below.
You can see that we created a number of individual
TextBox items that will show up in the dropdown list
and we can even say, "Hey, this one should be selected."
In fact, I'm going to move this one just to prove this.
We'll move it to the last one will be selected by default.
All right, and then in this SelectionChanged event here
I want to handle that.
And I'm going to go ahead and paste in the code.
It's a little bit tricky honestly.
The way that we retrieve the value is that we're going to
use the sender that was passed in
in order to get a reference to
the ComboBox itself, and then to get
access to the SelectedItem that was chosen
from the ComboBox,
then we're going to choose combo.SelectedItem
and we're going to cast that to a ComboBoxItem.
And only then can we retrieve the Content of that
ComboBoxItem and display that in the TextBlock below.
So let's go ahead and run the application.
And here you can see sixth was chosen because we set
the IsSelected property to true for that.
But when I make different selections you can see
how they show up here in the label to the right-hand side.
So that's how we get access to the SelectedItem.
This is great because you can
have a long list of items unlike a RadioButton.
However, they're all hidden and it might not be completely
obvious to the user that there are many other options.
In this case, you might want to choose a ListBox instead.
Now the ListBox is going to be a pretty important control
when we go forward, when we're creating
our hamburger navigation.
There's a bunch of different ways that we can create
that hamburger navigation that's popular in Windows 10.
I choose the ListBox for reasons that I'll demonstrate
in an upcoming lesson
to kind of follow up on a promise that I made earlier.
However, let's go ahead and take a look.
It, too, has a SelectionChanged event.
Let's go ahead and handle that.
What makes the ListBox a little bit different than
the other items like the radio and the ComboBox,
is that several items can be selected.
Take a look here that I changed the SelectionMode
which is by default a single item,
and I changed it to Multiple,
so you could select multiples.
And what I want to do is use this link query
against all of the ListBoxItems
for those items where the IsSelected property
is true and then I want to grab out just the
Content property of those selected items,
put them in an Array of strings
and then I'm going to call string.Join()
to concatenate them all together
for display into the TextBlock below.
So let's go ahead and run this
and you can see what I mean by all that.
All right, so I'll select the first one, the second,
the third, I'll get rid of the second one,
I'll get rid of the First one, I'll add the Second one.
So you can see how that works.
Now what we'll use it for, when we actually do use it
in an upcoming lesson,
we'll change the SelectionMode.
It'll just be Single selection.
But one of the features that I like about it
is that once you make a selection,
it actually will keep that selection highlighted
which is one of the things that we noted about the
hamburger navigation style on the money app,
the sports app, the ones that are built-in to Windows 10.
Okay, we'll come back to ListBox some day soon here.
Now let's move on.
I want to show you
the Image control
because it too will be used in an upcoming exercise.
And the Image control will do just like what it says.
It will display an image.
However, there is this interesting property.
First of all, you set the Source.
And in this case the Source is going to be relative
to the root of our projects.
So we're going to look in the Assets folder
for a logo.png.
We could also supply it a location across the internet
or some other folder in our application.
The thing that I wanted to point out which
is interesting here is the Stretch property.
And there's a couple different options
and I'll go through each of them here
as we run the application over and over.
So first of all the Stretch property is None
which means we're not going to stretch
the property to fit the available space.
There's no stretching at all.
We're just going to put it in its original size
which as you can see is quite large.
Next we're going to change the Stretch property to
Fill, and let's see what that does for us.
So the Fill selection will say, okay, it's a
250px wide by 50px tall area
so fill it up to the best that you can
so it'll just stretch that Image out of shape
and make it distorted but it will fill up
the entire area.
And then the next one that we'll look at is
Uniform and that will make sure that
it's not distorted and it's actually resized correctly
so that it fits in the available area,
but there's a lot of extra area here that is unused
off to the right-hand side.
Finally, UniformToFill is the last option.
It's going to look a lot like None
that we looked at earlier, however,
it's going to keep the proportions correct.
It's just going to stretch out the proportions
to fit the available space.
And again this might not be so obvious in this example,
however, if you have a different size boundary
and a different type of image or size of image,
you might see some change in how that looks.
All right, so let's go ahead and move on from there
to the ToggleButton.
And the ToggleButton is just
a stateful Button,
so you can click it on and you can click it off.
There's also an option to make it a ThreeState,
so you can click it and give it no value,
click it on or click it off.
And so I've set the IsThreeState="True"
so that we can see it at work.
Here I'm going to handle the
MyToggleButton_Click event
and inside of here
I'm merely going to display whether
the ToggleButton is on or off,
if it's Checked or Unchecked.
Let's go ahead and run it.
I see the Premium Option.
I turn it to true.
I click it again, which sets the
IsChecked to Null essentially
and then I check it again and it's false.
So that's ThreeState.
We can turn it to TwoState and it will be simply
one click on, one click off.
Then the last one that we're
going to look at here is similar to that
except it's called the ToggleSwitch.
The ToggleSwitch allows us to
toggle between two states.
And we see this control used often in the Settings panel
in Windows 10.
What you can do that's interesting is actually set a
Content area for what should be displayed
whenever the Toggle is in an off position or an on position.
You can also handle other events but this will be
primarily how it's used to display the current state
of the toggle.
So let's go ahead and run that application one more time.
And you can see I've set it to "I'm off right now".
I can turn it on and "I'm on".
I'm off, I'm on.
And I just used a simple TextBlock,
but if you got creative you could do quite a bit with this.
Okay, so that's all I wanted to cover in this lesson.
Hopefully, you were able to see
for each of the controls that we covered,
how to display it,
if we can, how do we handle the events
that it emits or how do we set properties
that are special to that particular control,
and then also finally how to retrieve the current
selected value out of that control.
All right, so let's continue on.
We're doing great.
We'll see you in the next lesson.
Thank you.