Hi, I'm Bob Tabor with www.learnvisualstudio.net,
and this is the challenge that I call
the Adeptly Adaptive Challenge.
You will be asked to create an apdaptive
solution for a fake news website.
So you can see as I make the application larger,
at some point, at 900 pixels wide, actually,
each of the individual news items
will become extremely large, 400x400.
When we go with the smaller size,
it's more like 200x275.
Also when we get larger you can see that
the title grows from an 18 point font to a 26 point font,
and there are instructions for this
I'll call your attention to in just a moment.
Furthermore, if we were to run this on
mobile you wouldn't be able to see
this SearchBox any longer,
it would be hidden, the visibility would be collapsed.
And we'll talk about which of which of the techniques
that you've learned you should use to make that happen.
Alright, so let me shut that down.
I'm giving you the resources with this lesson
and it'll include a number of different things
like screenshots of things that we just looked at
in the live demo.
Furthermore there are a series of instructions,
I highly recommend you keep these handy.
You're going to create just the beginning of a fake news app.
Now if this were a real app,
we'd go out to an online service,
pull down data, and then Bind to it,
and we'll do something similar to that
when we get to the weather app
that we'll build together here in just a little while.
In this case I'm going to give you
some hard-coded data to use for the application.
But essentially each news item will contain
an image, a headline, a subhead, and a dateline.
So when you're going to create a NewsItem class,
and it's going to have these properties,
and you're going to then create
a bindable Collection of these items
and then Bind to them using a GridView.
Let me see if there's anything in here,
I would highly recommend
that you read through this thoroughly.
I'm going to give you all the images that you'll need
so there are five Financial images,
five Food images that you'll use.
They correspond with data that I'm going to give you
in this little helper method,
that's to be used with the Manager class that you'll build.
So here's a little helper method that will return a list
of five Financial news stories,
and five Food news stories.
I give you, let's walk through this.
Use techniques that we discussed previously to create this.
Having said that you're only going to need to create
a MainPage.xaml so we not going to
utilize the device family-specific view.
Instead we're going to do this all
with the Visual State Managers and Adaptive Triggers.
You're going to use a GridView,
you're also going to create a User Control
that will store those values,
because you'll have to use that technique,
because we're going to re-size each of the individual
templates for the news items
in the DataTemplate for the GridView.
I think a lot of this is self-explanatory.
Just have a keen eye here towards these two items.
Each NewsItem should be 200x275 when in a narrow state,
400x400 wide in a wide state.
The wide state I'm defining as 900 minimum window width.
And then the AutoSuggestBox,
when the width is less than 400 should be hidden.
So the only way you would really be able to see this
because you can't see it
when you're running on the local machine
is when you actually run it on
one of the smaller device emulators.
So let's go ahead and run that real quick.
Now, just to note,
We're not actually implementing the AutoSuggestBox,
we're not implementing Search,
I just want you to be able to successfully use
the VisualStateManager to Show and Hide
based on the Width of the window.
And so again, when it's less than 400 pixels wide,
the visibility of that
AutoSuggestBox should be collapsed,
and when it's greater than 400 it should be visible.
And I think that's all
that I really wanted to say about this.
I give you all of the Segoe MDL2 assets that you'll need,
the Colors, the FontSizes, the Margins.
When in doubt reference the screenshots that I give you,
A, B, and C, that are available in that folder.
And then obviously here this helper method
which will give you
the list of news items.
This should probably take you 40, 45 minutes
if you make no mistakes and you know what you're doing.
If you're new to all of this
it might take a little bit longer.
Don't get discouraged, keep struggling, pushing through,
you can do this, I know you can.
Reference the videos and the cheatsheet
that we just went over previously,
and I know you can figure this out.
Just want you to get some hands-on exercise.
All right, so if you get stuck,
take a look in the next videos.
I've split them out so that you can find the part
that is pertinent to what you're looking for.
I hope that helps, and good luck,
and I know you can do this.
Thanks.