So we've kind of finished with the first half
of the series.
Now we're going to move on and we're going to change the format up
just a little bit.
Up to this point we would cover some topics
that were loosely related,
then we would have a cheat sheet session,
then I would assign a challenge,
in order to reinforce those ideas.
Now we're going to kind of move past that,
move on to a new format where we're going to build
four entire applications from scratch.
So a lot of times the developers that I've spoken to
through the years, they understand C#
they understand Object-Oriented Programming.
But they don't understand how to decompose something
in their head and make a full application out of it.
So hopefully this process will illustrate how to do that.
Secondly we're going to move into other areas
of the Universal Windows Platform
that we haven't talked about yet.
Learn some new techniques,
some new features of Visual Studio.
So there'll be a lot to learn taking this other tact
as we approach this material.
So feel free to follow along, that would be great.
I'm going to move fast, I'll warn you right up front.
Make sure that you reference the snapshots
for each video.
So at the end of each video I'd copy off
the current state of the code into its own .zip file.
So make sure you download that .zip file
and you take a look at the code that I typed in there.
Or you're going to be pausing or rewinding a lot,
which is fine too.
But you might find more satisfaction at looking at
that actual code that I typed in.
So what are we going to learn?
Well let's go ahead and run the application
and first of all I wanted to point out that you see that
red splash screen.
We'll talk about that.
How we were able to achieve that
by modifying the Package.appxmanifest file.
And that will be near the end of our development effort
on this application.
But we can add resources that'll be utilized in the store,
on the start bar, and the splash page, things like that.
Alright so you can see that I had
this simple soundboard application.
The idea here is that there is an icon for each sound.
I've only included a handful of sounds.
Feel free to flush this out, add as many sounds
and more functionality if you want.
But the idea here is that you can find a category
of sounds using the hamburger navigation.
And then we find one that you want to play,
you just tap on it,(sound effect)
click on it and it will play that sound.
Okay so clearly hamburger navigation,
using the back buttons, State Management,
looking at the AutoSuggestBox we are able
to find one specific sound,
play that,(cow mooing)
and then clear out that sound and have
the state of the application return back to normal.
There's also clearly we're using media here
we're using sound so we're going to demonstrate
the use of the Media element,
which allows you to play video and sounds
and various functionality around that new User Control.
We're also going to demonstrate drag-and-drop
so here's a .mp3 file that i have on my desktop
and I was going to drag it and drop it.
Alright and this is a little song
that was played by a friend.
It's actually kinda long so,(sound effect)
if you play another sound it will cancel that one out.
That was purely accidental but a cool feature none the less.
Okay we've already talking about
the Package.appxmanifest.
And then finally what we're going to do
after we build this application,
is we're going to submit it to the store,
walk through that entire process
and then just to kind of restate this,
I've already built this application.
I'm coming back to record this video
after I've finished.
And at the very end,
I left you with a cliffhanger.
You know, is this actually going to pass?
Am I going to be able to get this thing into the Window Store?
And so just this morning I got this notification
that your submission for UWP SoundBoard passed certification
Alright, so it's in the store
it will be published within 24 hours.
Alright so that's pretty cool.
So it actually worked.
So the cliffhanger I leave you at the end
of the last video with,
I've already, it's going to be anti-climactic
because you already know that it will pass.
And I didn't do anything off-camera.
Everything you saw was what I did here on camera.
Alright so hopefully this will be
a great learning exercise for you.
Again, different format, so don't let that throw you.
Please follow along, if not by writing code
at least stay engaged as I write it.
It'll be a little bit dryer
because I'll be talking to myself a lot
instead of talking to you.
But hopefully you'll get some value out of it.
Okay, let's start up in the next lesson.
Thanks.