Hi, I'm Bob Tabor with www.learnvisualstudio.net
and it's time for another cheat sheet review
where we'll talk about Windows 10 Layout in general,
specifically, several new Layout controls
that allow us to cheat Windows 10 Layout
and that hamburger style navigation,
and then finally we talked about controls as well.
So let's open up our cheat sheet
and then let's scroll to the bottom here,
and we'll start with lesson number 17,
where we talked about the relative panel.
We said that the RelativePanel allows you
to define an area where all the controls on the side
can either align themselves relative to the panel itself,
or relative to the other controls.
And we said that the controls would use attached properties
to tell the Layout engine
where they want to be positioned in relation to.
We said that there's different types of properties
that can be set and they're applied in a certain order.
So first, you have panel alignment relationships
like align the top of my control with the panel,
align the left of my control with the panel,
and these are applied first.
The next grouping are sibling alignment relationships.
They allow you to AlignTopWith
AlignTopWith relative to another control,
or left with another control,
and then finally, applied last are
the sibling positional relationships.
So for this given control,
put it in such a position
where it's above or below, or to the left
or right of another given control.
Alright, so I have a quick little example here
that you can use as a form of cheat sheet,
where we have a RelativePanel and two Rectangles.
And the first Rectangle, it sets its attached property
AlignRightWithPanel="True",
so it will always be to the right of the Panel.
And then, we say to the second Rectangle
that it will be relative to LeftOf the RedRectangle.
Alright, next up, we talked about the SplitPanel
and we said that you use the SplitPanel
to create a panel that can be displayed or hidden
and it's used for that hamburger style navigation
and we said that it's basically
two main pieces of the puzzle there.
There is the part that's hidden that comes
and shows itself and hides itself, that's the Pane.
And then, there's the part that is actually beneath it,
or to the right of it, and that is the content.
So let me go ahead and copy and paste
a little example into the window here,
and it looks like I need a little formatting.
And so, one of the things that we can do
is change the display mode, and the DisplayMode
will dictate the behavior of the Pane
and the content area, which are defined below it here.
So let me just go ahead and copy and paste
in the different DisplayModes.
So there's Inline, CompactInline,
Overlay, and CompactOverlay.
So Inline is where the panel is completely
covering the content, and when it's shown,
it'll actually push the content out,
so that it's still visible.
CompactInline is almost identical,
except it will show a little sliver of,
if you have it docked to the left at the left-hand side,
it'll show those icons on the left.
Overlay will do the same thing as Inlign,
it will completely cover the...
the Pane will be completely hidden, and when it's shown,
it will completely cover the content.
CompactOverlay will let a little area peak out,
and then whenever it's expanded,
then it will completely cover whatever's underneath it.
And so, I also gave a little C# code snippet
that allows you to basically show and hide the Pane.
Whatever its current state is, do the opposite
and set it equal to the IsPaneOpen property.
Next up, we talked about working with navigation.
And, let's see, let's get a couple things here.
Alright, first up, we said that at the highest level
of our application is the App and App owns a Window
and inside the Window is a Frame.
We see all this set up for us in the App.xaml.cs
And then, the Frame will load in the MainPage.
Now you don't have to do it that way,
but that is what the Blank App template will give you.
So then you can either load new Pages into that root frame,
or you can add other Frames into your XAML pages
and then load content in and out of that,
and we demonstrated that by creating a Frame
inside of the MainPage, and then loading Page 1,
Page 2, Page 3 inside of that Frame.
So the way that you navigate, there's a Frame property
on the Page that'll give you access to the parent Frame
and you just call its navigate method, you pass in the type
that you want to create a new instance of,
and you can also optionally pass in
any additional parameters of any type.
Then, you can retrieve whatever was passed in
from the previous page by overriding a specific method
called OnNavigatedTo, and we can retrieve
the value of the Parameter that was passed in
by calling the NavigationEventArgs "e.Parameter"
and then casting it to whatever the object type is
that you passed in, and then you can work with it
in any way that you like.
We also talked about the BackStack and how
it essentially keeps the history as you move
forward and backwards and it will replay
that navigation event and we showed that
you can traverse the BackStack
by checking if the Frame can go
back or if it can go forward, and if it can,
then you can call GoBack and GoForward methods.
And then finally, I demonstrated in that video
how you can create kind of a global variable
at the App level by declaring a static internal field
in the App class definition.
And that would allow you to get around those situations
where when you replay the BackStack traversing,
you don't get the values that you would expect.
They don't maintain the state of whatever
was typed into a given form field as you go
and you traverse around through the BackStack.
Next up, we talked about the common XAML controls,
and this is going to be a long one,
I'm not going to spend too much time on it
because we did work with this at length.
I basically just stripped out the essence
of each of the controls that we looked at,
and hopefully that'll be helpful to you.
So let me go ahead and paste in the first chunk here.
So lesson number 20: Common XAML Controls - Part 1,
we looked at the CheckBox,
we saw that there was a checked property.
Although it's not represented here,
we're able to access it programmatically
in C# in this line of code.
It also supports a Tapped event,
we can handle that Tapped event
and then display some result there.
Similar to the CheckBox, the yes or no/true or false
CheckBoxes, a RadioButton allows you
to provide several different options to the user.
And here, you need to use a GroupName
to group together multiple RadioButtons
that belong in the same group.
So, you can see that in this case, I was able to handle
the Checked event, and in that Checked event,
I implemented this ternary operator,
where I'm just checking to see
if the RadioButton.IsChecked.
If it is, then we'll just print out Yes,
if it's not, then we'll print out No.
You might need to do some variation on that.
Also, I didn't mention this at the time,
but IsChecked is a nullable bool,
so you have to cast it to boolean
in order to get the ternary operator to work.
I should have mentioned that before, it just came to me now.
Next up, we talked about the ComboBox,
which allows you to add a number of different
ComboBox items to a drop-down list,
so when somebody clicks the arrow,
they can see all of the items that were in the list.
You can set an IsSelected to a default value,
so in this case, when we load up the XAML Page,
the Sixth option will be displayed in the ComboBox.
To actually select an item in the ComboBox,
we get the value that's passed in
from the SelectionChanged event,
so there should be a SelectionChanged EventArgs e
EventArgs e, args n, I'm sorry,
there should be a sender, and then an EventArgs e.
So we're gonna take the sender,
whoever initiated this event, the SelectionChanged event,
we're gonna cast that to ComboBox,
then we're gonna find in the ComboBox
a SelectedItem and cast that to a ComboBox item,
and now that we have a ComboBox item,
we can grab its content and then print that to screen.
Next up, and this was an important one, the ListBox.
And the ListBox is important because we were able to use it
in the next video where we actually were creating
a more full hamburger example.
So here, we create a number of ListBox items
with content inside of them, we set the SelectionMode
both to Multiple and Single.
In Multiple, you can select multiple list items,
and in Single, you can only select one.
And since you can select multiples,
I have this little link statement that allows us to find
all of the ListBox items that were selected.
Grab out just the content and put them in an Array,
and then use string.Join for that Array and can catenate
them all together with a comma.
And then the next thing we talked about
was the Image control, and you want to set the Source,
attribute, and the Stretch attribute.
We talked about the different Stretch options
about None, Fill, UniformToFill, and Stretch.
Next up, we talked about the ToggleButton
and how to retrieve its value.
The toggle button has an IsThreeState, and remember,
the three states were Clicked,
Unclicked, and then I guess you could say Selected,
where it was turned on.
And so, whenever it's clicked, we can evaluate
the current value of IsChecked,
either true/false, or null.
Finally, we talked about the ToggleSwitch
and that would allow us to define some content
for the OnContent and the OffContent.
So when you flip on the switch,
you can show this content,
whatever's here, in this case, we just put a TextBox.
When the user switches it off, then it would display
the other section here underneath ToggleSwitch.OffContent.
Alright so, that was a whirlwind review,
but let's continue on.
We talked next about implementing
a simple hamburger navigation menu,
and I pointed you to Jerry Nixon's example
for a more full-featured example,
and I demonstrated my example
in the most simplest way possible
by using a SplitView and a ListBox control.
At any rate, one of the things that we needed to do
was actually to grab off some icons
in the Segoe MDL5 Assets font
and I showed you how to use the Character Map app
to find the fonts that you want to use
and then you prefix and suffix whatever the value is
you find with a &#x
and then suffix it with a ;.
Alright, and then finally, and I'm not gonna write out
a lot of this, you can always find this code example.
You can use ListBox and ListBoxItems
for the navigation links inside of a SplitView,
and that's what we did in that example.
And that technique's gonna come in handy
in the very next video because you're challenged
to create a more full-featured
hamburger navigation style with a search bar
and all that stuff and we'll start that in the next lesson.
We'll see you there! Thanks.