Okay, so we're making great progress here.
The next thing we want to do is evaluate
what the user clicks on.
The song is playing, they're going to choose an album cover,
and we want to evaluate the click.
Is it the song that's currently selected?
If yes, then we want to award them points,
and we want to display
a "correct" symbol in place of that album art.
However, if it's not correct,
we want to deduct points from their score
and then display the "incorrect" icon.
These icons are available for the download that
is associated with this video.
So, wherever you typically download the source code from,
those two files, the "correct" and "incorrect" PNGs
will be there as well.
Ok, so let's go ahead and get started here,
and we're going to evaluate whatever the user clicked on.
And we know that will happen
here in the SongGridView_ItemClick event.
So, the first thing we'll want to do is
we're going to ignore clicks
when the music isn't playing.
When the music...
When we are in cooldown.
So if not playing music,
then just return.
This isn't the right time to be clicking on this
part of the application's user interface.
However, if we are currently playing music,
then we want the current animation
to pause for a moment.
So pause the playback of the countdown animation.
And as far as the music is concerned, MyMediaElement,
we're going to stop the playback of the music.
Ok, so that should fix that problem.
Next up, we want to determine what was actually clicked on,
so we're going to go var song equals the ClickedItem
in the Grid and we'll cast that to an instance of Song.
And now we want to find
what the correct song was.
So what did we pick randomly
before we started this round?
Well...
Here we want to...
actually get access to
the correct song.
So FirstOrDefault where
Selected equals True.
And now we want to evaluate,
so if the song...
You know what we're going to need to do?
We're going to need to compare apples to apples, I'm afraid.
Well, maybe not.
That's going to be a pickle.
We'll see if it works.
If the song, in fact, just to kinda get this squared
in my mind,
clickedSong...
Alright, so if the clicked song...
Yeah, I should, may not even have to do any of this,
honestly.
So if clickedSong.Selected,
then what we want to do is...
set the clickedSong
.AlbumCover
.SetSourceAsync...
and we're going to need a FileStream here.
So I should be able to just do what I did earlier
with await file.OpenAsync...
Why can't I do that?
Oh, I see.
Okay. Let me start over.
Let me get a reference to the correct URI,
so let's go...
var uri
equals new Uri
and we'll need to get at the correct PNG,
so let me just copy these into my Assets folder,
make sure I do that first of all,
assets...
Alright, great.
So, back here.
Sorry for the indecision,
just this is the nature of how this sort of thing goes.
So "ms-appx:///assets
"/correct.png."
Alright, so we got that,
and then what I want to do is
well, let's get that file, so...
"StorageFile file equals
"StorageFile
".GetFileFromApplication
"UriAsync"
and I'm going to give it the URI,
so that should give me a reference to that file
in the file system.
So "var fileStream
"equals file.OpenAsync"
access mode Read, like that,
and then what I want to do is
clickedSong.AlbumCover.SetSourceAsync
.SetSourceAsync()
to that fileStream
like that.
Alright, so I've got lots of problems here.
First problem I think I have here
is that I've got an async and I need to do this.
So, await that and then we'll have to add
async here.
Great.
And then SetSourceAsync(), why are you not happy?
Oh, we've gotta await you as well.
Great.
And what's the problem here?
Ah. Okay.
It's actually that problem.
There we go. Nice.
And this should actually be selected.
If the clickedSong is selected, then we want to change that,
but otherwise we want to do the reverse.
And for now, I'm just going to go ahead and do this,
where I see an opportunity to kinda consolidate that
into fewer lines of code,
but for right now I'm just going to copy and paste
just to see if the logic and the selections
of what I'm working with here
will actually work,
so let's try it.
My concern is that we're going to lose our connection
to what we're binding to,
so when we click it....
Hold on.
When we click it,
we're only clicking a copy of the object,
not part of the collection that we've bound to.
It'll make sense here in a moment.
(music plays)
That was an odd coincidence,
but we'll go with it.
(music plays).
Okay.
So you can see, I think we've got it working.
(music plays)
Okay. Great.
Now, I'm not entirely sure.
We're going to have to do some more work here.
But lemmie get rid of all of that,
and I think what I want to do here is
Uri uri like that,
and then all we'll do is just grab off the URI like so
and then we'll do this like so.
And get rid of that, great.
This should work, still.
See how I was able to consolidate all that?
Alright, and then the other thing I need
is a score, so let's go ahead and go
int _totalScore
We'll set it equal to zero initially,
and what we want to do is
go back to where we were, yeah, here,
and I want to
grab the score here
so let's go score equals
MyProgressBar.Value
And I'm just going to make sure that it's an int.
So that's, if we get it right, I want a positive score,
but if we get it wrong what I'm going to do
is kinda the opposite.
So ... score equals MyProgressBar.Value
MyProgressBar.Value
And let's go ahead and do this
like so.
And I'm going to subtract points if you get it wrong.
Oh, actually, multiply that times minus one.
This might not be the most fair scoring system,
but it's just going to illustrate
how I'm going to go about this.
We can always fix this later.
So we're going to set totalScore plus-equals
whatever the score was from that right there.
Alright, and I think also, while we're here
what I want to do is set some things about,
so the ResultTextBlock.Text
equals string.Format score,
total score, after...
So here what I want to do is show, first of all, the score.
Then I want to show the round.
And then I want to show the total score like that.
So then let's go with TitleTextBlock.Text
equals String.Format
and oh, you know what we need do?
So here's what I want to do
is "Correct Song"
but we've only determined whether our song
is correct or incorrect,
not whether it's, which one is the correct one.
So let me do this.
var correctSong equals
let's get all of our songs,
FirstOrDefault
where Selected
equals true
So that should give me the correct song
and now I can do something like this.
correctSong
.Title
and then the ArtistTextBlock.Text equals String.Format
"Performed by" ...
correctSong.Artist
And then ... AlbumTextBlock.Text
equals string.Format
"on album"
and then correctSong.Album
Now, what I want to do is
whenever we...
That's when we start the cooldown, we'll see that.
But when we restart,
prepare the next round,
where do I do that at?
I want to clear all that out.
Populate SongList, pick random songs...
And my code is honestly unwieldy.
I should be splitting this up into other classes
and things like that,
but I'm not going to do that just yet.
Okay.
I'll worry about that part later.
I gotta think about that a little bit more
when we're going to reset that.
But at any rate, I need to set the state of these songs
because now we're kinda done working with them,
so the clickedSong, I should be able to set
its Used property equal to true,
and then I should be able to set the correctSong,
the Selected is now false.
And then I want to make sure that we don't
reuse it because it's already been clicked on,
and that means it has either a checkmark or an X,
and so the album cover won't be visible anymore,
so we want to make sure that it's been used
and we don't accidentally choose it again.
So finally, what I want to do here is do a check.
I'm only going to run this five times,
so if the round is greater than or equal to five,
then I'm going to do some end-game cleanup.
Otherwise, if it's not, then I want to start
the cooldown process again.
Here what I'm going to do is set
the InstructionTextBlock.Text
equals String.Format
and I'm going to say "Game Over, you scored"
and then put the total score in there,
_totalScore
And then the PlayAgainButton's visiblity,
I'm going to set that equal to Visible.
Okay, so we'll show that.
And that should do it.
So let's go ahead and now see what we get ourselves here.
(music plays)
Hmm, thought I knew that one.
But you can see I scored minus 60.
"Catch Me When I Fall," Storm Coming,
so it was off that album.
(music plays)
And I don't know any of these songs,
they're all made up,
so that should have been "Humble and Proud,"
should have been off that album,
so these two should not be selected in the future.
(music plays)
Hey, I got one right.
That was "Brian Plays a Hot Guitar,"
Inclement Weather, on the Longhorn album.
Great.
(music plays)
I got that one wrong, too.
Hey, I got one accidentally right.
So I played five rounds,
I scored negative 50, and I can play again.
Now, this doesn't do anything,
but we'll have to come back to that, then,
in the next video,
so I think that's all I really wanted to cover
in this video.
Let's go ahead and stop it here
and then I can re-group and figure out where we go
from here.