Hi, I'm Bob Tabor with www.LearnVisualStudio.NET.
In this lesson, we're going to talk about
several related topics
and all kind of merged together at the very end.
So we'll talk about Default Properties,
Complex Properties,
and the Property Element Syntax,
then we'll talk about how an intelligent XAML parser
really saves us from extra extraneous XAML code,
because it can infer
the relationships between the elements
by their context, so we'll talk about that at the very end,
but before we get started here,
I just want to point out
kind of the containment relationship
that we'd see in our XAML.
Since XAML is essentially an XML document,
we can embed elements inside of other elements
and that again kind of implies a containment relationship.
So, you can see that we have a Page object
and inside of the opening and closing
Page tag, we have a Grid object,
and inside of the opening and closing Grid element,
we can see that there's both a Button and a TextBlock.
Now, what's really going on behind the scenes,
and we don't see this in our XAML is,
what's actually kind of more the proper parlance in XAML
is that the Page's content property
is set to a new instance of the Grid control,
and the Grid control has a collection
called Children, and here we're adding two instances
of control to that Children collection.
So again, we don't see those properties listed anywhere here
so if you take a look, we don't see a content property
listed among the other properties.
We don't see any mention of Children here
in the Grid control but what is going on behind the scenes
is that we're populating those properties.
And I'll explain why we don't see them in our XAML,
again, at the very end of this lesson.
But for now, just understand there's a little more
than meets the eye.
We're actually setting the Grid's Children property
and we're setting the Pages' content property.
Now, if you take a look at the C# version of our code,
it more accurately shows that relationship
between the LayoutGrid.
It has a Children collection of controls,
and we're adding to that Children collection
an instance of the Button, OK.
We just don't see that here in our XAML, OK?
So just keep that in the back of your mind.
We're going to come back to that in just a moment.
Let's talk for a moment about Default Properties.
So, depending on the type of control
that you're working with, the Default Property
for that control can be populated
by using this embedded style syntax,
where we have elements inside of elements.
Now, in the case of, for example, the Button control,
the Content Property happens to be
the Default Property for that control,
so I can remove that property
from the properties or the attributes of that element,
and then I can also just remove that self-enclosing
syntax there for the element,
and just create a proper closing tag for the Button.
So we have an open Button tag and a closing Button tag
with nothing inside of it, but we can add something
like Hello World inside of it,
and now, by using that Default Property syntax,
we can actually see in the Design View
that we've changed the content property for the Button, OK?
So that will come to bear here in just a moment as well.
Keep that in the back of your mind.
Let's go back to the XAML editor
for our MainPage,
and let's talk about Type Converters just for a moment.
You'll recall from the last lesson, we talked about
Type Converters and I really, at that time,
only mentioned some simple Type Converters.
For example, the HorizontalAlignment property.
Here, that particular property is adorned with an attribute
that the developers of this property
decided to create a type converter
so that we can just give it a literal string value
and it will perform the type conversion
to an instance of
an enumeration Windows.UI.Xaml.HorizontalAlignment.Left,
and the same holds true, this simple type converter,
for the VerticalAlignment as well.
Now, there are some more complex versions
of Type Converters, like we see here in the Margin.
Here, our Margin property in XAML is set to a literal string
of "20, 20, 0, 0",
and if you take a look at the Background property,
it also is set to just a simple string,
a literal string of "Red",
but if you take a look at the C# version,
there's a little bit more going on here.
The Type Converters have to work a little bit harder
than they did with the Horizontal and Vertical Alignment.
In the case of the Margin, notice that
we're just not giving it an enumeration
but we're actually creating a new instance of an object
called Thickness, and that Thickness has a constructor
that accepts four input parameters
that happen to be the
left margin, top margin, right margin, bottom margin.
Likewise, if you take a look
at the Background property here,
we're actually setting it to a new instance
of an object called a SolidColorBrush,
and we're passing in
as an input parameter to the constructor,
a enumeration of type, Windows.UI.Colors.Red,
so in these cases, they're a little bit more complex
than the previous cases we looked at,
however, there's still even a
additionally more difficult situation.
In some situations, there are properties,
and values that you set to those properties,
that are simply too complex to be represented
merely by Type Converters, or handled by Type Converters.
So when a control's property's not easily represented by
just a simple XAML attribute like we see in these examples
that we've been looking at,
then it's referred to as a complex property.
So to demonstrate this,
I actually want to remove
this Background color here.
We're going to remove it.
And we're also going to remove this Default Property
and I'll reset the Content property here
back to what it was.
I think it was just "Click Me", alright?
And then finally,
I want to go over here to the MainPage.xaml,
I'm going to comment this out just so we don't accidentally
get some results we're not expecting
if I happen to decide to run it. OK.
Let me go ahead and add that closing, OK.
Now, we're good to go.
Alright, so now what I want to do
is put my mouse cursor on the Button
so that when I look at the Properties window,
the Name is set to ClickMeButton.
That lets me know that I'm in the right context
for the Properties window.
And I want to set that Background property again
using the Property dialog here,
and I want to change the Background property,
so I'm going to make sure to select that.
Now since we've removed it in the XAML,
our Background property is not being set at all.
And what I want to do is change that
to a GradientBrush,
and a GradientBrush is just going to give us a gradient.
As you can see right now, the gradient starts out as black
and then it slowly fades into the color white.
Now, if you look at the XAML that was generated,
we see that quite a bit has been added to our project
between the opening and closing Button tags.
Here, we're setting the Button.Background property
to an instance of LinearGradientBrush.
So whenever you see this type of syntax,
this type of element embedded inside of another element,
this is called a Property Element Syntax,
where we have an Object.Property
and what your intent is
is to give it some additional XAML
inside of that Property Element Syntax
that will define the values for this Complex Property.
Now, what is LinearGradientBrush?
It's simply just, again, kind of think of a paint brush,
so whenever you see the term "brush",
you're just thinking about color or colors.
In this case, we're looking at a paintbrush
that can paint a color starting at the top of the wall,
at black, and by the time we paint the bottom of the wall,
it'll be white, OK.
Now, let's actually change this.
I'm going to put my mouse cursor back up here in the Button,
and I'm going to come back to the Property window
and I don't want it to go
from black to white.
I want it to go from black to red,
so there's a little circle on this upper left hand corner,
I'm just going to drag it all the way here
to the right hand side,
and notice that it changed the GradientStop
from White, the color White to the color Red.
Let's save that and take a look at
what it looks like here in the designer,
and you can kind of see how that's represented.
At the top of the Button, it's black,
the bottom of the button is red, great.
Now, honestly, you probably never, ever want to do this
because it just doesn't follow the same aesthetic as
the rest of the applications that your users
are going to see in Windows 10,
but let's pretend for now that
you want to express your individuality
or there's some branding that you want to do
that your company is known for
and you need that gradient, OK.
So, you can see that, as we go back to the XAML editor,
if you do want to define a LinearGradientBrush,
you have to supply quite a bit of information here.
You have to not only give it the colors that you want
to use, you also have to give it
a collection of GradientStops and their Offsets,
where one Color starts
and the other Color stops, OK?
While this does look like a lot of additional XAML
just to represent a Color,
the code snippet here that I have highlighted
is actually shortened automatically by Visual Studio.
Let me take just a moment here
and type out what the full XAML should be
if Visual Studio didn't try to compact it for us, OK?
So, give me just one moment here.
OK, so it took a moment or two
but you can see that I've added a couple lines of code here
in Line 23 and 24, and then the closing tags
in Lines number 28 and 29 here, OK?
And so you'll see that we're setting the Button's Background
to a new instance of the LinearGradientBrush class.
The LinearGradientBrush class has a property
called GradientStops.
The GradientStops property
is of type GradientStopCollection,
so we create a new instance of GradientStopCollection
and add two instances of the GradientStop object
to that collection, OK?
So, as you can see, that
we were able to omit lines 23, 24,
as well as 27, or rather 28,
or yeah, 27 and 28,
and we were able to omit this, or actually,
Visual Studio, when it generated the XAML for us,
was able to omit it because it wanted
to make the XAML more concise and more compact,
and it's made possible by an intelligent XAML parser.
So first of all, we talked about Default Properties
at the very outset of this lesson.
The GradientStops property is the Default Property
for the LinearGradientBrush.
The GradientStops property
is of type GradientStopCollection, so the only thing
that we can put in a GradientStopCollection
are instances of GradientStop.
So since we just put two GradientStop objects
inside of a LinearGradientBrush,
it knows that we're dealing with the Default Property
and that Default Property is of type GradientStopCollection,
so we don't even need to put that in there.
That's already implied. We can just supply it, whoops,
gave it the wrong thing here.
We can just give it the two GradientStops
and it can infer the rest that it needs
from its context, OK?
So the moral of the story is that
the XAML parser is intelligent,
and it doesn't require us to include redundant code
that it can infer from the context.
As long as it has enough information to create
that object graph correctly, it'll do it
and we don't have to give it any more than it needs.
And furthermore, Visual Studio will
emit concise code if we use the Properties window
or other tooling support inside of Visual Studio.
So just to recap this lesson,
we talked about a number of different things again
that all kind of fit together.
We talked about Default Properties,
we talked about Complex Properties,
then we talked about the Property Element Syntax
like we saw here, like we saw,
we've actually removed some of those
lines of code between Line 22 and Line 25,
and we also talked about how an intelligent XAML parser
allowed us to remove those lines of code
because it allows us to keep our XAML compact
by inferring from context what inner elements
should be used for.
And finally, whenever possible,
Visual Studio will generate concise XAML for us, OK?
So let's keep plugging along
with more XAML in the next lesson.
We'll see you there, thank you.