Okay, so next up we're going to create the Data Model,
which we're going to call Sound,
and the Sound will have an audio file and an image file,
and also a category.
Then we're going to create a sound manager,
which will allow us to get either
access to all sounds or just
a soundbyte category.
So we're going to pass in an empty or populated
ObservableCollection that we're going to Bind to,
and we'll stick instances of Sound into it,
whether it be all of them, or just filtered by category.
And then I'll do some preliminary Binding,
just so we can see something appear on screen.
It won't do much yet,
but at least it'll get us that far.
So let's go ahead and get started here,
and create a Model Folder.
And I want to create a class inside that Model Folder,
called Sound.
And in this class I'm going to create,
I'm going to give it a Name,
and a Category.
So let's come back to Category because
I think I want to create enumeration there.
Whoops, and then let's give it a,
an AudioFile and,
an ImageFile, alright.
And I'm going to create a SoundCategory,
so public enum SoundCategory.
And those Categories will be,
you know, the Categories that
I already kind of had here: Animals, Cartoons,
Taunts, and Warnings, so.
Animals.
Cartoons.
Taunts.
Warnings, great.
And so I'll make this Category of type SoundCategory.
Alright, and I think I'm going to also do something
to make it easy to populate all these.
I know that the Audio and the ImageFiles follow
a similar pattern, they're all going to be found at,
/assets/audio/categoryname/soundname
asssets/audio/categoryname/soundname
Same thing with icons.
They'll be at /assets/images/animal,
or category/name.
So I can make it easy on myself whenever I create
new instances of these little guys,
by creating an overloaded constructor.
So public sound, and we'll take a...
Name and a Category, SoundCategory.
And then we can do something like this.
Name = name.
Category = category.
And then the AudioFile will equal String.Format.
And we'll give it the Category and the Name.
And inside there it'll be like,
/assets/audio/
then whatever the Category name is,
then whatever the file name is, WAV, right?
And we can do the exact same thing for Image as well.
So ImageFile.
Just change this from Audio to Images,
and from WAV to PNG, and that should work.
We'd populate those two, just be a really easy way
of constructing those.
Let me make sure I have the names of things right,
like these folders, yeah that looks good.
Okay, I think we're good to go there, great.
Next up, let's create the SoundManager,
which will allow us to get instances of Sound.
So...
I like to make these manager classes static and stateless.
Or I should say the methods inside of them static.
And what I want to do is be able to pass in an
ObservableCollection, and have it populate it.
So I know I'm going to create like a private static.
And this will return,
what will it return?
Yeah it'll return just a List.
Called getSounds, something like that.
And...
So let's do a var sounds
equals new List, like that.
And then we'll just do sounds.Add.
Add new Sound, and we'll use the overloaded constructor,
to give it a Name.
So for example, maybe Cow.
And...
Animals.
And we'll just follow that little pattern there
a bunch of times.
And then we'll return sounds, okay?
So you know, the other one's Cat.
Then here, I'm going to have to look at my folders.
Cartoons, Gun, and Spring, okay.
Gun, Spring, and both of those are,
Cartoons.
Great.
Now Taunts: Clock and LOL, okay.
And then finally, Warnings: Ship and Siren.
Whoops whoops, Warnings, there we go.
Okay, so far so good.
So we can get a list of new sounds, so public static void GetAllSounds,
public static void GetAllSounds.
And first thing I'll do is just
var sounds = getSounds.
So what I want to do is be able to pass in
an ObservableCollection of sound.
Because that's what I'm going to have
passing in from MainPage.xaml.cs,
to this SoundManager, so ObservableCollection
of type Sound, like so.
Let me get that namespace in there,
System.Collections.ObjectModel, great.
Whoops I've gotta give it...
Observe, I don't know what a good name for this is,
sounds, here I'll just do this,
I'm going to call this allSounds.
Hard to know what to name things,
I keep saying that, but it's true.
All right, all sounds, okay.
So sounds.Clear() because I want to get rid of
anything that's already in the Collection.
And then do you remember what we did with that nifty little.
That nifty little LAMBDA expression we did here?
I think I can do that, isn't that how that would work?
Yeah, I think that'll work.
Well, we'll test it and make sure it works,
but I'm pretty sure that's the LAMBDA expression
I need to add, so we're gonna loop through every sound
that we pulled back from this getSounds.
And for each one, I'm going to add it to this
ObservableCollection called sounds.
I don't need to return anything because
it's passed in by reference.
Let's do the same thing here with public static
void GetSoundsByCategory,
and it's going to work almost identically.
We'll still have
this ObservableCollection
passed in, but I'm also going to pass in
a Sound Category called soundCategory,
and we'll just filter on that.
And let me fix that, okay.
So here again we'll get allSounds = getSounds.
This time I want to filter though,
and so var filteredSounds...
Equals allSounds.Where, and,
p.Category == soundCategory, alright.
And then I'll go sounds.Clear(),
just like before, and then,
filteredSounds.ForEach.
Okay, yeah, why can't I do that?
Because I didn't ToList this on the end I think.
There we go.
filteredSounds.ForEach,
given p,
call sounds and Add that item
to our ObservableCollection.
Okay so that's all the setup we should have to do for
SoundManager, and for sound at least for the moment.
Now in the MainPage.xaml.cs,
we're going to want to create a
private reference to
the ObservableCollection
ObservableCollection called sounds.
Whoops, ObservableCollection.
Whoops.
Alright, there we go.
Great, okay, very good.
And what I want to do is...
First of all, after we initialize the component.
Let's call the SoundManager,
and get all sounds passing in
our ObservableCollection,
and that should populate it now.
Okay, very good.
And that's all I should have to do for the moment,
and let me just see if I can Bind to it.
So let's create an XML namespace
for data, and we're going to set that equal to,
whoops, not application insights.
We'll set that equal to UWPSoundBoard.Model.
Great.
Here in my DataTemplate,
I'm going to need to set the DataType
equal to data:Sound, okay?
And then let's compile, you can see that,
I'm getting a blue squiggly, it's just because we haven't
built in a while, let's make sure everything builds.
Okay, good.
And then I'm going to set the Source
Source=x:Bind, and then...
What's the name, AudioFile?
Does that sound right?
I think that's right.
Oh, I'm sorry, duh, ImageFile not AudioFile.
Okay, that's better.
Let's see what this does.
Oh and then I need to give it a Source, so,
ItemsSource,
and we'll go x:Bind that to Sounds.
And I'll cross my fingers, and with any luck,
we'll get at least some images on screen.
Ah, okay.
No reference, okay we can fix that.
Mm, yeah.
Alright, it's not pretty,
but I got all of my icons there.
Yeah, things are pretty ugly right now.
But I got the Binding to kind of work.
And we'll fix, well let's take a quick stab at
why we might be getting some oddness there.
I think the fundamental problem here is that
that SplitView should be in Grid.Row="1".
I think that's pretty much the biggie.
So let's try that again, that should at least push that
grey little area down a little bit.
Okay, got that going for us now.
And while we're here and while I'm thinking about it,
let's go ahead and get the...
The HamburgerButton_Click working.
So we'll go MySplitView.IsOpen
MySplitView.IsOpen = !MySplitView.IsPaneOpen
Like so, and at least that'll open that up.
Now the other thing that I need to do here,
I'm going to need one more,
I'm going to take a different tact,
I think I said with regards to the,
Pane of our SplitView,
I was going to use a ListView Control instead.
And so what I need to do is make another Model class,
a View Model class called MenuItem.
So let me go ahead and just do that real quick.
It's pretty easy, it'll only take
a minute or two to do this.
So let's go MenuItem.
And let's go public class MenuItem,
and we'll go...
IconFile, and then SoundCategory,
so what Category does that icon represent?
And that'll help us to filter.
And filter the sounds based on the selected menu item
in the SplitView Pane.
So back here in the MainPage.XAML then,
what we'll do is...
Do it right here I guess.
I'm going to create a private
List.
Called MenuItems.
And so we'll set that, and then we'll set the Category
equal to SoundCategory.Animals.
Now the IconFile will be at
Assets/Icons/animals.png
Assets/Icons/animals.png, like that.
So let me go.
And let's go cartoon.
And taunt.
And warning.
So cartoons.
Taunts.
Warnings.
Great.
Now let's Bind those here
on our ListView.
So...
Let me go ahead...
And I'm going to add a StackPanel.
With the Orientation="Horizontal".
And here I'm going to add an Image,
and I'm going to set its Source
equal to the IconFile.
And I think I need to set the
Height="0.5", Width="45".
I may have to reduce that, but let's start with that.
And then the TextBlock next to it, it'll have the Text,
.
Like that.
FontSize="18".
And I know I'm going to need some padding on the left.
Actually let's go Margin on the left,
"10,0,0,0".
And then on the ListView, I'm going to set the ItemsSource
ItemsSource=""
ItemsSource="".
Alright, let's see if that works.
It may not look pretty, but let's just
make sure it even works here.
Oh.
Where do I have,
MenuItems being paged cannot be found on it.
IconFile, Category, wait, what?
MenuItems.
Uh, whoops, whoops.
ListView, I'm going to need a template here.
Kind of got ahead of myself there, didn't I?
And let's go x:DataType="data:MenuItem".
x:DataType="data:MenuItem".
That should work, let's build it.
Okay.
What did I do this time?
Oh, here again, same issue as before.
MenuItems = new List.
And go.
That is not what I had in mind.
Somewhere I have erred.
What did I do wrong?
All right, I think I just lost my mind, that's all.
Let's see if that works, fixes it.
There we go.
Alright, this, the margins and everything are off,
but we can fix that pretty easily.
I'm going to actually do that in the next video,
this one's getting kind of long.
Okay, so we created two Data Sources,
one for Menu, but the main one is for the Sounds,
and we also created a SoundManager that lets us
get at those sounds and split them up by category.
And we'll continue working on this
in the next lesson when we actually now
hook up the sounds to the media element
and start playing things, that'll be exciting.
Okay, we'll see you in the next video, thanks.