Hi, I'm Bob Tabor with www.learnvisualstudio.net.
In this lesson we gonna combine several ideas
that we just covered in previous lessons in order to create
what I call a "poor man's" hamburger navigation Layout.
Now, why am I calling it a "poor man's" version?
Because I'm trying to give you the simplest, cleanest,
clearest path so that you can implement hamburger navigation
right away in your Windows 10 apps.
There is a "rich man's" version of this detailed at
Jerry Nixon's blog here at the shortcut on screen.
Like I said, Jerry Nixon works for Microsoft.
He's done an awesome job with this particular article.
Let me pull it up here.
"Implementing an Awesome Hamburger Button
with XAML's SplitView control."
The reason why I would call it a "rich man's" version
is because it's more robust.
It includes a bunch more features.
But it's also a bit more complex
if you are indeed an absolute beginner.
Just keep that in mind.
You might want to visit it and bookmark it for later,
maybe after we go through several more lessons.
You'll be able to use his version instead of mine.
What I want to do now is to recreate the hamburger layout
that we saw in the Money app.
When I click on the hamburger little icon at the top,
the SplitView opens up.
When I click it again,
it closes and all we can see is the icons.
Furthermore, whatever we currently select,
you can see that one of the secondary colors,
in this case, a darker green color,
highlights the fact that we're no longer
on the Home tab but rather we're on
what I guess is the Watchlist.
We're not going to implement any of these other
pieces of the puzzle.
We've already talked about many of them.
I'm gonna let you do that
whenever we get to our next challenge.
That's one of the reasons why I wanted to
go through this lesson is because we're gonna use
the hamburger navigation Layout in several of the apps
that we're gonna build together later in the series.
But we're also gonna use it in an upcoming challenge,
what I'm gonna call the Hamburger Heaven Challenge
that'll allow you to kind of implement the full...
The bar at the top of the search and the back arrows,
as well as the hamburger down the side.
Let's go ahead and get started.
I've created a new project called HamburgerExample.
You can see here, all I've done is just open the App.xaml.cs
and I removed the Frame counter.
Let's open up the MainPage.xaml and begin working together.
I'm gonna get rid of the designer view again
just because at this point it's in the way.
The first thing I'm gonna do is create
a couple of Row definitions.
(typing) so create that Rows definition
We're gonna create two row definitions this time.
We're gonna set the Height="Auto" in the first one.
Then we'll set the Height="*" on the second one.
The next thing we're gonna do is create a RelativePanel.
I'm gonna set that into a Grid.Row="0".
I'm not gonna put that on there.
Honestly, I'll just leave that off.
Then, inside of that we're gonna put a Button.
We'll come back to that in a moment,
but that'll be our hamburger button.
Beneath that, what I want to do is add a SplitView.
Here, we're gonna add this into the Grid.Row="1",
that second Row that takes up the * size.
This is where we're gonna do the majority of our work.
Inside of this SplitView,
like we talked about in the previous lesson,
I'm gonna use a ListBox control for all the reasons
I talked about in that previous lesson.
You'll see it all come together here in just a moment.
The ListBox is gonna require us to create
a number of ListBoxItems.
I know we're gonna have several of those as well.
I'll just copy and paste a couple here.
That's our general Layout
of what we're gonna do in this lesson.
Now we just have to fill in the details.
Hopefully, up to this point it makes sense.
The ListBox will sit inside of the SplitView.
Each ListBox item will have an icon on the left
and then Text on the right.
As you select an item from the ListBox,
we're going to handle the Click event
or SelectionChanged Event and...
I don't know if we're going to do anything with it.
I just want to show you how we would actually use that.
Let's start here with the Button control.
The first thing I want to do is give it a Name.
We're gonna name it HamburgerButton.
Then what I want to do is choose a icon that
represents the hamburger.
You'll recall that it has three vertical lines
stacked above each other.
To do that we're gonna find that there's
a specific FontFamily available on Windows 10 devices
called Segoe MDL2 Assets.
What I'm gonna do is open the Character Map application.
You can get to this by going to your Cortana search bar
or in your task bar on the desktop
and typing in Character Map and that should find it.
What you can do is scroll all the way through all of these
graphic assets for this specific font:
Segoe MDL2 Assets.
I happen to know where this one is at,
where the hamburger icon is.
I just have to find it again
so bear with me one second here.
Obviously, with so many to choose from
it's easy to lose track.
There I go.
It's right here and you can see that the most important part
of this is what you see down here in this little status bar.
You see a capital U+E700
and it's marked for private use.
We don't care anything about that.
The only thing that's important to us is the E700 part.
Let's do this.
Let's set the FontFamily to Segoe MDL2 Assets.
Then we're gonna choose to set
the Content="E700".
I'm gonna put something before and after that E700.
I'm gonna suffix it with a closing semicolon
then prior to that, I'm gonna add an &,
a #, and an X.
Now, I'm also gonna set the FontSize large
so we can actually see it.
You probably wouldn't want to set it to 36
in a real application.
You just have to kind of test it and see what works for you.
I think that's pretty much it.
I think we're gonna add the Click EventHandler for it
to open and close it.
We'll get to that in just a moment.
Now let's take a look at what it looks like in the designer.
Let's blow this up a little bit
so we can actually see what we're looking at.
You can see we've got our button with an icon on it.
Awesome.
We can style up that button to be
one of the primary colors for our apps.
I'm just not gonna do that in this particular example.
So we have our button and now let's move on
to the SplitView itself.
I'm gonna give it a Name 'cause we're gonna need
to reference it programatically.
A Name="MySplitView".
Here we're going to set
the DisplayMode="CompactOverlay".
What I want is for it to show icons.
Then when it comes out I want to overlay
any of the content that's underneath it.
That's why I'm choosing that DisplayMode.
When the Pane is open, I'm going to set it's width to 200.
When it's closed I'm gonna be around this size.
I may adjust it a little bit but I'm going to set
the CompactPanelLength="56".
When I was getting ready for this 56 seemed right,
but we can monkey with that a little bit later.
Also, I want the HorizontalAlignment="Left" on this.
There might be some other settings that we'll want
as we test this and play around with it.
Put all these on separate lines.
Next up is the ListBox.
This is where we're going to actually display items.
Let's go SelectionMode="Single".
We only want to select one at a time not multiples.
That wouldn't make sense in this context.
When the selection changes...
I'm gonna give it a Name, too.
So let's give it Name equals
(typing)
Name="IconsListBox".
Something like that then we're gonna go ahead
and set the SelectionChanged
SelectionChanged equal to a new event.
We'll come back to that later.
Then, we're gonna set for each of the TextBox items.
We're gonna do something like this.
We're gonna open it up and we're gonna need
to add a StackPanel.
We want what comes next to be oriented horizontally.
Then I'm gonna put TextBlock.
This first TextBlock will be the icon.
The second TextBlock will be the actual text.
Where will we get the icon from?
Once again, we're gonna go to the FontFamily="Segoe MDL2 Assets"
FontFamily="Segoe MDL2 Assets"
then we'll set the FontFamily="36".
Finally, we're gonna set the Text equal to...
Now let's find another icon we want to use with Character Map.
We can choose any of these for this example.
You'll just have to hunt through to find something
that you're looking for.
Let me choose something relatively simple like this
little share button that we would see all over Windows 10,
especially on the Edge browser.
I'm gonna select that and it's E72D.
(typing) E72D
We're gonna add a ; after it.
I'll put an &, #, x
above it like so: "&#xE72D;"
I just realized a mistake here.
Font size equals 36. Great.
The next step I want to put the text that comes next to it.
We'll put the Text="First Option".
Very generic, you can come up with something
better than that.
How about I just rename that to "Share".
Think that might be better.
We'll set it's FontSize="36",
and we'll see what that looks like.
We may have to come back and adjust that.
We're gonna do the same thing for the other ListBoxItems.
In fact, we'll just create two.
(typing)
Let's open up our Character Map
and find another icon we want to use.
I'll go ahead and use this star.
Anything that you find is fine.
In this case, E734.
E734, ; after it, &#x before it: "&#xE734;".
Then let's set the FontFamily.
(typing)
FontFamily="Segoe MDL2 Assets".
Finally, the FontSize="36".
Then I'll just put here Text="Favorites".
We'll put it's FontSize="36" as well.
I think I have enough here to work with.
The one thing I will want to do though,
is whenever the selection changes...
Actually, let's back up to the hamburger.
Whenever someone clicks the hamburger,
remember what we want to do.
We want to show or hide the SplitView.
Let's go and select F12 on our keyboard.
We're here in the code behind
and what I want to do is MySplitView.IsPaneOpen = !MySplitView.IsPaneOpen;
MySplitView.IsPaneOpen = !MySplitView.IsPaneOpen;, like so.
Remember we talked about how that would show and hide
the SplitView's Pane.
Let's run and see what happens now.
Alright, not exactly what we had in mind.
I think I see the error in my ways here.
I forgot one crucial, little thing here.
That is, we need to go SplitView.Pane.
Wrap that around our ListBox because it's sitting outside of
the Pane right now.
Great. Let's run it again.
I see that it mostly works. The hover works great.
There's some margin issues here
and that font is way too large but we're very close.
Tell you what, let's go ahead
and modify that FontSize down to 24.
That should help.
Then, I want to put some margin space
to the left of this TextBox.
We'll set Margin.
The reason is because that second TextBlock
is bleeding too close to the first TextBlock.
We want to set some space in there.
We'll put 20px to the left
of both of these TextBlocks.
Great. Now let's run one more time.
There we go, that looks nice.
Then the other thing we'll want to do now is
to just create a SplitView.
We'll set the SplitView's Content.
For our purposes I'm just gonna put a TextBlock in there.
I'm gonna give it a Name.
(typing)
Just to prove that the click actually works
or that the SelectionChanged actually works.
Furthermore, I'm gonna change or add to this ListBoxItem.
I'm gonna give it a Name.
We're gonna call this first one the ShareListBoxItem.
Then the second one, give it a Name="FavoritesListBoxItem"
Name="FavoritesListBoxItem".
Now, in the ListBox SelectionChanged EventHandler.
What I want to do is put my mouse cursor there and hit F12.
That'll open it up in the code behind.
I can do something as simple as this.
What did we name that again?
ShareListBox
if (ShareListBox.IsSelected),
else if (FavoritesListBoxItem.IsSelected).
Each of these cases result...
ResultTextBlock.Text = "Share"
Then we'll do that same.
ResultTextBlock.Text = ""
Here's where you probably want to do
what we talked about earlier with navigation
and load in another Page into a Frame
and that Frame would sit in the middle
where we currently have the content area.
That's something that you're actually going to need
to do for the next challenge.
Let's see what we have here.
You can see that when we select
either of the buttons it changes the selected item.
I can even select then go away and it still selected it
because we have Overlay and not InLine.
Hopefully, that all made sense.
You're gonna need this skill.
This "poor man's" hamburger navigation layout
for our upcoming challenge as we move along
like I said before.
I think we're just about ready to get started with that.
After a quick review we'll get started with that challenge.
We'll see you there. Thanks.