My goal in this video isto display characters in
a list view, and so,to get to that point,
there's gonna be a lot of steps.
Honestly, we're not really allthat close, even though we have
data from the Marvel API andwe deserialized it.
But let's go ahead andget started.
I wanna start by talking aboutthis method we were working with
in a previous video,this GetCharacterList.
There's a couple ofproblems with it.
The first problem is thatthe name doesn't really describe
what the what it does.
GetCharacterList should begiving me a list of characters.
But really what it'sdoing is returning back
the root object forthe entire object graph.
So it's giving me thatcharacter data wrapper.
And that would have to go in and
find the charactersthat are associated
with the character datacontainer, all right?
And sothere's a lot of traversal.
Furthermore, some ofthe characters that will be
brought back won'thave image data.
And soI want to filter those out.
And there's a couple of othersteps too that I need to take in
between there.
What I really wanna dois be able to go from
the mainpage.xaml tothis Marvel facade.
And I want to pass inan instance of an observable
collection of character.
So I have an observablecollection of character that I
can bind to on my main page.
And I want to pass thatobservable collection into
a method here on myMarvel facade and
let it add characters to it andso as we're adding characters
to it, then the listwill grow and grow.
So to accomplish that,what I'm wanna do is change,
first of all, the name of thismethod from GetCharacterList to
GetCharacterDataWrapper and
then I'm gonna make thisa private helper method.
Then I'm gonna call into that
from a public static async
Task calledPopulateMarvelCharacters.
And then you're gonna passin an observable collection.
A character, called
marvelCharacters, so like that.
All right, I'm gonna need toadd a using statement for
the benefit ofthe ObservableCollection.
And then what I want todo is make a call into,
so var characters = actually,
let me start back over again.
Getcharacterdatawrapper =Getcharacterdatawrapper, okay.
Then what I wanna dois var characters
= characterdatawrapper dot.
And so I'm gonna have totraverse through the character
data container.
And it has a propertycalled results,
which is a list of characters.
So let's go data.
So characterwrapper.data.
And then I seewhere the issue is.
It's not giving me what Iexpect in IntelliSense because
I didn't add the await keyword.
And now, I should be ableto use IntelliSense and
find what I'm looking for.
Get data.results and
that should give me backa list of characters.
Now what I want to do is iteratethrough the list of characters,
so foreach var character andcharacters.
And I'm gonna add each characterto the marvelcharacters
that I passed in,the observable collection of
character, Like so.
Whoops, character.
There we go.
Now in between here, I need tofilter out, so fIlter characters
that are missingthumbnail images.
And so what we'll do is this.
If the character.thumbnailis not equal to null.
And the character.thumbnail.pathis not equal to an empty string.
And then from experience, I knowthere's one more situation.
It's possible that a character'sthumbnail doesn't exist.
It's possible thata character thumbnail,
the path is empty string.
But it's also possible thatthey return back this long URL
that will actuallydisplay an image.
But it's an imagenot available image.
It has a little outline ofa character with not available.
The text inside of it sothis what we'll do.
character.thumbnail.path isnot equal
to this magic string,this URL that I have, okay?
Now, before we go any further.
I'm gonna take this magicstring, I'm gonna cut it out and
I'll put it in a constant.
private constant stringimagenotavailablepath =,
and then we'll pastethat string in there,
and I'll copy andpaste that here.
So now we're pretty sure thatthe character has an image and
we can use them in ourapplication, so at that point.
Then we're gonna addthem to the application.
Now, let's take a lookat the documentation.
Go to the How-Tos section andlook at Images.
If you take a look atthe thumbnail JSON,
notice that there's a path andan extension property.
That's not everything you need.
There's missinginformation here, and
you fill in the type of image or
the size and the orientationof the image that you want.
So if you scroll down, there'sthis Image Variants area here.
And you can see that there'sa Portrait Aspect Ratio
where you have a portrait,square or standard, and
then the landscape right?
And so then and even within thatyou had different sized images.
So for our purposes, we'regonna use a portrait small,
that'll be a little image nextto the name of the character
in the list of characters thatwe're working on right now.
And then, once you clickon a character and
you see all the detailsof that character,
then we're going to displaythe standard extra large.
So what we're gonna needto do then is to go
over to our Model's Folder, openup the CharacterDataWrapper,
and look at the Thumbnail class.
And what I want to do is add twoadditional properties that will
be ignored while we'redeserializing into the object
graph but will be useful now aswe're populating a observable
collection of charactersthat we intend to bind to.
So I'm gonna go prop, prop,prop tab, tab, string tab tab.
Small enter, enter, prop,tab, tab, string tab,
tab, large enter, enter.
So we have two new properties,and I'm gonna populate those
properties here insidethe if statement.
So, we'll gocharacter.thumbnail.small
= string.format, and
then I'm gonna need tokinda follow that pattern.
Where we had the path/ then theimage that we wanted to use and
that's gonna be a standard, so
a square,small size dot andthen whatever the file
extension is that theygive us passed in, right?
And sothen we'll just enter those
replaceable values,giving it the path.
And then also the extension,
like that.
And we're gonna dothe exact same thing for
the large version.
So, character.thumbnail.small,let's go large.
Equals, andhere we want to go the portrait.
And then, we want to change,they don't have a large,
they have an extra large.
That should be aboutthe right size for us.
All right, great.
Very good.
Now that we haveall this in place,
I think we're ready toopen up the MainPage.xml.
And let me get ridof my webcam here so
you can see the entire screen.
Let me go back so
you can look at the righthand side of the code here.
You can pause it andcatch up with me.
And then also, you can pause ithere and take a look at this
URL, or you can just look at thesource code associated with this
snapshot, this snapshot in time,all right?
Back to the MainPage.xml.
Let me rid of that,and let's open up
the MainPage.xml.cs andwhat I'm gonna
want to do is to createa property so prop tab, tab.
This is gonna bean ObservableCollectionCharacter
called MarvelCharacters.
And I'm gonna need to adda using statement for
the ObservableCollection,and a using statement for
the character,all right very good.
Then I'm gonna want to, in theinitializer for the main page,
I'm gonna create a newinstance of Marvel character.
So MarvelCharacters = new ObservableCollection(Character-
>().
So far so good.
Now, we're not gonna havea button click event, and
we really don't need anyof this stuff anymore.
So, I'm gonna stripall that out, and
we'll come back to it later.
In the main pages on XAML I'mgoing to get rid of the button,
and I'm gonna removethe background.
And inside of here, what Iwanna do is use that technique
that we learned aboutearlier in this series,
where we have contenton the left and
content on the rightin a wide layout.
But when the layoutbecomes smaller,
we're gonna take the contenton the right and
move it beneath the maincontent on the left.
And so to accomplishthat what we'll do is,
we're gonna createa four by four grid.
So we'll go Grid.RowDefinitions,and
we'll create tworow definitions.
And we'll set the heightof the first one to *,
and the height ofthe second one to Auto.
And we'll modify some ofthis information, especially
the column information, wheneverwe add the adaptive triggers.
So, ColumnDefinitions.
And we're gonna make the firstcolumn definition Auto, and
then the second columndefinition width = *.
Now, there's one last thing thatI wanna do, and that's add a row
definition that willcontain attribution text.
We'll talk about thatin just a little bit.
But I'm gonna set the heightof this last row = 30 for now.
We can adjust that later.
All right, so, to begin with,
on the left-hand side we'regonna have a ListView.
On the right-hand side,
we're gonna have a grid thatwill contain all the details.
So we're gonna follow thisdesign pattern called master
detail where you have a listof items on the left,
you select an item on the left,and
it shows the details aboutthat item on the right.
So we're going to give this thename, MasterListView, and we'll
refer to it like that throughoutthe remainder of the series.
And then,
we're gonna call this grid'sname DetailGrid, and there will
be a bunch of other stuff thatwill goes inside of this.
Finally, I'm gonnaadd a text block and
I'm gonna set the name of thatto, well I don't even know if I
need to set a name, let me justset the text to = Attribution,
we'll come back to thatin just a little while.
And I'll makethe VerticalAlignment = Center,
and the HorizontalAlignment= Center.
All right,let's get that up here, and
move these guys downtheir own level.
And finally what I want todo is add a ProgressRing.
And that ProgressRing, we'regoing to initialize it whenever
we're making a callinto the Marvel API.
Because it could take a while,and then we will hide it
whenever we've gottenthe information that we need.
So what I'll do is, I'm gonnagive it a name cuz I need
to access it programmatically,MyProgressRing.
And I'll make the width 100,and the height 100.
And then I'm gonna setthe Foreground = Gray.
And we're gonna makethe ColumnSpan=2,
and the RowSpan=3, like so.
So it's gonna bedead-center no matter what.
In fact, I'm gonna go ahead and
set theVerticalAlignment=Center, and
the HorizontalAlignment=Centeras well.
Nice.
Okay, so we should be able touse that whenever we start up.
In fact, when we startup let's go ahead and
add a loaded event to our page.
So we're gonna handle itin a Page_Loaded even,
in our MainPage.xaml.cs.
And here's where we'llwind up calling into our MarvelFacade.PopulateMarvelChar-
acters, and
we'll pass inthe MarvelCharacters,
All right, like so.
Now this is awaitable, andthere's one thing that I wanna
do to this while I'mthinking about it right now.
The pattern forcreating your own awaitable
methods is to addthe suffix async.
So for example, here we have ourGetCharacterDataWrapper, and
it's an async method returninga task of CharacterDataWrapper.
It's a pattern to add thatsuffix so people know that
this is intended tobe an awaitable task.
So, we're changing the name toGetCharacterDataWrapperAsync and
I'm gonna hit controlperiod on my keyboard to
open up the refactoringmenu in IntelliSense and
it's going to then remain.
Everywhere I called in toGetCharacterDataWrapper,
it's gonna rename it toGetCharacterDataWrapperAsync.
And notice that now every callto it, which we made the call
right here, in our code, noticethat it has renamed it for us.
And we'll do the same thingwith PopulateMarvelCharacters.
I'm gonna add the Asynckeyword on the end and
then hit Ctrl+ on my keyboard,and
I'm gonna choose the refactoringto rename that as well.
And so now,in our MainPage.xaml.cs,
it should have the new name andit does.
Of course now it's awaitable,so we're gonna have to call
awaits, that means thatwe're no longer void.
Or actually, let's just do this,async, like that, great.
And the next thing that we'regonna do is, let's go ahead
while I'm thinking aboutthis and go MyProgressRing,
we're going to setthe IsActive = true.
As we're loading,MyProgressRing.Visibility will
also equal Visibility.Visible.
And then the oppositewill be true once we've
successfully populatedthe Marvel characters and
called into ourPopulateMarvelCharacterAsync.
So we'll set IsActive = falseand then Visibility.Collapsed.
All right, so that should work.
Now, in the MainPage.xaml,
I want to work primarilywith the ListView.
And I'm going to DataBind,to that Marvel characters.
Let's set the ItemsSource=x:Bind
MarvelCharacters, like that?
And then we're gonna need toadd a ListView.ItemTemplate and
inside of thata DataTemplate and
I'm gonna need to adda DataType, right?
And so at this point I need tocome back up to the top, and
I need to add a name space so
xmlns:data=using:HeroExplorer.M-
odels.
So now, I can use the DataTypeCharacter, like that.
And inside of my DataTemplate,I want to use a StackPanel and
orient the items horizontally,and
the items will be an Image anda TextBlock, and
the TextBlock will containthe name of the character.
So I'm going to go ahead andset the text attribute
equal to an x:Bind statement,and we'll use the name.
And the Image,we're gonna use a Source.
And we'll setthe x:Bind equal to
the thumbnail.small, like that.
All right, let me build it.
And we're gonna give it a whirl.
Okay, great we've gotdata in a data bound.
Now, I'm not really crazyabout where it stuck
the attribution there.
I think I missed something.
In fact,I know I missed something.
Let's set the details grid,
Grid.Column = 1,and Grid.Row = 0.
And we're gonnadynamically modify these
whenever we add adaptivelayout to the application.
We have to do this tothe TextBlock as well.
That's why it wound up kindof in the middle there.
So Grid.ColumnSpan = 2 andthe Grid.Row.
Will equal two.
Now let's save that and run it.
Okay, now a couple of things.
I'm not crazy aboutthe frame counter [LAUGH].
We'll get rid of that.
Not crazy about theselittle squares.
They're just not inspiring.
I've got a better idea there and
then let's tackleattribution as well.
If you take a look atthe Marvel API and
you go up to the top intothe How-To section and
you select Attribution& Rate Limits,
we're gonna learn two importantpieces of information.
Let's scroll down andlook at attribution.
It says that every time youdisplay any information from
the Marvel Comics API,
you need to use the texton every screen or webpage.
So it's this data providedby Marvel, copyright.
Now they didn't update this for2015 but
I know that that's their intent.
If you take a look at I'm justgonna copy this to my clipboard
and we'll come back toyou just a moment here.
If we take a look at theinteractive documentation and
making sure I'm loggedin here and I am.
Let's open up characters and
let me just bring back likea two characters and try it out.
If you take a look atwhat's brought back,
there is attributiontext that's provided.
It's almost identical,it's just 2015.
So, I'm going to hard codein it in my application but
ideally you would pull that fromthat top level root object,
the data character wrapper,okay?
So I'm gonna go back here and
just hard code this text andchange 2014 to 2015.
So textblock text equals dataprovided by Marvel period and
then the copyright symbol 2015Marvel and we might address
the date later or just pullfrom our call-out to Marvel.
All right, so far so good.
Now, I said that I hadan idea for the image.
I wasn't really crazy abouthow we went about it.
What I'm gonna do isactually put every image
inside an ellipse.
So I'm gonna use the ellipse tokind of define the boundaries
and inside of that I'm gonnause a different brush.
Not a solid colored brush.
Not a gradient color brush,but rather an image brush and
the image brushwill have the image
that will bind to fromthe character object.
So we'll just start off withan ellipse, easy enough, right.
Width equals 45 andheight equals 45 and
then inside of that I'mgonna use  and
I'm gonna put an .
I'm gonna set the ImageSource
equal to a binding statement so
x:Bind thumbnail.small.
Spell it right.
Like that andI missed a quote mark there.
What am I missing?
And I missed a quote mark there.
Wow, I'm slipping.
Okay, let's try this again.
Attribution text looks good,
still gotta get rid ofthat frame counter.
Okay, so now look atthe effect that we get here.
There's a a circle.
Very nice.
The next thing that I wanna do,well,
let's do a couple of things.
I'm gonna add a little bit of,let's put like,
for example, the verticalalignment here equals center.
I'm gonna use font size equalssomething a little bit larger
like 18 and then I'm alsogonna add a margin equal to
ten pixels, well yeah, ten,no, ten pixels to the left
and overall I wannaadd a little margin.
Ten from the left, the five fromthe top, zero from the right,
and five from the bottombetween each item.
We'll see what that gives us.
All right,I like that a lot better.
Very nice.All right and
then the last thing I'm gonnado for this video is actually
once and for all vanquish mynemesis, the frame counter.
Bam.
Okay, all right solet's stop right there.
I think we madeplenty of progress.
Let's, in the next lesson we'regoing to display the details for
the character by selecting oneof the characters in the list
view, okay?
We'll start back therein the next video.
See you there.
Thanks.