Ok, so continuing on, in this lesson
we're going to layout the user interface for the game.
We're going to set up the data binding.
We've already collected a lot of data,
now it's time to connect it to a GridView,
and the DataTemplate and each
individual item and make it clickable,
we'll come back to that part,
and to basically do initial game setup.
So, the game won't be playable by the end of this video,
but will in really good shape to
actually start the game logic like scoring
and countdown in the next video.
Alright, so let us get started now.
Where I left of in the previous video,
there was an issue, and it wouldn't compile,
or it wouldn't run, I don't remember which.
But the issue is easy, basically all I need to do is this,
I didn't new up songs, so that's why it croaked.
If I add that and create a new instance of
ObservableCollection now we should
be able to run the application.
While we won't see much behind the scenes,
it should be going out and grabbing all of the files.
and grabbing off all the metadata,
and then creating new instances of the
song class and making those available
for the rest of our app, again,
not a whole lot going on here unfortunately,
but behind the scenes there's a lot happening.
It's time to kind of rectify that,
and to get started with this I'm going
to open up MainPage.xaml and we're
going to start laying out the pieces
that we need for this app.
I'm going to start off by adding two rows,
so there's going to be a first RowDefinition
that will just be, i think it's just going
to house the countdown bar.
We'll make it 100, and the other RowDefinition
will just be for the remainder of that space.
Then we're going to add a StackPanel,
this is just going to be that first row
where we're going to add a ProgressBar.
I'm going to go ahead and give it a name
because we're gong to have to reference
that programatically, so name equals....
I'm going to set the maximum value to 100
and the minimum value to 0.
I'm going to set the current value to 100
we're going to use it as a countdown,
so it'll always start at 100 and tick backwards.
Also, I'm going to go ahead and
set the height of this to 20 and
the foreground equals blue.
Again, I could really use some help
from a graphic designer to make this look good.
I'm also going to add in that top area
the instruction TextBlock,
so let me go ahead and give it that name,
instruction TextBlock...
This is going to tell the user what to do next.
Hey, get ready because the next
round is starting in ten, nine, eight sort of thing.
I'm going to set the foreground equal
to blue again there, and the horizontal
alignment I'll set to center.
Then I'm going to go ahead and
put the media element in here.
It doesn't have visual quality but
I'm going to go ahead and stick it there.
I'm going to set the auto play equal to true.
I changed this to capital "M" on MyProgressBar.
I go back and forth on what to name
the XAML elements because I'm not sure
that they're public, I think they're more protected,
so, it's really a judgement call
on what naming convention to use there.
So, that's going to be for Grid.Row equals zero.
Let's put the second panel, StackPanel...
and it's going to be Grid.Row equals one.
I'm going to set the orientation of this vertical
which I don't know that I need to do that,
but I'm going to go ahead and do it anyway.
Then, the majority of this is going to
be a GridView control.
Let's go ahead and give the GridView
the name of song GridView,
and I'm going to set the is item click enable equals true.
I'm going to go ahead and handle an item click event,
I'm also going to....
set the ItemsSource.
ItemsSource equal to...
what we created in the previous video, the Songs collection.
That should be visible
to this MainPage.xaml.
Did I make that private?... yeah, I made that private,
it still should be visible here though
because they're in the same class right?
Let's add an ItemTemplate,
GridView.ItemTemplate ...
inside that ItemTemplate, we're going
to add a DataTemplate,
we're just going to just add a simple
Grid with an Image control.
I should probably call this AlbumArt.
I'm going to make the height 75
and the width 75 because I happen
to know that's the exact size of each of the
images that are used in the metadata
for the mp3's since I created them myself,
or had a developer create them for me.
I know that I'm going to bind to a
property of songs called AlbumCover,
let me double check that
just to make sure that is in fact the name.
Yeah, AlbumCover is the name of the
property I want to bind to, so let me
go ahead and do that... like so...
That should pretty much do it
for the GridView itself,
we'll come back and obviously have a lot to do there.
Then I need a few TextBlocks to display things,
so there's going to be one called
the result TextBlock, that'll tell you
if you got the answer right or wrong.
There will be another TextBlock
called TitleTextBlock, this will show you
what the correct song title was
in case you missed it.
There will be an ArtistTextBlock
that will display the correct...
artist.
There will be a AlbumTextBlock
to tell you the album that the song
that was playing was performed on.
Now, I know that I'm going to want
another button in case you want to play again.
So, I'm going to call this "Play Again" button,
and the content will be play again.
I'll make the background of this red
and the horizontal alignment will
just be in the center there.
I'm going to set the visibility initially to collapsed
because I don't want to see it until
we get to that state where the game is over
and I want to ask, "Hey, do you want to try it again?"
At which point, then we'll allow that to happen.
So let me also add a clicked event here,
and that should take care of that
and get rid of the button click,
but I'm going to need somewhere to put
all of that code in the button click.
So, I think what I'll do is actually
put that in a Page_Load event, so....
Loaded equals page loaded and let's go there
and look through all that code I cut,
and I'm going to put it there.
We can get rid of that.
Then there's one last thing that I
want to do here as well,
I have two rows, the second row
will obviously take up a majority of the space there.
What I want to do is, we've already got
a StackPanel inside that row one, so the second row,
and I'm going to add another grid
and I'm going to say that it's
grid.row equal to one.
so it's going to sit in that same row,
cell actually, as the StackPanel that I just created.
All this is actually going to have is a ProgressBar,
actually, sorry, a ProgressRing.
I'm going to call this start up ProgressRing.
I'm going to set the horizontal
alignment equals center, and the
vertical alignment equals center.
Let's set the width equal to something
nice and big, like 200 and height equals 200, like that.
Actually, that might be a little bit too big,
let's put that back to that and then let's go
foreground will say grey.
I'm going to put all that on seperate
lines so it's easier to read.
The idea here is that since it's going to
take some time to go through your
entire music collection as you start up the app,
I want to
display the ProgressRing
and when it's finished with that operation,
then I'll hide the ProgressRing.
Alright, so that should do it for layout,
basically, we may have to come and tweak a few things,
margins and things of that nature,
but I think we're pretty much in good shape to go
so, what I want to do is...
Let me see here, oh yeah...
(mumbling)
So when the page loads, we're going
to do some of these things here,
in fact, now that I think about it a little bit,
I might want to take some of the stuff
and put it into its own helper method.
So, let's go private...
and I'm guessing I'm going to have to
make this async task
called SetupMusicList.
I'm going to go ahead and grab off...
I think I'm just going to perform
just these steps right here.
Actually, I think I'm going to have it return...
allSongs.
So, return allSongs, like that.
so we'll go async, and we'll make this a task
that will return allSongs, and allSongs
is an ObservableCollection... of StorageFile.
So that will setup the music list,
I feel good about that.
We'll do something like this...
all songs equals setup music list,
and we'll await that, yeah, that should work.
Then I'm going to create another private helper method,
so private async...
and right now it won't return anything,
except a promise.
PrepareNewGame.
I guess, I'm going to pluck off some of this stuff here.
The first thing I'm going to do is go
songs.Clear(), so this would allow me
to say, "Hey, whatever the previous collection of
songs were when we played the game before
in the last sessions, clear those songs out."
So, this will allow me to reuse this method
to prepare a brand new game.
Then I'm going to grab randomSongs, let me see...
I need to grab that as well.
Actually, I don't want to do that.
Let me think about this for a minute.
I think what I want to do is make allSongs
a public collection, or rather public to the class.
So, ObservableCollection of StorageFile
called all files, like that.
Ok, that makes me feel good actually.
We'll just do this...
Let's not call it all files, let's call it all songs.
And then here we'll just use all songs
because we only really need to get those songs
one time, but every time we want to play
a new game we can reuse that list of songs.
So that's kind of my thought process there.
Probably, we'll need to do some other things,
like we'll need to do some state management here,
and we'll get to that later.
Back to page loaded, so I do all that to do this.
I'm going StartupProgressRing.IsActive equals true.
Then I'm going to set up the music list,
then I'm going to await prepare new game,
then I'm going to call StartupProgressRing.IsActive
equals false... great.
Let's see if this actually works.
So I forgot a couple of things here.
Alright, let's see if this will even build.
It did not like something here.
It has the wrong return type.
It does not like that I have put this here,
so let's go ahead and rethink that a bit.
Let's go private void here, and
instead of putting all of this here,
I need to make sure at a minimum,
this Grid actually ready for action.
On the Grid itself...
I'm going to get rid of this background.
Alright, and now we'll stick them in there.
I think I can do this and then...
async task... I should probably be able to do void there.
Let's build it and see what happens.
So build went well.
Oh my goodness, it worked, look at that.
How cool is that?
Alright, so we were able to data bind.
Got some margin issues here at the top.
This doesn't do anything when we click on these items,
but we're in really good shape here.
I'm almost thinking that's all I
really wanted to accomplish.
Let me add around this,
let's go margin...
20 20 20...
That should help that.
Oh did you notice the little...
The ProgressRing popped up too, that's awesome.
Ok, one other thing I want to do with
my StackPanel here.
Let's go up and put margin equals 20
and that should just do for all sides.
Nice, ok, very good.
Alright, so that's pretty exciting.
We made a lot of progress here
in a short amount of time,
so I'm going to go ahead and stop right here.
We'll pick it back up in the next lesson.