Alright so this is the
part of the solution
for the Stupendous Styles Challenge that
involves the Pickup Date and Time.
As you can see here on the screenshot,
we're going to need the logo again,
we've already got a Style for that, that should be easy.
Looks like we're going to need
a Row with two Columns in it,
and then we'll need that DatePicker and TimePicker.
That should be pretty easy.
Let's go ahead and, actually I'll keep that open.
Let's get rid of that
and so let's open up the SchedulePage.
I think the very first thing we can agree on
that we need to do is set the Background="Green".
Okay, and so the next thing I'm going to do is
actually go to the DonutPage,
and I'm going to grab some of this stuff here
and I'll grab that,
and I'm going to paste it,
see how much did I grab?
Okay, there we go.
I sometimes forget what I copy
and what I need to paste over.
Alright, looks like we're going to need a back Grid down there.
Okay, so let's see what this looks like.
Okay, pretty good start.
And I think this was supposed to say pickup, right?
And here we're going to have the DatePicker
I think the DatePicker was on top right?
Let's look at this.
Yeah date picker
and in the next row we'll have the time picker, pickup.
Great, pickup, DatePicker.
Place holder text? No. Okay.
Well, I think that's all we're going to do there.
Grid.Row="1"
and a Grid.Column="1".
And then the TimePicker.
TimePicker... Grid.Row="2"
Grid.Column="1".
There might be some Margins, but you know,
this is I think almost all we need.
Yeah, I'm not crazy about the date format.
What did we have here?
Select a date, huh.
Oh, you know what, I got the wrong DatePicker.
This should be the CalendarDatePicker.
There we go, and let's go ahead and
set the Foreground="White" while we're at it.
And we'll do the same thing for the TimePicker.
Alright, that's a little more I like it.
There we go.
Awesome,
and I think that's all we gotta do for that.
See, this one was simple,
and most of it was just copy and paste,
but there was a lot of functionality on that Page.
Okay, so let's, without further ado, let's move on.