Hi, I'm Bob Tabor with www.learnvisualstudio.net.
Previously, we saw how to use AdaptiveTriggers
and the VisualStateManager to change the layout
of your application based on the current window size.
We viewed, then, after that, a technique using
AdaptiveTriggers and the Visual State Manager to make
dramatic changes to the layout of an application
using a little creativity and a GridControl,
and then based on the given Trigger
for the different layouts
to put a series of StackPanels
in different cells of a Grid,
and then also change up the call spans,
things of that nature, and it worked great.
But, in this lesson, we're going to take a look
at a second technique that allows you to create
a dedicated view for a given device family
that your application could potentially run on,
and, at run time, the dedicated view,
or what they call the "DeviceSpecificView"
will be chosen based on the device
that your app is currently running on.
It's a very simple technique,
Microsoft has made it extremely for you easy to use this,
however there are a few advanced techniques
and I'm going to show you a great article
that will dive into those advanced,
those advanced topics related to this.
But let's show the demo that I created, first of all here.
As you can see, I have just a simple
"Hello World" style application
running on the desktop.
"Hello Desktop DeviceSpecificView"
Now, you saw that we had a Blue Background
and we had a fairly large Font,
if I were to change the device that this runs on,
choosing one of the mobile emulators to debug on.
let's go ahead and run the application again,
and this time you can see that the Background is Red
and that we have a smaller Font used for
"Hello Mobile DeviceSpecificView."
Notice that the word is changed there at the top,
Now, at first glance, you might say, well,
this doesn't look any different
as far as the results are concerned
from the techniques that we looked at previously.
That's absolutely correct,
however take a look at the implementation,
now keep in mind the simplest implementation
that I could possibly show you
in order to demonstrate the technique.
You can take this as far as you want to go.
So, in this case, I created two
additional folders in my Project.
One is called "DeviceFamily-Desktop"
and the other one is "DeviceFamily-Mobile"
and by creating these folders any Pages
that I add to those folders will be
utilized at run-time for your application.
So, you can see that I've created
two "MainPage.xaml"
In this first folder, the "DeviceFamily-Desktop" folder,
I've added a Grid with the Background="Blue"
and the TextBlock with different Text
and the different FontSize.
Now, you might say to yourself,
"Well, this is great, its much cleaner
than using the VisualStateManager
and the AdaptiveTriggers." and that's true,
and I think that's one big benefit,
especially if you are going to make dramatic
sweeping changes to your layout based on the device.
Here is the second "MainPage.xaml"
inside of the "DeviceFamily-Mobile" folder,
let's go ahead and take a look at the Grid now,
I just set it to Background="Red".
TextBlock, changed up the Text in the TextBlock
and changed the FontSize
Again, no VisualStateManager,
no AdaptiveTriggers, pretty easy stuff.
And, so, I think that, you know, you can
think about this in terms of using
entirely different controls for layout
based on whether you anticipate this will be
used in a desktop or a mobile.
Now, one of the things I want to say here is that
while the specific, little, tiny application that I built
does not utilize the
VisualStateManager or AdaptiveTriggers,
you might still hope to use that for your application
because there are different screen resolutions
even inside of these different device families.
So, just keep that in mind,
that while they do overlap in functionality,
its not a complete overlap.
You may still, you might choose
a combination of these two techniques,
just the only difference would be
what functionality that you would display
for a phone at a, you know, a 1080p screen versus
what you would display on the desktop at a 1080p screen.
You see what I'm saying?
Because when you' re holding a physical device,
like this device here,
your thumbs are going to be at the bottom of the device
and so you might change up the layout
based on how most users use their app,
or their phone, rather, with just their thumb,
so you'd probably leave this to just
purely information here at the top,
and then at the bottom it would be more
controls that would allow you to
type things in or make selections.
Whereas on a desktop, you know, you're using a mouse
and you're scrolling around the entire screen,
it doesn't really matter where you put things.
So, just keep that in mind,
these are not mutually exclusive techniques,
they can be used together.
Now, I promised you a great resource
to learn a little bit more about this technique.
So, let me show you this URL,
bitdo.device-specific-views,
this will take you to an article
written by a gentleman by the name of Igor Ralic,
I hope I pronounced his name correctly.
But, let's take a look at that
because I want to show you that
you can take this example two steps further.
First of all, we only talked about
using the folder called
"DeviceFamily.Mobile" and "DeviceFamily.Desktop,"
however, you can also just leave everything
in the same root folder
and then just append on this extension
"DeviceFamily-Mobile.xaml" or
"DeviceFamily-Desktop.xaml"
and it will work the same way.
Now, if you have two files with same name
or you have one named this way,
where you've actually changed the file name
and you have a folder that has "DeviceFamily-Mobile'
with the "MainPage.xaml" inside of it,
then you can take a look at this,
kind of what I would call the advanced scenario,
where he describes how you can use the
initialized ComponentEventHandler
to choose at runtime which version
of "MainPage.xaml" you'll choose from.
So, I'll leave you to that,
if this is something you're interested in.
But, at any rate, I hope that this makes sense
and that you'll find it helpful.
I think, again, another tool in your
toolbox for AdaptiveLayout
and it can be combined with what you
already know about using AdaptiveTriggers
and the VisualStateManager.
Alright, so that's all we've got to say about that,
we'll keep moving forward in the next video.
Thank you!