Hi, I'm Bob Tabor with www.LearnVisualStudio.NET.
I'm going to let you in on a little secret,
nobody memorizes all this stuff,
at least not at first.
It would probably take you
several months of working
and building applications in order
to really internalize a lot of this.
Intellisense is just awesome,
and it really helps you through a lot of the rough spots.
Little code snippets online are great,
I use cheat sheets, which allow me to,
they're just basically notes that I've gathered
from watching a video series,
or from reading articles online.
It helps me to organize the information,
see it visually, and then organize it in my mind as well.
We're going to use this as a form of,
of review throughout this series of lessons.
This is what I promote on LearnVisualStudio.NET,
and it's a great way to index in to the content to
remind yourself of what the major ideas where,
the crux of those videos.
You can always remove the stuff you don't need,
you can add stuff that you might think
might be helpful in the future to make this your own.
Now, I'm going to copy and paste from some notes,
I use to type all this in by hand,
but admittedly it was a
very slow and painful process for both
the teacher and for the learner.
You can see here that I've created on my desktop
a little cheat sheet,
I would encourage you to do the same thing,
UWP-Cheat-Sheet.txt.
You can call it anything you want,
you can put it anywhere you want to put it.
This is just the way I'm going to do it in this series,
and I'm going to begin to just type in
or copy paste things in here,
and you should feel free to do the same.
You can use mine, or you can type it in yourself.
I would recommend you type it in,
it creates a little muscle memory.
But at any rate, we're going to create a cheat sheet,
and I'm going to paste in
the big idea from a lot of the lessons.
As we got started, you know, there wasn't a whole lot
that we could add
that would be useful long term,
because it was a lot of high level ideas.
But, when we got into XAML itself in lesson number four,
we talked about the nature of the XAML syntax,
how it is just a flavor of XML,
or rather it uses XML to implement the syntax.
to implement the syntax.
And when you're writing XAML,
you're really behind the scenes creating instances
of classes and setting attributes
or setting properties of those class instances
that define the user interface.
It's very natural for us to use an XML style syntax
especially to be coming from a web development background.
You're already using HTML to lay out your pages.
Same idea here,
you get designer support as a result of that.
It's a much more succinct language.
We compared writing XAML
by hand versus writing C# by hand
that essentially did the same thing.
And we saved a lot of keystrokes and characters,
and also the XAML parser was very intelligent,
and Visual Studio played along,
and it allowed us to write code much more succinctly
to define our user interface.
All right, moving on from there,
in the next lesson after that,
we talked about some specifics of XAML
and we talked about type converters.
And we said that, this is one of the ways in which
it's made easier to write the XAML
than it is the C# version,
because we can give
attributes of elements, literal strings, in XAML
that are converted into enumerations
or potentially even instances of classes in C#.
So, type converters, one of the items,
one of the tools that would help us keep our code succinct.
We then talked about several different topics
related to XAML in the next lesson,
Understanding Default Properties,
Complex Properties and the Property Element Syntax.
So you can see here that
the default property for a button is the content property,
we set the button's content property to "Click Me",
we could've done the same thing
by just setting that attribute inside.
But by understanding default properties,
that kind of led us to the next step in the process,
which was to talk about complex properties.
So I've got kind of a big chunk of code here,
I'm going to paste it in.
Unfortunately, let's turn off word wrap
for just a moment here so you can see this.
We have
a button, and we're setting the background
of the button
in a complex property,
setting its property, the background property using the
property dot element syntax.
And, remember in this example,
there was a lot more going on,
but it was hidden from us
by Visual Studio and the XAML parser,
because a lot of that could be inferred by the context
of what we typed in between the elements
that we had here
in this particular context property.
All right, then next up we talk about
the XAML schemas and namespace declarations.
And we said that stuff at the very top of the page,
don't touch it.
We also said that the schemas
are part of XML and XAML is no different,
it has a number of different schemas.
I think we saw like five or six different ones,
and they define the rules for the XAML syntax itself
for the controls that are defined
in the Universal Windows Platform API.
They're used for designer support by Blend and Visual Studio
and so on.
And then the little namespaces that were created,
the little whatever it was, some value and then a colon,
they tell the XAML parser where to find the definition,
or rather the rules for a given element in the XAML.
Now a lot of the XAML that we write
will have no namespace little prefix in front of it,
because a lot of it's defined in the default namespace
for our page.
Moving on, we talked about layout,
specifically about layout grids, with grids,
but let's start with just talking about layout in general.
The layout controls don't have a content property
like a lot of the other controls have.
Instead they have a children property of type UIElementCollection,
this allows us to add multiple items
into a single layout control.
And we saw what happened whenever you attempt to put
multiple controls inside of a control,
inside of the Content property of a control,
you get that little error that you're trying to set
the Content property more than once and it won't let you do that.
So, by embedding any control
inside of a layout control inside of its elements,
you are implicitly calling the add method
of the children collection property for that given element.
So Grid.Children.Add(MyButton).
All right, and then let me give you a quick definition of a Grid,
and I just copied this from one of our examples.
Here you can see that we defined both rows and columns
using property element syntax.
Whoops, let me get rid of that one,
I wonder how that got in there.
Much better, okay.
So we have RowDefinitions,
and then we define the number of rows.
This is all out of whack, okay, there we go.
And notice that we set the heights and the widths as well,
which the sizes can be expressed in a number of different ways.
And, let me paste that in here.
Let's turn word wrap back on.
Come back down here, okay.
So it can be
expressed in terms of
explicit pixel sizes, right?
So I can set it, so equal to like
100 for example.
But we said that that was a bad idea,
because we're working with different form factors
even within a given device family,
and it may not look correct on a given form factor.
So we would prefer to use auto and star sizing,
which are relative ways of expressing sizes.
Auto will use the largest value of the element it contains
in order to define either the width or the height
of that given row or column respectively.
Or we can use star sizing,
which says utilize all the available space that we have.
So, we also saw an example where we were able to
prefix the star with a number.
And so, for example, we saw how one star
would essentially be saying
of all the space available give me one share of the total.
Whereas three star would say
hey give me of all the available space,
give me three shares.
So essentially in this example that I created right here,
there would be six total shares,
and a three star would be
essentially either 50% of the width or the height
depending on what we were defining.
We also talked about how elements will
put themselves inside of the grid
at a specific row, column, or a specific cell.
And we use this
attached property syntax,
remember that Grid.Row is not defining the button,
it's actually defining the grid control,
but we can attach it
and say hey I want to set myself
to this row and this column.
So that's how we will actually work with
the grid control and define where we want
to put ourselves, to put our controls.
Also, notice that whenever we're
referencing rows and columns that it's 0-based,
so by setting the row equals zero,
we're saying first row,
one would be the second row and so on,
same thing with columns.
There's always one default implicit cell,
there's always on every grid a row zero column zero
even if we don't define it explicitly, okay?
And so if we don't specify that
whenever we're working with
a given object that we're trying to place inside of a cell,
that it will be in the default cell,
or the default row, or the default column.
So in this case we're saying
set the row equal to zero, first row.
We could have left that off completely
and it would have been the same thing.
Also by not defining the Grid.Column,
we're essentially saying Grid.Column="0"
because we're saying put it in the,
the default cell.
That's all we said about the Grid.
We moved down and talked about the StackPanel,
here's a simple definition of a StackPanel.
We can also set various properties of the StackPanel,
and we talked about the
vertical orientation is the default,
so from top to bottom
the first text block will be at the top.
Below it, vertically, will be the next text block.
We can change that to a left to right flow
if we were to set the orientation to horizontal.
That should be ... "Alignment" should be
"Orientation", okay.
Most layouts will combine multiple layout controls
in order to get the desired effect,
and you'll see that as we build real examples throughout
the remainder of the series.
And then we also said
the fundamental difference between a Grid and StackPanel
is that Grids will allow you to overlap controls,
so if you put three controls in the same cell,
and you set the top and the,
the vertical alignment to top
and the horizontal alignment to left,
they will essentially stack on top of each other.
And you may not be able to see items below
or underneath other elements in the same cell.
However, StackPanel will always stack things
on top of each other, or horizontally left to right.
Okay? So that's all I have for this review,
let's pick it up with a little exercise
that will hopefully get you working
and get these concepts under your belt.
We'll see you in the next lesson, thank you.