Hi, I'm Bob Tabor, withwww.learnvisualstudio.net and
this is the solution video for
the challenge I callthe Hamburger Heaven Challenge.
Without further adolet's go ahead and
get started, make sure thatyou're only watching this video
after you've struggleda little bit.
So I'm gonna go ahead andcreate a project.
And we're gonna make sure it isa blank app universal windows
template project.
I'm gonna call thisHamburgerHeavenChallenge.
All right and I'm just gonnafollow the instructions as they
appear in our littleinstruction file here.
So let me open that up as welland I'll keep it off here to
the left side and I can get toit pretty easily from there. Okay.
So, one of the first
instructions was that you gonnaneed to find the two images
that are availablecalled food png and
financial png andadd them to your assets folder.
Great. Okay. So
here's what I'm gonna do isactually gonna get rid of that.
I have them on my desktop atthe moment and I'm going to
select them both and drag anddrop them into my assets folder.
So far, so good.
All right, and next up saidthat you have to add two pages
to your app, Food.xaml andFinancial.xaml.
And each of these willhost single image control.
We're gonna set the Source tofood and financial, great.
That's easy enough.
So with the project selectedhere, I'm going to go to Project
> Add New Item, make surethat I add a blank page.
Gonna call the firstone Financial.
And then I'm gonnaadd another one and
it's gonna be called Food.
All right, and let's goahead and get rid of that.
And inside of here, I'm gonnaactually get rid of that.
I'm gonna add an image control.
I'm gonna set the source equalto Assets, and this is food.png,
and then I'm also gonna setthe the VerticalAlignment="Top"
just to make sure that it buttsitself up against the top.
That's all I should haveto do for Food.xaml.
And then we'll do the samething for Financial.xaml.
Get rid of that.
Get rid of that Background.
Add an Image.
Set the Source.
Equal to Assets/Financial.png,and
the VerticalAlignment to Top.
All right, so far so good.
All right,let's get rid of that.
And actually while I'm here andI have the App.xaml.cs I'm
going to go ahead andrip out frame counter.
All right, good.
All right, instruction number 3,you must create an app featuring
hamburger style navigationusing a SplitView.
It must also display a searchbar in the upper right hand
corner, hamburger button,back button, title of the page.
Very good.Okay, so let's go ahead.
That's gonna be the big step sofar.
Again, let's get rid of that.
We gonna get rid of this and I'mgonna do like I did previously
when I created two rows,the first one would be auto,
the second would be star.
So let's createGrid.RowDefinitions, and we'll
create the first RowDefinition,and copy and paste it.
And we're gonna set the width,or
sorry, the height ofthe first one to Auto, and
then the height ofthe second one to *.
All right, very cool.
Now, in that top one, I'm gonnacreate a relative panel because
we're gonna align some thingsto the left and to the right, so
create a relative panel.
And inside of that relativepanel we're gonna put a button
for the hamburger.
We're gonna create a button forthe back button.
We're gonna create a text box,or
a text block rather, forthe title label at the top.
Then we're gonna create anotherbutton that'll be aligned
to the right-hand side, that'llhave the search icon in it.
And then a text box that
will be where they cantype in their search text.
Okay, great.
So let's name some of these.
Name="HamburgerButton".
This one will bethe "BackButton".
The TextBlock will bethe "TitleTextBlock".
This Button will bethe SearchButton.
So Button Name="SearchButton".
And then this finalTextBox will be
the "SearchTextBox", great.
All right, so next up,let us put, the hamburger
button will be alwaysaligned to the left panel.
So let's goRelativePanel.AlignLeftWithPane-
l="True".
Great.
Here, let me actually put someof these on separate lines.
It'll be easier to see them.
So that's the firstthing we need to do.
And then I'm gonna go ahead andset up the FontFamily.
We know that this is gonnause that hamburger icon, so
we're gonna goSegoe MDL2 Assets.
We'll set the FontSize="36".
And next the Contentis the biggie.
And we're gonna set thatequal to "&#xE700;", right?
And finally,I'm gonna do a Click event here,
and I know I'm gonna need it.
So I'll just go ahead and
add that hamburgerbutton click event.
Great.
Okay, next up we're gonnalook at the back button.
Let's set its RelativePanel
to right of the HamburgerButton.
Okay.
And we're gonna need to changeits font family also to
the "Segoe MDl2 Assets" andthe icon I use.
Let's set the FontSize="36".
The one that I used,
="#exE0C4;" all right.
There's also some coloring,
I might add to thisa little bit later.
But let's add the clickevent to this as well.
Okay, next up,that TitleTextBlock,
and we're gonna make that RelativePanel.RightOf="BackBut-
ton".
And then we're gonnaset it's FontSize="28".
And I know this wasn't veryobvious, but I actually
set the font weight equal tobold which gave it a little
bit of heft to it so that itstood out a little bit more.
I think we're gonna have to addsome margining here as well, but
we'll come back to that.
Next the search buttonto the right most.
So we're gonna go
RelativePanel.AlignRightWith
=.
Whoops.
AlignRightWithPanel="true".
Sorry. AlignRightWithPanel="true",
right?
And we know thatwe're gonna need
the FontFamily="SegoeMDL2 Assets".
And we're gonna setthe FontSize="36".
And were going toset the Content.
And I found the Contentthat we need,
it is at "&#xE1A3" that shouldgive us that little search icon.
Oh, and I forgot, you gotta havethat semicolon on the end or
you're gonna get all thatblue squirly underneath it.
Make sure I did everythingright here so far.
Segoe MDL2 Assets, 36.
Yeah, that looks good so far.
And, we don't really need to puta click event on this because
we're not going todo anything with it.
So, I'll just leaveit the way it is.
And, finally I'm going toadd a search text box, and
we're going to put thaton the relative panel.
We're gonna set it tothe left of the SearchButton.
All right, so hopefully you cankinda picture this in your mind.
And we'll set its Height="48".
And this isn't something thatwe talked about, either, but by
setting the Height, you're gonnaget the larger area for these
are to type in and it'll lookjust more aesthetically correct.
I'm also gonna set the width toget it to look correct as well.
And then I'll setthe FontSize="24", so
that when they type in.
The font.
Something into that text box,it'll be rather large.
And then finally,
did you figure out how todo the placeholder text?
That's kinda easy, honestly.
All you do is go toPlaceHolderText= and
you just type in "Search", andthat'll take care of it for you.
Great.
All right.
So, that should takecare of all the buttons.
Let's take a look atwhat we have so far. Okay.
Everything's pretty large but
it basically works.
Let me make it smaller here.
Okay.
So, we've got everythingthere lined up correctly.
You don't see the text block butit is there.
Okay, great.
So next up,let's handle the SplitView.
So, that's gonna go rightnext to the RelativePanel.
Actually gonna go belowit in the row equals one.
So, a SplitView Grid.Row="1".
And then inside ofthat SplitView we're
gonna need to createa SplitView.Pane,
and then a SplitView.Content.
Yeah, SplitView.Content.
All right.The content one's easy.
Let's just go ahead anddo that right now.
Frame.
And I'm gonna give the framea name called MyFrame.
So, we can referenceit programmatically.
And we'll just do that.
In fact, I don't even need tocreate that extra space there,
let's just rid of that.
Pane is where we're gonna domost of our work here, and so
we're gonna add a ListBox.
So, let's add a list box and
we're gonna adda bunch of list items.
Actually just two ListBoxItem.
So, ListBoxItem.
And now, let's set
the SelectionMode.
I think this is the default,
I'm just gonna setit to single anyway.
And so, we're good there forthe moment.
I'm actually gonna createa closing ListBoxItem tag,
because inside of this,I'm gonna add a StackPanel.
I'm gonna set the orientation ofthat StackPanel to Horizontal.
Because again, we want the iconand then the text next to it.
And so, we're gonna needthat to go horizontally.
All right.So, let's go ahead and
just put two TextBlocksin that stack panel.
In fact, we'll kind of don't,let's just copy all this and
reuse it.
Like that.
So, now we have two.
Great.
All right.So, the first one we're gonna
set the FontFamily= to"Sugow MDL2 Assets".
And we'll set the FontSize="36",just like we've been doing.
And we can choose anyicon that we want, but
I'm gonna use this particularone that I actually
demonstrated inthe assignment video.
So, I believe this is the house.
Use any one you want, though.
So this is &, or
ampersand, #x,
and then E80F;.
[COUGH]
So, that shouldtake care of that.
Let's go on tothe second TextBlock.
And here, we'll just setthe text equal to, well,
we can just do this.
We'll just set inhere Financial.
And we'll set the FontFamily forthis one equal to 24.
That should make itabout the right size.
All right.So, let's just actually copy
this again anduse it here again.
And this time though,I'm gonna change up the icon.
And for that little star,I'm gonna do the E1CE,
that should work there andwe'll call this one Food.
Again, use whichever iconthat you wanna use for
that to go in MDL2 Assets font.
I'm also gonna give each ofthese ListBoxItems a name.
So I'm gonna call thisName = Financial, and
I'm gonna call this Name= what is this, Food.
And you'll see how that comesto play here in just a moment.
We're also gonna needto set in this ListBox
the SelectionChanged event,so we'll set that up.
Probably should've given thata name, but okay, it'll work.
I hate when I make that mistake.
All right.
And before we go and actuallycheck this thing out, and
run it, I'm gonna go tothe HamburgerButton, and
I'm gonna put my mouse cursorinside that event handler name.
Hit F12 on my keyboard, soI can get to that event handler.
And what I wanna do is, so,my, what do we call that?
I don't think we give it a name.
Did we?
We should have callit MySplitView.
Yeah.
It's called my split, so
Name="MySplitView", sohere we go.
MySplitView.IsPaneopen =
!MySplitView.IsPaneOpen; So,
that at least shouldopen it up and close it.
Furthermore, I think we'regonna need to set a couple more
things, now that I thinkabout it on the SplitView.
I mean, we didn't give itsome important stuff like
DisplayMode, and we're gonnause the CompactOverlay.
And then also, we're gonna usethe OpenPaneLength set to 200,
like we did when we worked onthis in one of the previous
lessons when we actually createdthe poor man's hamburger.
And then also, we're gonna setthe CompactPageLength="56",
because that seemed tobe a pretty good number.
Now, we can look andsee what we got.
Okay.
I see that these needto be larger fonts.
So, let's go and fix that.
And I also need somemargins as well.
So look, we had FontFamily="24".
Oh, duh,I'm a silly [LAUGH].
FontSize not FontFamily.
There we go.
Fixed it.
Make sense now. Okay.
So,
let's set the marginon both of these.
Let's put a little space onthe left-hand side there.
There, like so, And I'll copyand paste that to the other one.
So, the Margin=20,0,0,0.
That should fix that problem.
And I also noticed that there isnot a lot of room between, and
I guess I'd never even set thatTextBlock equal to anything,
here.
I'm just gonna runthis real quick.
Okay.
At least that looks good.
All right.So now,
let's get into some ofthe internal parts.
I think we got prettymuch everything there.
You must create two navigationoptions, I guess we did that.
In the main center area,you'll use a frame.
When the application starts,
you want to load theFinancial.Xaml onto that page. Okay.
Great.
So right here, I'm just gonnago in the constructor for
the MainPage.
Let's go My.Frame.Navigate to
the (typeof(Financial));That should work.
I've got a weird littlesituation going on with my
IntelliSense andwith this template.
So, you'll have to excuse mehere as I try to get this to
work right.
All right.That's a little better.
All right.So,
least that should takecare of that situation.
Let's see if weresolve number five. Okay.
Yeah, it did.
It loaded it up when we start.
Okay, great.
I realize I didn'thave this off,
I had it off tothe left hand side.
Number six, clickingthe navigation will take you to
either to a page Food.xaml orFinancial.xaml.
Okay, that's easy enough.
So, here whenever the selectionchanged, let's go ahead and
put our mouse cursor inthat event handler name.
And then F12 andthat'll bring us here.
And so, we'll do something like.
If financial.is selected then
we'll do something else.
We'll do something else andI can do else ifs here.
In fact let me go ahead anddo that just else if so
that it shows how you couldhandle multiple is selected.
All right hopefullythat makes sense.
And so when somebodyselects the financial one,
I wanna set,first MyFrame.Navigate and
then we're gonna send themto Type, Type of financial.
And then I'm also gonna setthe TitleTextbook.Text equal
financial, something we reallydidn't talk about much.
Furthermore, whenthe app first loads up,
I'm gonna need toset that as well.
Like so.
And let's do the samething down here,
With this one andwe'll set this one to food.
And we'll set this to food.
Okay.
Great.
Okay, let's go ahead and run theapp to see what we have so far.
All right, sowe're able to navigate.
All right, we need a littlespace here between this,
between this title textblock and that arrow.
So let's go back intothe MainPage.xaml and
go up to our text block here.
TitleTextBlock.
And I wanna set somemargin in there.
So let's go Margin Equals.
We'll put some spaceon the left of it.
I'm gonna put a littlespace above it, and so
our margin equals 20, 5, 0, 0. Great.
Let's see that how that looks
now, whoops, I put it inthe wrong spot didn't I?
Yep, doesn't belong there.
It belongs here.
And now that should work.
All right great, moving on.
So let's see whatelse we got here.
Here are the instructions.
All right, sowe finished up number five.
Number six, clickingthe navigation will take
you to either food or financial.
We already did that.
The background should onlybe displayed when you're not
viewing the home page.
And I guess I probablyshould say that it should
take you home to.
I forgot to say that butit should.
So, let's go ahead andmanage that state.
So we'll gothe BackButton.Visibility
equal Visibility.Collapsed,
when you're on the home page.
But we'll have it, let's see
Visible when you goto the food page.
Furthermore, we're gonnaneed to make sure that it's
set to collapsed.
When the applicationfirst loads.
All right.
All right, so you can seethat it's not there, but
when I go to food it's there.
When I go back tofinancial it's gone, great.
Okay.
And so now, whenever hit theback button, we need to go to
financial or actually let's justdo it the right way, right.
So, if MyFrame.CanGoBack then.
MyFrame.GoBack.
And one thing I didn'tdemonstrate there is that we're
gonna wanna make sure thatFinancial.IsSelected equals
true, so that, even if we're notclicking on the ListBox item,
it will still show it asthe current selected page.
And I probably should do that
as we're first openingup the application, too.
Hopefully that makes sense.
So I'll show you what I mean.
When we first launchthe application, that should be
selected, however I don't thinkit's loaded up quite yet.
Let's go to food.
Now you can seefood's selected and
then we're gonna usethe back arrow and
it sets the selectionback to food.
So let's do that again.
There we go.
Nice.
All right, now we've done that.
Search button must bealigned to the right.
Okay, we got all that done.
Back button must usea back arrow icon.
Font sizes are good.
Colors include light gray.
Mm-hm, I think we're prettymuch done with this.
Let's run and see.
All right, sowe look good there, that works.
We can go there.
Yeah, all right,I think that's the solution.
Did you come up withwhat I came up with?
Does it work?
Does it look kindalike what I've got?
Hope so, andif you did it congratulations.
That's awesome.
We're well on ourway now to creating
really good looking appsthat belong in Windows 10.
Font sizes might need tochange up a little bit, but
hopefully you get the idea.
Okay.
So let's continue on andkeep learning.
We're gonna talkabout what happens
whenever we're working on aphone device versus on an Xbox.
And that's gonna be kinda inthe next section of lessons and
we'll talk about that next.
We'll see you there, thanks.