Hi I'm Bob Tabor with www.LearnVisualStudio.NET
and this is the solution for the challenge
that I call the Laudable Layout Challenge.
Now, let's stop right here before we get too far.
If you're watching this immediately
after watching the challenge video, the previous video
if you've not cracked open Visual Studio
and written a single line of code yet
then stop what you're doing.
Shame on you!
Open up Visual Studio, do this for yourself.
Nobody learns by just watching videos.
I mean nobody learns by just watching videos
they also have to get their hands dirty in the code.
That's how you learn.
So, stop the video right now.
Don't watch another second of this.
Go off and do the challenge.
If you get stuck, come back here
and watch just enough of this to get unstuck.
All right, we cool?
Let's get started.
So let's create a new project.
I'm going to call this "laudable".
And I spelled that incorrectly once
and had to redo this video, so I learned
how to spell "laudable", if nothing else.
LaudableLayout.
All right, and let's bring up the image
that we're trying to recreate here, all right.
So it looks like we have one, two, three, four, five rows
plus a row at the very bottom, which I'm going to add
that will just kind of
I'll use star sizing to take up all the available space.
That'll make sure everfything else gets pushed up
and it only takes as much as it needs.
Then it looks like there's one, two, three columns
and on my screen as I'm looking at it here
it looks like about an inch for
this last column here on the right.
This looks like maybe two inches here on the left-hand side
and in the center it looks like three inches.
So, this would be a great two star, three star
one star layout, as far as the columns are concerned.
It looks like the rows will just be auto for the most part
so this should be pretty easy.
Let's go and minimize that and bring Visual Studio back up.
And we're only going to be working with the layouts.
Let me open MainPage.xaml and move this over
so we get a good look at this.
And I'm going to do most of the work just here
from memory, in the XAML pane and not really worry
about what the designer looks like too much
we'll come back to that later.
So, first thing I'm going to do is lay out
some rows and columns, so here we go.
Grid.RowDefinition
and then below it Grid.ColumnDefinitions.
And so the RowDefinition
will have a height of "auto"
in almost all cases, and we need five of those.
Two, three, four, five.
And the sixth one, I'm going to set that to star sizing.
Okay?
Let's do the same thing for column definitions.
So we're going to create a column definition
and we're going to set it's width equal to...
I'll come back and fill that in in a moment.
The first one will be one star.
The second one, whoops, sorry, will be two stars.
The second one will be three stars
and the last one will be one star.
Great.
All right, so next up I know that I'm going to need
one, two, three, four text blocks.
So let's go ahead and TextBlock
and I know I'm going to set it in a row
and I don't think I need to change the column at all
in these, so we'll just leave that like that.
One, two, three, four.
This will be row zero, row one
row two, row three.
I don't even need to use this
so I'm just going to delete it.
Let's see.
And then I'm going to need text boxes.
So TextBox.
Grid.Row equals
and then Grid.Column equals
one, the second column.
Let's copy that a bunch of times.
And paste it.
Great.
Then this will be row one.
It'll just match whatever the row is
of the text block above it.
And then finally, let's go and add a button
and this will be in Grid.Row four
and Grid.Column one.
Okay.
Now, let's come up here and set
the Text property for each of these.
So this is "First Name".
This is "Last Name".
And this one's "Email".
Whoops.
Okay and then the Button's Content property
is going to be equal to "Save", all right.
Now let's worry about this top TextBlock.
We want its text equal to
"ACME Sales Corp", all right.
And I know that the font size is going to be 48.
Now, this was the tricky part.
If you found this, good for you.
Grid.ColumnSpan equals three.
So that should make it span and you can see barely here
in the little sliver of our design window
that we get the desired effect.
Okay, let me actually blow the design window up
so we can take a closer look at what we've done so far
because we're getting close to the end here.
Okay, we have some margin issues.
We need more spacing on the left.
We need spacing between each of the rows.
Otherwise we're in good shape.
So, let me get back here, and the first
thing I'm going to do is just create a margin
from the left for the entire grid.
So, we'll go 10 pixels from the left and then zeroes.
That should move everything over from the left.
Next up, we're going to want to create space
between each of the text boxes
to give them a little breathing room.
So, margin, zero, zero
zero, 10.
And that should do it.
And I'll put 10 pixels of space
beneath each of the text boxes
thus stretching out the height of each row.
And I think the last thing that we needed to do
was to ensure that the text block
in each of the rows is centered.
We can see right now it's aligned
to the top and left side of that cell.
And so this is the last thing we'll need to do.
We'll go VerticalAlignment equals center.
Let's copy that and put that in each of the text blocks.
And I think we're done with this.
Let's go ahead and save this and run the application.
All righty.
And there you go, we've got it.
Now, I do see one little annoying thing
that we never talked about.
Whenever you create a new project
you automatically get a frame counter.
That's great, whenever you're debugging
certain types of applications.
We won't need it in this series
so I'm going to get rid of that
and the way you do that is you go to the App.xaml
you go to the code behind App.xaml.cs
and you go down to line number 34, oh I'm sorry, 43.
Had that transposed.
And let's go ahead and delete lines 43 through 48 like so.
And now when we run the app
the frame counter will no longer be there.
Awesome.
Oops, I see one omission here.
There needs to be more space between
this text block and the first row.
So one last thing we'll need to do here.
Let's go up to the TextBlock and let's go ahead
and add a margin there as well.
Margin equals zero, zero, zero, 20.
That should put sufficient space below it.
And there we have it, great.
All right, hopefully you got this.
You know, if this is something you struggled with
then maybe you should come back tomorrow and try it again.
Just to cement these ideas in your mind, okay?
So if you're ready to move on to the next challenge
we're going to do one with StackPanels.
So, we'll see you there.
Thanks.