Okay, the goal in this finallesson is to demonstrate how to
integrate Cortanainto our application.
And I created a small examplecalled Cortana Example.
And it's meant to illustrate, inthe most simplest way possible,
how to integrate Cortanainto your application.
I don't think you'll finda simpler example out there.
So watch what it can do.
Hey, Cortana.
[SOUND] In example appadd a red rectangle.
>> All right,adding a rectangle.
>> Hey, Cortana.
[SOUND] In example app,add a blue circle.
>> Sure, adding a circle.
>> Hey, Cortana.
[SOUND] In example app,add a rectangle.
[SOUND]>> Sure, adding a rectangle.
>> Okay so hopefully
you'll see that there werethree scenarios here.
In the first scenario, I gaveboth the color and the shape.
And the second example, I gavea color and a different shape.
And then the third example,I gave only the shape and
let Cortana decide whatthe color should be.
Except Cortana's notquite that smart.
You have to give it a littlebit more information than that.
And I'll demonstratethat in this video.
All right, so let me show youhow I created this application.
It all starts with somethingcalled a voice command
dictionary.
This allows you to createa series of voice commands that
Cortana will respond to foryour application.
And so in this case you can seethat I've created this XML file.
It follows a veryspecific schema,
as laid out here inthe XML namespace.
We'll talk about where tofind that in just a moment.
You create a set of commandscalled CommandSet for
every language and region thatyour application will support.
So in our case,this is the English-US version.
And it's also important to notethat Cortana's not available
in every region andevery language just yet.
So, the next thing that I dois create a command prefix and
this is why I said hey, hmm,in example app whatever, okay.
So this means thatshe's listening for
this specific command prefix sothat she can identify your
application and send the commandto your application as opposed
to other applications thatmight be running at that time.
You see here that Ihave two commands.
One is addRectangle andthe other is addCircle.
These names are importantbecause I'm gonna utilize them
from within our codein just a moment.
Here I have a seriesof ListenFor elements.
And this will allow me togive variations on a command
that she can stillrespond to and
it still all triggerthe add rectangle command.
So in this first caseshe's listening for
add a rectangle, in the secondcase she's listening for
add a color rectangle.
Now, the little brackets arounda in this case are important,
because thoseare optional words.
So you could say addrectangle or add a rectangle.
Furthermore, if you already usethe color you would have to say
add a color rectangle.
So I didn't use the squarebrackets around the word a.
Now as far asthe color is concerned,
you can see that it'susing curly braces.
And if you look below,
there's a phrase list that goesalong with that label color.
Here we can listen to colorsred, blue, yellow and green.
Any of those colors will be
recognized by Cortanain this command.
Then finally, you can see thatthere is a feedback command, and
this is what she actuallysays back to the user.
So, it says,
okay, adding a rectangle,or okay, adding a circle.
Now these are identicalexcept for
the fact that I'm usingcircle versus a rectangle.
And they triggerdifferent commands.
Notice that there are othercommands that I'm not really
using like thisnavigate command.
That might be useful if I wannanavigate to a different page
in an application.
Not really gonnademonstrate that in this.
This also is an example,
think more just forreference than anything else.
So that you can rememberwhat this is used for.
There are also additionalelements that can be used inside
of a command set.
If you wanna learn moreabout command sets,
here's what you need to do.
Pop open your web browser.
Go to dev.windows.com/cortana.
Then scroll down andgo to Cortana Interactions,
under the Get started area.
And then if you take a lookat any of the articles
that are inside of thisCortana integration section,
you'll find example XML files.
So, for example,in this first article,
launch a foreground app withvoice commands in Cortana.
It talks about the VCD,
or rather the VoiceCommand Dictionary, and
it gives you some example XML.
In fact, I just copied thisXML and paste it into my own
file that I called,CortanaExampleCommands.xml.
So, you wanna referencethat page, again,
dev.windows.com/cortana andthen navigate to
Cortana integrations, andlook at the new articles there.
It'll also give you additionalcommands that you can use for
different scenarios.
Okay so, after Cortanarecognizes the command
prefix and the command itselfby using one of these listen for
items to identify a specificcommand then what we wanna do
is actually receive input forthe application.
Now what I had todo was override
a method called on activated.
And specifically,
I want to know how thisapplication was activated.
Was it activated as a resultof a voice command?
If it wasn't,then I wanna return.
But if it was, then I'mgonna grab out the command
arguments that were passed in-
As I activated event args.
And so we're casting themessentially to a specific
type of event arg, called aVoiceCommandActivatedEventArgs.
And then once we havethe command args for voice,
we can grab off.
The result propertyinto a variable
called speechRecognitionResultand
here I can determine whichcommand was spoken, in which,
the entire text, if I wantto parse through it myself.
Additionally, I can use thatspeech recognition result to
get at, which color inthe phrase list was
selected, was spoken.
And notice here that I'm justindexing N in both cases to
the first item.
It's possible that thereare multiple commands and
multiple phrase liststhat were cast in.
So we're describingthe first one,
and then the rest is reallyjust logic in my application.
In this case, I'm going tocompare the spokenColor that we
grabbed off from the semanticinterpretation of properties
indexing into the color label.
And then I just make sure thatwe return a windows.ui.color and
now what I want to do is geta reference to the main page.
And I'm gonna determineby the voice command.
Was it addRectangle oraddCircle.
And either way,I'm gonna call a method on
the page that I just gota reference to here.
And I pass in the colorthat was selected.
So back in the MainPage.xaml,
I just made a two publicmethods, here's a public
void create rectangle and here'sa public void create circle.
They're pretty much identicalasking the color and
just printing the randomleft and top.
And then creating a new instanceof that particular object.
In this case an Ellipse.
Giving it a width and
height and a margin and then Iuse the fill, I use the color to
create a solid color brush thatI apply to the fill property.
And then I just make it a child
by adding it to the layoutgrid that I have.
So, pretty simple right?
All right, so let's use the whatwe learned in this example to
add Cortana integrationinto our application.
So what I'm goingto do actually is,
kind of put this overto the side here.
And then, I'm going toopen up our application.
The first thing I want to do tomy application is add new item.
I'm gonna add a voicecommand dictionary.
So I'm gonna scroll down tilI find the XML file, and
I'll call thisVoiceCommandDictionary.
Oh there is one last thingI need to show you as well.
From that previous project.
Let me drag it backinto view here.
One thing I didn't show you waswe need to load up that voice
command dictionary and I do thathere in the Page_Loaded event.
So I'm gonna go out andsay hey I wanna grab
this Cortana examplecommand set xml file and
I wanna load it into my commanddefinition manager by calling
the install command definitionfrom storage file a sync method,
passing in the storage file Icreate a reference to here.
All right, sohopefully that makes sense.
So now what I'm gonna do isactually open up that previous
voice command dictionary.
And I'm going to paste it in
to my newVoiceCommandDictionary.xml.
And of course I'm gonnachange everything up.
I'm gonna call this commandprefix Hero Explorer.
And the example will berefresh the character list.
So I'm only gonnahave one command and
it's not gonna have a phraselist associated with it.
So we'll just go ahead andget rid of all that.
This is gonna be a verysimple implementation.
I'm gonna call thiscommand refresh and
the example will be somethinglike refresh the character list.
And we'll give a coupleof variations on this so
Refresh [the] character list.
Or even just refresh
the characters.
And I might even just makethis character also optional.
I don't know if I can do that,we'll just throw that in there.
So, you can just sayrefresh list, or
refresh characters,or refresh the list,
or refresh the character list,refresh the characters.
A lot of differentways to get that is.
And the feedback we want,is refreshing.
Character list.
All right, so that part's done.
The next thing that I wanna dois go to the app.zamzar file.
Let's open it up here, and I'mgonna override a method that you
cannot see, and I'm actuallyjust gonna copy, and
paste it from thisCortana example And
then we'll strip out the thingswe don't need from it.
So I definitelywon't need colors.
It doesn't like that anywaycuz I don't have the proper
namespaces added.
That's fine.
Get rid of that.
And there are other thingswe need like spokenColor.
We don't need to graboff anything like that.
We can just remove all of that.
I don't need the textthat was actually spoken.
All I really need to do is makesure that the voice command is
indeed the commandthat we're looking for.
So I can actually get ridof most of this as well.
And I just want to make surethat the voiceCommandName
= "refresh".
That's what she passed in.
And if it is then we'll
call into our publicmethod on our main page.
We'll print that injust a little bit.
But I'll get rid of all of here.
All of this rather.
So, and this greatlysimplifies the application.
Everything else thatneeds to be there,
we've eliminated allthe fluff that we don't need.
Okay, great.
Now in the mainpage.xml.cswhat I want to do.
In the Page_Loaded eventis actually load up at
that VoiceCommandDictionaryfile.
So I think I'll actually do thatfirst before we go off into
populating the mobilecharacters so that we can place
in this third record, and we'llchange the name of the file
cuz I need this one voiceCommandDictionary.xml.
Otherwise, everythingcan stay the same.
But I do need to createsomething that we can call from
the app.xml.cs fromthat OnActivated event.
So, here's where I needto make some decisions.
I think I could really just take
virtually everythinginside of this.
In fact, let me just go aheadand grab everything up here.
Take all this andI'll put it in a method.
Called refresh.
So we do that.
Go public async
void Refresh().
And its only job willbe to do all that.
And then we'll callRefresh from here.
And this also sets us up tocreate some user interface
element that you canclick on to refresh, but
we're not gonna dothat in this video.
Or in this series of videos,for that matter.
Okay, so that looks good.
Let's make sure itall compiles here.
All right hopefully Ididn't forget a step.
I think we're in good shape,let's make sure.
Oh, I need to go back here tothe app.xaml.cs, that's right.
And here I need togo page.Refresh.
Yeah, yeah.
We'll just get rid of that.
And that as well.
All right,
in fact for that matter, I canget rid of that and that too.
Okay, great.
So let me go ahead and give it awhirl and see what happens here.
Let me go back toour local machine.
Run the application.
Okay, so it looks like westart with New Warriors.
Go on from there.
So, here we go.
Hey, Cortana.
In Hero Explorer,refresh the characters.
>> Refreshingthe character list.
>> All right, sothat didn't work.
Let's put a break point here,and
see if we ever get tothis inactivated event.
We'll stick this right there,and let's run it again.
Oh I see what the problem is.
We were already at tencharacters [LAUGH].
All right soa little bug in the logic.
That's not a problem.
So let's goMarvelCharacters.Clear[ ].
And that should fixthe problem now.
Let's go ahead andget rid of that.
And we'll go ahead andgo to that and
it should work this time.
Hey Cortana.
In hero explorer,refresh the character list.
>> Sure thing.
Refreshing the character list.
>> All right, sowe started out with death bird.
Everything went away.
Now we'll start adding new ones.
All right, andyou can see it's working.
All right, great.
So Cortana integration was easy,
especially once you figureout all your logic issues.
[LAUGH] Butyou obviously can expand this.
I only showed youa simple scenario.
The application wasalready running.
There's also another scenariowhere you can create
a background task that'sconstantly listening,
even when yourapplication's not running.
And it can launchyour application and
then give it the Cortana commandthat the user spoke to Cortana.
Again, an advanced example.
You can find that inthe universal Windows apps
examples on GitHub,
which I'm gonna give you thelink to in the very next video.
In fact, that's a good segue tothe next video because we're
gonna wrap up this series.
I'm gonna give yousome places to look for
other great, great resources andthat's one of them.
But, see how easy it wasto integrate Cortana?
So, you're gonna find that
people will want thislevel of integration.
This is one ofthe coolest new features
to come out ofMicrosoft in a while.
All right, so let's wrapit up in the next video.
We'll see you there.
Thanks.