Hi, Bob Tabor with www.learnvisualstudio.net
and in this lesson I wanted to talk about adaptive layout.
This kind of takes the conversation
that we started with in the previous lesson
to a higher level, and in the previous lesson
we talked about the nuts and bolts
of actually using the Visual State Manager
and AdapativeTrigers to change
attributes of objects in XAML based on screen size.
Now we wanna talk about kind of at a higher level,
the patterns that you might follow
or the general thought process behind an adaptive layout.
Again, adaptive layout, super critical
to the Universal Windows Platform story,
where we build one code base and we can use it across
multiple form factors.
So, I found a very creative example
that illustrates this idea very well
on Wintellect's Blog.
So this gentleman by the name of Jeff Prosise,
who I highly esteem and respect
came up with this example and let me put this URL
on screen right now here.
Came up with this great example of what I'm talking about
in this article 'Using AdapativeTrigers
'To Build Adaptive UIs in Windows 10'.
And, in the body of this lesson,
he kind of, or this article,
he kind of outlines this Contoso Cookbook example.
So I took that idea and ran with it
and I've created a little news-style application
that has an image of my cat,
some information about Mr. Tibbles
and some lorem ipsum text that we'll use.
And, really the core of this again
is the VisualStates that have been defined
for a Wide layout and a Narrow layout in this case.
And so, let's look at this in action.
First of all, let's look at it on...
whoops,
on our local machine,
and you'll see what I'm talking about.
Okay, so you see we're in the Wide layout right now
and we have a photo and a headline,
I haven't spent a lot of time designing this.
And two paragraphs of text.
Now as I resize the application,
notice that it goes from three columns
to just one column, and now I can scroll down
and read everything about Mr. Tibbles,
if I knew Latin and if this was actually about Mr. Tibbles.
But hopefully you get the idea
how we dramatically change the layout
of our content based on the screen width.
Now let's see this at play and how it actually works
inside of the phone emulators.
So let me change there to the Mobile Emulator,
the four inch, have it deploy out there really quickly
and you can see in this case,
we just get that single-column view.
Now how does this all work?
Well, let's talk a look at the actual code
that makes this happen.
First of all, it starts off with a series
of StackPanels that hold the Content.
So on my first StackPanel, second StackPanel
and third StackPanel, and notice
the Names that I gave them: "First"
which contains the image of Mr. Tibbles and the TextBlock.
The "Second" just contains that first paragraph of lorem ipsum
and then the "Third" StackPanel which contains
some more lorem ipsum.
Now, by default, you can see that,
what am I doing here?
I'm setting the, yeah,
the Rows and everything, I set them
to are kind of irrelevant because that's going to be set here
in the Visual State Manager.
So I have two VisualStates again,
the Wide State and the Narrow State.
Whenever we're in the Wide State,
we're going to utilize all three Columns
that have been defined.
And then we begin to put each of our StackPanels
inside of a specific Row and Column.
So we put the "First" StackPanel
in Row 0, Column 0, we put the "Second" StackPanel
in Row 0, Column 1,
and then we put the third in Row 0, Column 2.
Furthermore, we set the ColumnSpan to 1,
so in other words we don't want
any of our StackPanels to span more than one Column,
makes sense, and so that's how we get that Wide layout
that we saw as we ran the application originally.
So that is this layout.
One Column, two Columns, three Columns, alright.
But whenever we shrink, the State or the size
of the window below 800,
we fall into the territory of the Narrow VisualState
so the Trigger here is 800, and we hit that minimum width
of 799, we're now into our Narrow State
and we begin to change the Grid.Row and Column
for each of our StackPanels.
The "First", "Second" or "Third" StackPanel are now all set
to the same Column, just different Rows.
Furthermore, for each of the StackPanels
we set its ColumnSpan to 3, so take the entire width,
all the Columns, as the width of your content.
And so that's how we get the effect
whenever we then resize,
now we're taking each of the StackPanels,
this is the "First" StackPanel,
and we're spanning three Columns.
And here's our "Second" StackPanel,
we're spanning three Columns,
and our "Third" StackPanel, we're spanning three Columns.
Okay, so hopefully you get the idea
of what's possible and the layout that changes
that we can accommodate based on screen size.
Now again, I want to emphasize something I said previously.
I don't know that there are any specific guidelines
regarding what you should do
for the various AdaptiveTriggers in your applications.
It's really up to you and the layout
of your specific application.
What you can do is take a look at the stock applications
in Windows 10, both on the desktop and on the phone.
So, if you take a look here on our News App on the desktop,
we still, we have our hamburger navigation,
we have our Search fields here at the top,
there's this little edit button here on the top bar as well,
there is, we can expand some things, okay.
So you get the general idea, right?
Let's take a look at the News app then
inside of the phone.
Alright, same stories, same hamburger navigation.
Notice that some of the icons
might be a little bit different.
Notice that the Edits icon here is at
the bottom instead of the top.
So we could accommodate that
based on what we've learned.
Okay, this listing is in a list,
as opposed, in a vertical list
as opposed to kind of of,
well I guess this isn't a vertical list too,
it just has multiple columns, okay.
So, you can see how adaptive layout works
in the stock applications in Windows.
So I guess the moral of the story is this,
you have the tools to make your application
change form, however that makes sense
for your application.
You get to decide the break points,
you get to decide what layout changes need to happen.
It's all up to you.
And perhaps that's where you need to
for your specific type of application,
you could take a cue from obviously the News App
or the other apps that are bundled with Windows.
But beyond that, there's not a lot of guidance.
So you want to choose carefully, you want to test,
and think logically what would make sense
if I'm holding it versus I'm clicking on it with a mouse
versus if I'm sitting, you know, back in my couch,
scrolling through or working with the application, okay,
and how would I want the UI to change
based on those layouts.
Okay, so that's the notion of adaptive layout
and something that we're going to add
to a few of our applications coming up.
Alright?
So let's continue on.
We're going to look at a few more concepts
before we begin to depart from the more
educational aspect of this, and more into
the actual hands on, let's build real apps,
which comes in the second half of the series.
So, hang in there, you're doing great,
we'll see you in the next lesson, thanks.