Hi, I'm Bob Tabor with www.learnvisualstudio.net.
As you already know, Windows 10 has a very
distinctive look and feel.
I'm not just talking about things like
the hamburger-style navigation, I'm also talking
about the colors, the background/foreground colors,
the typography.
And so, there's actually this great resource
that deals with the aesthetics of building
Universal Windows Platform apps.
As you can see onscreen right now,
it's at this URL that I'm going to pop up right here,
and this will talk about the aesthetics, about navigation
styles, so anything related to the design and
user interaction, user experience, you'll definitely
want to consult this document; there are probably
other great resources available on www.microsoft.com as well,
or www.windows.com.
But even inside of those guidelines,
there is room for some creative expression,
for example, your company may need
its branding, its colors, its font styles to be
represented in the application.
So, you'll not only want to know what the rules are,
but then you'll also want to know why and when
to break those rules.
Now in this lesson, I'm going to talk about the
technical aspects of working with XAML
to style up your app.
Primarily, what I want to talk about are
creating reusable styles and resources that
can be shared between many different elements
across a single Page, multiple Pages in your
entire app, or even across multiple applications.
Now in the next lesson, we're going to talk about the
pre-built Themes that are available that will help
enforce consistency across all apps on a given
user's device, we'll talk about that later.
Now suppose that you have a particular color,
or a setting that you know that you're going to want
to use throughout the entire page of your
application, or the entire app.
Perhaps a color or a setting that you
might want to change occasionally,
and you just want to make that change
in one place and then have it reflected
everywhere that that particular style
is being utilized, kind of similar to
Cascading Style Sheets.
Well, in that case, you're going to want
to create a resource and then bind
to that resource as necessary.
So I've created a new Project called
XAMLResources and I want to create the most
simple illustration, example, of using resources
that I possibly could.
So, what I'm going to do here, in the MainPage.xaml,
and I made no changes to this whatsoever,
I'm going to add a Page.Resources section.
All right, so, inside of that Page.Resources,
I'm going to add a new Resource that I'm going to call
SolidColorBrush, and I'm going to give it a Name,
called MyBrush, and that will simply use a
solid color brush Color of Brown.
Again, an extremely simple example,
just to illustrate the concept and
then we'll move on from there with
better examples.
Now whenever I want to use that Brush
that I've defined anywhere in my application,
I can reference it like so, using a
binding Statement.
So here, I'm setting the Foreground
of my TextBlock to a Binding statement.
You can see the open and close curly braces
and the word StaticResource, and then I
give it the name of the resource that I want to
bind to, in this case, MyBrush.
Now, the key is that Binding syntax,
which we see often for different purposes in XAML,
binding to a resource takes the form of
the Binding expression syntax of the open and close
curly brace and then the word StaticResource and then
whatever the resource name is.
The curly braces indicate binding, so that first word,
StaticResource, defines the type of binding
that we're engaging in.
We're binding to a resource that's defined
in XAML and it's only evaluated once
as the application first starts.
And there are other kinds of Binding expressions
that allow you to continually evaluate
the information that'll be bound, or pre-compile
the Binding statements that we'll talk about
as well, and so on, and those will come into play
at various points during the remainder
of this series of lessons.
Now, in this case, I've only created a
SolidColorBrush, but we can create
lots of different Resources.
So, for example, here I'm just going to create
a Resource that's a String, and it'll just
be called greeting, and here I can
use that greeting in that Text attribute
of my TextBlock.
So, here I'll go StaticResource, and then
I'll use the key greeting like so.
Let's run the application; we haven't done that
just yet, take a look at what this will look like,
hopefully it'll say "Hello, World" in a brown font.
And, it does. Again, extremely simple example
to get started here.
Now, beyond simple Resources, Styles allow you
to collect one or more settings that can be reused
across a Page, or across an entire app,
for a specific Control.
Then, whenever you want to reuse that Style,
you set a given Control's Style attribute
and essentially bind it to the Style
that you've defined.
So virtually every Control, and even the Page itself
has features of its appearance that
can be customized, whether it be Fonts,
or Colors or Border thickness, or Width,
or Height, what have you.
So all these attributes can be set
on an individual basis on each Control
in your XAML, which will make your XAML
quite wordy and maybe even difficult to
kind of parse through visually.
And that would be one downside.
The other downside is, obviously, if you
miss a setting and you're trying to
keep things consistent, you might forget,
"Oh, I forgot to set the FontSize,
"the Font color", you can keep this all consistent by
defining that Style one time and then just
reusing the Style.
Alright, so here, I'm just going to copy and paste
a style, this is just to kind of save
from having to type it all out.
Alright, so we start with an open tag
called Style, and we define the type of Style
that this will be used for.
So, the TargetType for this Style will be
a Button Control, and we give it also a Key
so that we can reference it then, later on,
in our XAML.
And here we use a series of Setter elements.
Each Setter has the Property we want to affect,
the Property we want to set, as well as
the Value that we want to set it to.
So, just a series of name/value pairs.
So, in this case, whenever we apply the Style called
MyButtonStyle, we want to set the Background="Blue",
the FontFamily="Arial Black",
and the FontSize="36".
All right, so let's go ahead and actually use that,
here I'm going to put a Button,
I'm going to set the Content="My Button Style Example"
Content="My Button Style Example",
set the Height="100",
and then I'm going to set the Style equal to that --
whoops -- set the Style equal to that Binding syntax.
So, StaticResource, and I'm going to type in "My",
and you notice that even IntelliSense will see
the Styles and the other Resources that we've defined.
So, MyButtonStyle, and that should be good,
and just to make sure that these work well
I'm going to create this StackPanel out of this,
(mumbles)
Now let's run the application.
OK, so you can see that I have now
a big, blue button, large text, all of
the Properties that we set for that style
were applied, very quickly and easily,
by just binding it to that StaticResource that we defined.
OK. So, again, these are very simple examples
to illustrate the idea, and as a result, it may not
be readily apparent why you would actually
want to utilize Styles and Resources.
I mean, what's the value of this approach?
Well, as your application grows larger and larger,
as you add more Pages or many more Controls
to your application, you might find this approach
to be quite handy.
I mean, it'll be a lot of effort to reapply even those
three Properties every single time you have
a Button Control in your application.
So, using Styles and Resources is going to help
to keep your XAML compact and concise.
It's also going to be easier to manage.
And so, in that regard, if you ever need to
make a change, you change it in one spot,
in the Style itself, and then it's applied everywhere.
Now I created these as local Resources on the Page
where they're being used, meaning that their scoped
to just this MainPage.xaml.
But what if I wanted to share these Resources
across all of the Pages in my application?
Well, in that case, I would remove those Resources
and the Style from this MainPage.xaml,
and I'd put them into an application Resources Element
on the App.xaml.
So, here, let me do this; I'm actually going to just
select, hit Ctrl-X on my keyboard to remove these,
go over to the App.xaml and go
Application.Resources,
and then I'll paste them in here.
Now, the end result should be the same;
nothing should change about my application whatsoever.
Now, we're to re-run the application, because we're sharing
those Styles across all Pages of my app,
by putting that into the App.xaml,
we get the same effect, and it just makes my
MainPage.XAML that much smaller and more compact.
Alright. And, one last point, you can see here that
this ResourceDictionary that we've defined
here in this Application.Resources,
that we're only using it to create, like,
Resources, SolidColorBrushes and Strings or
actually Styles, but this can also contain Static Resources,
Control templates, animations and even more.
So this is very handy, especially if you need to reuse
things across the entire application.
Alright, so beyond just a simple ResourceDictionary
that we've defined at the Page level and at
the Application level, you can also create
what are called merged Resource dictionaries
that allow you to define your Resource dictionaries
in multiple files and then combine them together,
and you might do this to help you manage
the complexity, to reuse your Dictionary files
in other projects, things of that nature.
All right, so what we're going to do here
in the XAMLResources is, right-click --
well, actually, let me do this instead --
I'm going to go to Project, Add New Item,
and here, what I wanna do, is select the
Resource Dictionary, I'm going to leave the name
as Dictionary1.xaml and click Add, (mumbles)
and I'm just going to paste in a really, really simple
SolidColorBrush, I'm just giving it the name "brush",
setting its color equal to "Red", nothing very fancy here,
but what we'll do then is we actually need to
merge this ResourceDictionary into
the Page's ResourceDictionary, and to do that,
we're going to go to the Page.Resources and
create a ResourceDictionary element,
and then a ResourceDictionary.MergedDictionaries
attribute, and here we're going to create a
ResourceDictionary and set the Source="Dictionary1.xaml"
Source="Dictionary1.xaml"
And, just to prove how this works,
I'm going to remove this foreground from
the MyBrush that I created earlier,
just to the brush that I know that's defined
inside of that Dictionary1.xaml.
And now, we should see red text at the
very top of our app, and we do. Great.
We can actually merge multiple Dictionaries together,
so, here again, I'm just going to go to Project, Add New Item,
Resource Dictionary, Dictionary2.xaml is fine for the name,
and I'll click Add.
And here I'm going to grab out the greeting, here,
and just paste it into Dictionary2, and then
I'm going to merge that into my MainPage.xaml.
So, right now, it can't find that greeting,
but what we'll do is just copy and paste that
and just change this to Dictionary2.xaml,
it should find it again and it should work just like before.
So, we can create multiple ResourceDictionaries,
merge them together, then reuse these Dictionary files
in other applications, or just split up our Styles
and other things that we've defined in the
multiple ResourceDictionary files for
easy management, so that we could find
what we're looking for when we need it. OK?
So hopefully this was helpful, just a way to
add consistency and manageability to your
application development efforts. Right.
So we'll talk about themes in the next lessons.
See you there. Thanks.